(EX CLAlMS )
This is Scott! Come in!
l found it. l found the lake bed!
l've got the lime!
Oh, my God.
lf you can hear me, wait.
Just wait, l'm coming!
Eli.
Which way?
Let's move out.
Scott...
Come on. Ready? Drink.
Come on, come on, come on, man.
Take the bag.
There's no time!
-You have to take it.
-Yes, you can.
-No, l can't make it.
-Get the hell up! Come on!
l can't make it.
(GREER GRUNTS )
l can't carry you and this!
Get your weak ass up! Come on!
Come on, soldier!
Less than three minutes
before the ship jumps again.
lncoming!
-l'll stay.
-lt's okay. l got it.
-Sorry, sir.
-You did your best.
Less than one minute.
(MUTTERlNG)
l see them !
They're carrying something!
GREER: We've got it!
Don't go! We've got it!
They've got the lime!
And they're not going to make it.
Forty seconds.
Give me the radio.
Eli, l want you to stick your arm
into the event horizon of the puddle.
Seriously?
Are you sure?
No. But l'm betting
there's some kind of safety protocol
that prevents someone
getting cut off en route.
And what if there isn't?
Twenty seconds.
Eli, do it now!
Come on, man. Come on.
Come on!
Five, four, three, two, one!
Eli, drink.
YOUNG: Scott, look at me.
Lieutenant, look at me.
Look at me! Look at me.
Well done, Eli. Well done.
(SHlP RATTLlNG)
(ENGlNE STARTlNG)
(BREA THEPLAYlNG)
(SINGING) In the quiet of a shadow
In the corner of a room
Darkness moves upon you
(BREA THEPLAYlNG)
In the quiet of a shadow
In the corner of a room
Darkness moves upon you
Like a cIoud across the moon
You're a-wearing aII the siIence
Look.
Of a constant that wiII turn
Like a cIoud across the moon
You're a-wearing aII the siIence
Look.
Of a constant that wiII turn
Like the windmiII Ieft deserted
(SlGHS )
Or the sun forever burn
So don't forget to breathe
Don't forget to breathe
Like the windmiII Ieft deserted
(SlGHS )
Or the sun forever burn
So don't forget to breathe
Don't forget to breathe
Your whoIe Iife is here
No eIeventh-hour reprieve
So don't forget to breathe
Keep your head above water
But don't forget to breathe
Your whoIe Iife is here
No eIeventh-hour reprieve
So don't forget to breathe
Keep your head above water
But don't forget to breathe
l brought you some water.
l still have some.
-You really need to drink it.
-l'm fine.
Everyone appreciates what you did.
Rush say how long it will last?
l still have some.
-You really need to drink it.
-l'm fine.
Everyone appreciates what you did.
Rush say how long it will last?
He's not sure.
How are you?
My parents died in a car crash
when l was four years old.
-l'm sorry.
-And the priest who raised me,
he pretty much drank himself to death
when l was 16.
My God.
l'm sorry. l'm not trying to diminish
what you're going through.
-l'm sorry.
-And the priest who raised me,
he pretty much drank himself to death
when l was 16.
My God.
l'm sorry. l'm not trying to diminish
what you're going through.
-l... l know.
-l think my point is,
there's just some things you never get over.
That's just the way it is.
-l... l know.
-l think my point is,
there's just some things
you never get over.
That's just the way it is.
You go on through.
As best as you can.
Don't forget to breathe
You go on through.
As best as you can.
Don't forget to breathe
You know you are here
But you find you want to Ieave
So don't forget to breathe
Don't forget to breathe
You know you are here
But you find you want to Ieave
So don't forget to breathe
Just breathe
English - US - SDH
RUSH:: Destiny.
The design is cIearIy Ancient:
Launched hundreds of thousands
of years ago:
SCOTT:: Where the heII are we?
Several billion light years from home.
We are on a ship, but we have no idea
where we are in relation to Earth.
RUSH:: This ship couId be the most
important discovery mankind has made
since the stargate itseIf:
YOUNG:: These are the wrong peopIe
in the wrong pIace:
SCOTT:: I've got a Iot of wounded:
We need to get home:
RUSH:: We bareIy have enough power
to operate the main systems:
This ship simply doesn't have
the capability to dial Earth.
Even if we can get
the life support working,
-we don't have much food and water.
-Then go get some.
Little boys playing soldier.
Well, l'm sorry.
l've no interest in playing your game.
l'm not playing anything.
l'm trying to save the lives
of everyone aboard that ship.
We do have power issues to be aware of.
lf l wasn't being clear,
l was giving you an order.
Dr. Rush.
-Dr. Rush, l was wondering if...
-Not now!
What are you doing?
Morning.
Colonel Young asked us to figure out...
l turned these systems off for a reason.
They need to stay off!
BROD Y: Don't know whether the ship
has electrolyzed it to produce oxygen,
but you can see
there's not much left in there.
We did some calculations
based on our estimates
of the water depth and tank dimensions.
-And the winner is?
-Just over 90,000 liters.
91,046. lsh.
Go, Math Boy.
-Sounds like a lot.
-lt wouldn't fill a backyard swimming pool.
Still, it's enough to loosen
the rationing restrictions, isn't it?
Camile, l think l know
where you're going with this,
and believe me when l say
that l, too, could use a shower.
(ALL CHUCKLlNG)
l don't think the showers use water.
They just spray a sort of mist
that you kind of stand in,
and it sort of beads up.
There's one in a compartment
off the crew quarters.
How do you know all that
if you haven't tried it?
How do you know l haven't tried it?
Oh, we know.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
Thank you, Lieutenant Rose Garden.
No, he's right. You're worse than he is.
Wow, you can tell them apart?
We also identified a recycling system
for liquid waste,
so once we get that system
up and running...
Okay, folks, let's have a better day
than yesterday. Thank you.
-Your ration, sir.
-Thank you.
l ordered you here 20 minutes ago.
l've been working.
Throughout the night, actually,
trying to find out
why our power reserves are so low.
l'm quite concerned, and so should you be.
Okay, well, how bad is it?
l haven't been able to access any
of the main systems yet, so l don't know.
You look exhausted.
Maybe you should take a break.
Get the information we need
and make some informed decisions,
and we report...
(HOLLOW RATTLlNG)
Could you please stop people
running around
activating every bloody system
they can get their hands on?
l will.
That was delicious. Thank you very much.
That man is a lot of work.
Let's bring in the next group, please.
Doctor, l'm very sorry to bother you.
l know you're busy, but l really need your...
What did l say?
(HOLLOW RATTLlNG)
Come on, it doesn't have to be profound.
Just who you are
and something you want to say.
Like... Hi, l'm Eli Wallace.
l'm 25 years old.
l'm currently unemployed,
and just for posterity's sake,
l'd like to say,
''Take your stinking paws off me,
you damn dirty ape! '' for example.
l'm not really gonna say that.
Just try it. Say something.
YOUNG: Well, it could be that Rush is
just starting a fire so he can put it out,
or it could be that he's so far ahead of us
he can see problems
that none of us can see.
So what do you want us to do?
Help him.
(LAUGHlNG) The man likes to work alone.
Well, with the way he's been treated,
you can hardly blame him.
l can blame him all day long.
lt's pretty hard not to, considering.
-This isn't helpful.
-Yeah, well, it's the truth.
YOUNG: Well, we're stuck
with Rush for now.
Scott is checking out the other shuttle,
seeing if it's operational.
He asked that you two join him
when we were done here, so off you go.
Dismissed.
Please tell me that's everyone.
We still have the question of what to do
with the Senator's body.
Yeah, we'll get to him.
He's not going anywhere.
l'd appreciate a file on everyone
by sometime tomorrow.
Nothing fancy.
-And my assignment, sir?
-Recipes, Becker.
For the love of God, recipes.
Second Lieutenant Vanessa James, 26,
Air Force Special Forces.
All l have to say is,
l don't want to die out here.
WRAY: Colonel!
YOUNG: l thought we were done.
There are still dozens of human resources
issues we need to talk about.
Pick one.
The matter of Lieutenant Johansen
resigning her commission.
Consider her reactivated.
-Well, l don't know if that's up to...
-Up to me? Yeah, it is.
We need a medic.
l don't even know why she resigned
in the first place.
Well, that's none of my business.
Colonel, look what we figured out.
We're calling it a recharging plate.
YOUNG: Uh-huh.
We've tweaked it so it works
with Earth technology.
For now, we have to be careful
not to leave them on the plate for too long
or it fries the battery, but...
-Not bad, huh?
-lt's great.
-(CHUCKLES ) lsn't it?
-Turn it off.
-Why?
-Well, Rush says we have power issues.
We've got all these things to recharge.
l know, but as soon as he gives
the go-ahead, you kids can go crazy.
For now, help me pass the word
to stop pushing buttons.
lt's cool, guys. This one's secure.
JOHANSEN: You think you can
fly this thing, man?
l can fly an F-302.
GREER: Yeah, in a simulator.
This is a real spaceship, man.
Yes, it is.
So, pretty screwed up, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah, pretty screwed up.
You think they're gonna work it out?
We're pretty freaking far from home, man.
l don't know.
Not today.
You should have shipped out
weeks ago, T.J.
-lt's not right.
-lt ain't right at all.
Yeah, well, l'm here,
so what do you want us to do?
Help me figure out
what kind of bird we got here.
l just radioed Brody to come down,
help translate the controls.
Took me half an hour
just to find the ''On'' switch.
(JOHANSEN CHUCKLES )
Maybe we can take a little joyride, huh?
Oh, joy!
You don't have to follow me around.
What do you mean?
l mean that l'm okay.
Oh. Thank God you said something,
'cause l thought you were
following me around,
and it was about to get awkward.
l don't mind the company.
l just don't want to keep you
from anything important.
l am done with important.
l'm taking the day off from important.
-You should.
-So should you.
(CHUCKLES ) Me?
l don't even know what to do
with myself, Eli.
l'm the last person who should be here.
-l'm second to last.
-You're underestimating yourself.
So are you.
Can you show me how to use that shower
you were talking about?
Yes. Yes, l can.
YOUNG: Scott's checking out the shuttle,
seeing if it's operational.
Everyone else is holding the work
until you give the green light.
Thank you.
Look, l want you to know
that l'm well aware
that in the field of Ancient technology,
or pretty much any other subject
l can think of,
you're the best l've got.
But we can't be working at cross purposes.
All l ask is that you check with me
before issuing orders.
Check with you?
No, no, you see, you got it backwards.
lf you're doing something,
l want to know what it is,
and this is not a request.
Done. Fine. l'll tell you everything.
lf there is an issue that affects
everybody on this ship,
like we're running out of power.
l think l already told you that.
l'm not here to snap your back
or piss you off,
but if we're going to be on this ship
for any length of time,
we need to be on the same page.
l think our length of time
together on Destiny
may be shorter than you think.
Okay.
l get it. Who can l bring in to help?
Honestly, it may take
longer than we've got
to bring someone else up to speed.
-Volker it is.
-Perfect, terrific.
You can tell him to sit on his hands
if you want to.
Spencer, Sergeant. l'm 31 .
All l want to say is, l never asked for this.
All l want is to get off this ship.
ELl: What's it feel like?
What?
What's it feel like on your bare skin?
-lt's really warm !
-Yeah?
-JAMES: Eli.
-l'm just standing guard!
Anybody could walk in. l... What?
-Whatever. l need to talk to you.
-l'm...
Alone. lt's important.
Wow, l am so torn.
Chloe, l'm gonna take Eli for a minute.
That all right with you?
Okay!
l'll check back with you later, okay?
(HOLLOW RATTLlNG)
Hey, heard you could use a helper.
Well, you heard wrong.
Yeah, Young said not to take no
for an answer.
RUSH: lf he wanted to be helpful,
he would have sent Eli instead.
Well, thank you for that,
but Eli's a kid, really,
-and l'm an astrophysicist, so...
-Mr. Volker,
l neither need nor want your help,
all right?
Look, he's just going to drag me right
back in here, and you know it.
Come on.
Right, l'm concerned that Destiny
is on the verge of losing power.
Look for yourself.
This ship's been flying around
for the better part of a million years.
l know.
So l don't understand why
all of a sudden...
Well, we showed up and started
doing things, how about that?
-Like what?
-Dialing back to Earth, for one!
Come on, we had to try.
Look out a window, man.
We're flying faster than the speed of light.
How close to the end of the rope
can we be?
You're obviously not capable
of seeing the signs.
Okay, well, speaking of signs,
when was the last time you slept?
Look, if you know what you're looking for,
there are clear indications that power
is being channeled
into life support and away from...
How can you know that?
We're still completely locked out
of the core systems.
Out!
-Okay, l'll... Forget l said anything.
-Now!
-No, l'll just work quietly...
-lt's too bloody late for that, isn't it?
l told him you'd be a waste of time!
A waste of time that we can ill afford!
lf you can't see the signs
staring you in the face,
then you're no good to me! Get out!