-Here!
-Here.
Okay, good, you two are with me.
-But these consoles just came on.
-No, nobody touch anything yet!
Dr. Rush needs your help.
Everybody else, just stay calm,
stay put. Please.
MAN: ''Stay put''? Wait, what do
you mean? You're just going like that?
There has to be
a mistake in here somewhere.
Seriously, who uses
a whiteboard anymore?
You have computers, like,
everywhere around here.
The power flow was in the target range.
Why wouldn't the address connect?
Wrong address?
There is only one found
in the Ancient database in Atlantis.
With no other instructions?
No, but that's not the issue.
lt has to be your proof.
My proof works.
You know how l know that it does?
Because you said so.
Gentlemen. How's it coming?
(ELl SCOFFS )
-Whoa, whoa ! What are you doing?
-Starting from the beginning.
Wait. Save! Save! Save! l can't...
Mr. Wallace, l would like you to join me
for dinner in the officers' mess.
-Thank you, l'm starving.
-We're quite close
to a breakthrough, actually.
l'd like Eli to keep working.
Well, we've been here for six months.
lt can wait a few more hours.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
ELl: A four-cheese pizza,
mozzarella shouldn't count.
You know what l mean?
When you have, like...
So, tell me, what's it like
when you finally go through the gate?
So, Colonel, you really have no idea
When you go through the gate,
you don't really feel it.
l'm telling you, the moment you
break through the atmosphere in an F-302
and you see the stars? That's incredible.
Wow. That just sounds so amazing.
Could l maybe go for a ride sometime?
where this ninth chevron stargate address
is gonna send you?
No idea at all.
Hmm.
But the Ancients built the stargate
with nine chevrons.
l can arrange that.
So, Colonel, you really have no idea
where this ninth chevron stargate address
is gonna send you?
-No idea at all.
-Hmm.
But the Ancients built the stargate
with nine chevrons.
lt's got to go somewhere.
(SCOFFS )
(MARKER CLATTERlNG)
(SlGHS )
YOUNG: We've also known
for some time that the only way
to unlock the ninth chevron
was to solve the power issues.
Well, if anyone's going to solve it,
l think Eli will.
Yes, that's right. lt's true. l am Math Boy.
(PEOPLE CHUCKLlNG)
Dr. Rush. Dr. Rush!
ARMSTRONG: l would like
to propose a toast.
Oh, no, that's really not necessary.
-Not to you.
-Oh.
When the proposal for this project
first crossed my desk,
l did not want to approve it.
-Oh, my God.
-lt seemed clear to me at the time
that there were enough
terrestrial matters of importance
that needed that kind of money.
Now, being a proud father of
a beautiful young woman is one thing.
Having that young woman exceed every
possible expectation is quite another.
(MELANCHOL Y OPERA
PLA YING ON STEREO)
lt was my daughter, Chloe, who reminded
me that there is no greater endeavor
than seeking an understanding
of who we are,
and the mysteries of the universe
in which we all exist.
-Not in those exact words.
-lt was also her idea
to embed the Ancient proof
in a medium that would give us access
to brilliant young minds
that we would have otherwise overlooked.
And so to all the brave men and women
who have volunteered...
(EXPLOSlON)
Okay, what was that?
(RADIO CRACKLES )
This is Young.
(EXPLOSlON)
YOUNG: The base is under attack.
All non-combatant personnel
report to your designated areas.
Everyone else to your battle stations.
This is not a drill.
Senator, l need you and your daughter
to go with Lieutenant Scott.
-Eli! You as well.
-Oh, yeah.
WOMAN: Hurry.
SCOTT: Yeah, we're on our way.
(SOLDlERS CLAMORlNG)
GREER: What's going on in here?
The life-support system is on,
but for some reason,
it's not working properly.
l'm attempting to reset it.
He has no idea what he's doing.
-Step away from that thing.
-ELl: That screen says
that what you're doing
is gonna overload it...
-Eli, please!
-ls that what it says or not?
You only think you know what it says
in this screen
because l embedded a rudimentary version
of the Ancient language into the game.
-This is not a game.
-Don't touch it, Rush.
When the oxygen aboard this ship
falls below critical level,
it will become increasingly
difficult to concentrate.
And what you're doing
could blow up the whole ship.
-Are you sure, Eli?
-Back off now or l will shoot!
Lower your weapon, Sergeant!
He already screwed us once.
l'm not going to let him do it again!
l need to get through, people. Stand aside.
(ALARM BLARlNG)
Sergeant, we're under attack.
Don't know who, don't know why.
Consider the charges dropped.
Go take your anger out on them.
Yes, sir.
YOUNG ON RADIO:: What do we got,
CoIoneI, Lucian AIIiance?
That would be my guess.
They haven't introduced themselves.
They started shooting the minute
they came out of hyperspace:
Our shields are holding,
but we're not the target.
What's heading our way?
A fuII squadron of gIiders
and a troop transport:
We cut them down some,
but the rest will be on your doorstep
in less than three minutes.
-Telford, did you copy?
-Roger that.
lf we can get to the transport before they
land their troops, we stand a chance.
RUSH: l am going to press that button.
lt's going to fix the life support,
and then you and l, and everyone else,
will be able to breathe and think
much better.
Now, you can shoot me for that if you like,
but if, however, there are any negative
consequences in resetting the system,
RUSH: l am going to press that button.
lt's going to fix the life support,
and then you and l, and everyone else,
will be able to breathe and think
much better.
Don't do it.
l suggest you might still need me
to help resolve them.
Don't do it.
Okay, look. Sergeant,
l know we are in a tough situation here,
but l am giving you an order.
Lower your weapon.
So?
Well, l suppose
that would have been too simple.
Apparently, that did nothing.
This may take a little more time, T.J.
Hang in there.
Copy.
Does Colonel Young know about this?
He knows.
Two weeks ago you told me that this
was the best experience of your life.
-Something must have happened.
-The scholarship came in.
l guess l've just been too afraid
to admit what l really want.
(SCOFFS )
Wow, you didn't tell me
you had even applied.
There's nothing else going on.
You know l'd tell you.
-Unless you were protecting someone else.
-l'm not.
Like l said, l just hadn't made up my mind.
(COMPUTER BEEPlNG)
RlLEY: Dr. Rush? l'm reading
a dangerous energy spike in the core.
Eli! Eli! l need your help.
-With what?
-The ninth chevron.
What? We need to get the hell out of here.
Look, it took us two years to find this site.
The properties are unique.
This may be our last chance.
(EXPLOSlON)
lf this bombardment continues,
the radioactive core is going to go critical.
You mean the planet...
lt's going to explode?
-Yes.
-Ah! Okay, okay, okay, okay.
-lf my math works...
-We can't assume that...
l said ''if''! Then if it works,
then it's not a power supply issue,
it's the gate address.
We've known the first eight symbols
for years,
the ninth has to be the point of origin.
So, what if we're not on the planet
you're supposed to be dialing from?
This is where we are.
Okay, what if
we are not supposed to be here?
Icarus Base, TeIford:
We can't hoId them back:
Let's go! Go!
(SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG)
Sergeant Riley, dial the stargate to Earth!
-SOLDlER: lncoming!
-Come on, come on.
RlLEY: Chevron one locked.
ELl: Okay, follow me.
The symbols on the stargate
are constellations as seen from Earth.
-That's what you said...
-Yes, yes.
Okay, so what if Earth is supposed to be
the point of origin?
-RlLEY: Chevron two locked.
-The only viable power source was here,
-light years away.
-What if that doesn't matter?
What if it's the only combination
that will work, like a code?
-RlLEY: Chevron three locked.
-A code?
-Yeah.
-RlLEY: Chevron four encoded.
-Stop the dialing sequence.
-RlLEY: l have my orders.
Get out of my way. Get out of the way!
We can't risk dialing Earth.
ARMSTRONG: Come on, let's go.
SCOTT: Go, go, keep moving.
(GASPS )
-Dad? Dad? Dad!
-SCOTT: Chloe!
My father! There could still be
people trapped on the other side.
All right, let's go, people.
You need to move it to the Gate Room !
This is Scott. l got about a dozen
or so people cut off from the Gate Room,
(GASPS )
-Dad? Dad? Dad!
-SCOTT: Chloe!
My father! There could still be
people trapped on the other side.
All right, let's go, people.
You need to move it to the Gate Room !
southeast corridor.
Oh, my God! What happened?
He was helping pull wounded
back from the surface.
Come on. All right. l got you. l got you.
This is Scott. l got about a dozen
or so people cut off from the Gate Room,
southeast corridor.
-Oh, God! Okay. Damn it!
-YOUNG: Oh, my God!
-Greer, we're pulling back.
-There are people still out there.
Listen, Hammond's already started beaming
up anyone pinned down on the surface.
Somebody's gotta make sure.
Sergeant, listen to me.
l got people cut off from the Gate Room.
The base is shielded, which means
the Hammond can't help them.
l need you here, now.
-ls that Dr. Simms?
-Stay with me, okay?
He was helping pull people back
from the surface.
(SNlFFLlNG)
-Simms, can you hear me?
-T.J.
-No!
Go.
-Oh, God! Okay. Damn it!
-YOUNG: Oh, my God!
-ls that Dr. Simms?
-Stay with me, okay?
He was helping pull people back
from the surface.
(SNlFFLlNG)
-Simms, can you hear me?
-T.J.
Hey, Tamara. Hey, Tamara.
Come on, we got to go.
-T.J.
-No!
Hey, Tamara. Hey, Tamara.
Come on, we got to go.
That is impressive.
The power's fluctuating at critical levels.
Colonel, l'm detecting a massive buildup
of energy from the planet.
Recall our fighters. Radio Colonel Telford.
He's got two minutes to get his people
aboard before we jump to hyperspace.
(RUMBLlNG)
Recall our fighters. Radio Colonel Telford.
He's got two minutes to get his people
aboard before we jump to hyperspace.
(RUMBLlNG)
What's everybody doing?
l ordered an evacuation.
He, uh... He didn't dial Earth.
lt's the ninth chevron address.
What?
The attack started a chain reaction
in the planet's core.
There's no way of stopping that.
And any blast could easily translate
through an open wormhole.
lt's too dangerous to dial Earth.
You could have dialed somewhere else.
Anywhere else.
-RUSH: This could be our only chance.
-Shut it down.
-You can't, it's too late.
-Riley!
-System's not responding, sir.
-l need to get these people out of here.
-We have a way out.
-We don't know what's on the other side!
-Damn it, Rush!
-Can't be worse than here, can it?
Nobody move. Await further instructions.
What's that?
Well, it doesn't look like life support.
RUSH: Yes, l realize that.
Whoa !
-What are we looking at?
-lt's a star map.
PARK: That's the Milky Way.
RUSH: l believe it's a visual log
of the ship's journey.
So, this is where we are now?
No. That's where the ship
originally embarked from.
ELl: Earth.
-lt's leaving the galaxy.
-RUSH: lt did. Long ago.
That was Pegasus.
So, those points are more stars?
No, they're galaxies.
Rush, where the hell are we?
Several billion light years from home.
-Please.
-YOUNG: Scott.
Stand clear.
You could take down the rest of the roof
with that.
Look, we don't have time to argue.
l need you to lead the evacuees
through the gate. You need to go with him.
No! l'm staying here
until l know my father's okay.
Make sure everyone carries as much
of the expedition supplies as they can.
-Why?
-'Cause you're not going to Earth.
Rush dialed the ninth chevron. Go.
Go!
(RUMBLlNG CONTlNUES )
Once l'm through,
follow one at a time on a three-count.
SOLDlER: Okay, people. Make way.
Come on, let's go. Keep it going.
You good? Okay, let's go.
lf you can hear me, stand back!
Okay, get down.
Fire in the hole!
(CHLOE EX CLAlMS )
(CHLOE COUGHlNG)
Dad?
GREER: Put your weight on me.
-Put your weight on me.
-YOUNG: Stay calm, everybody.
-l got you.
-CHLOE: Please.
Okay, everybody stay calm ! Don't push.
(YELPS )
Dad!
(EX CLAlMS ) Careful, careful.
-YOUNG: You're okay, sir.
-Are you okay?
l'm the last one. l'm all right.
Greer, go. l'm right behind you.
Hammond, this is Young, come in.
Hammond, this is Young. Come in.
GREER: Let's go, let's go, let's go,
come on, people. Let's do it. Let's do it.
SOLDlER: Hurry up!
-Sir!
-Go!
Sir. We've got Colonel Carter. On screen.
GeneraI, we bareIy got away:
The pIanet was destroyed:
We managed to beam
most of our people off the surface
before jumping to hyperspace.
We aIso beIieve that
the enemy forces were destroyed:
Any word on how they gained inteI
on our base?
No.
What about casuaIties?
Twelve. Eighty-plus MlA.
The bunker-shielding technology
prevented us
from beaming out anyone inside.
How many people made it
through the gate to Earth?
None.
None? Our sensors indicated
that the stargate was active
for a fuII six minutes
before the core went criticaI:
Well, they didn't come through here.
Then where'd they go?
Senator. l'm Camile Wray.
l believe as the highest-ranking member
-of the lnternational Oversight Advisory...
-Wray. You're with human resources?
-With the lOA. Yes.
-Don't worry.
l'm going to get things organized.
Okay, listen up!
Everybody who is able, we are going
to search this ship top to bottom.
Teams of three.
JOHANSEN: His vitals seem stable.
Do we have any idea
how long the air will last
if we don't get the life support fixed?
No, sir. Dr. Rush and the other scientists
are working on that.
That's not good enough, Lieutenant.
l need answers.
As soon as l have them, sir.
Okay, listen up!
-Weapons?
-Twenty-three, including handguns.
-One per group?
-Yeah.
[ Skipped item nr. 335 ]
Teams of three.
-Weapons?
-Twenty-three, including handguns.
-One per group?
-Yeah.
Flashlights, radios, only when necessary.
Once those batteries are dead,
they are dead. Regular check-ins
with Dr. Rush in the control room
every 10 minutes, and keep in mind,
as far as we know,
they are dead. Regular check-ins
with Dr. Rush in the control room
every 10 minutes, and keep in mind,
as far as we know,
this bucket is really freaking old,
and there may be areas of damage
where life support is unstable.
this bucket is really freaking old,
and there may be areas of damage
where life support is unstable.
And, look, be smart, okay?
Don't touch anything that
looks like it might be dangerous.
How are we supposed to know
what's dangerous?
-Becker, right?
-Yes, sir. l work in the mess.
-l mean, l did.
-Well, don't touch, just look.
You're... You're James, right?
How are we supposed to know
what's dangerous?
-Becker, right?
-Yes, sir. l work in the mess.
[ Skipped item nr. 356 ]
Subtle, man. Subtle.
SCOTT: lf it's okay with you, sir, it might
be best, considering your obvious skills,
for you to hang back here and
help keep the rest of these people calm.
Don't patronize me, son.
You're... You're James, right?
-Yes, Lieutenant.
-You and Riley are with me.
No, sir.
Subtle, man. Subtle.
SCOTT: lf it's okay with you, sir, it might be
best, considering your obvious skills,
for you to hang back here and
help keep the rest of these people calm.
-ls there any progress?
-PARK: Fortunately for us,
the life-support system activated
automatically when we dialed the ship.
Probably emergency reserves,
but only in certain sections.
The reserve is gone.
Don't patronize me, son.
No, sir.
Life support's been breaking down
section by section ever since.
Resetting it doesn't help.
l asked if there's any progress.
PARK: Unless something changes,
according to my readings,
we only have about six to eight hours
of breathable air left.
Okay, let me put this another way.
Has anyone got any good news?
l think l figured out the menu system.
-Try to find a schematic or map.
-(SCOFFS ) Yeah. Google Spaceship.
Hey, hey, hey. l don't suppose you've
got any food in that pack? l'm starving.
-No. Keep working.
-Well, where are you going?
-To find a bathroom.
-Yeah. That would be good, too.