No! No!
No!
(SOBBlNG)
Please! No. No! No!
No! No!
No!
(SOBBlNG)
He can't leave me.
Chloe. Chloe!
Well, at least he bought us a day.
(CHLOE GRUNTS )
You! You did this! You killed him !
You've killed all of us!
-Chloe, stop! Little help here.
-Hey, hey, relax.
-Hey, hey, Chloe.
-Just get away from me! All of you!
Miss Armstrong. You're in shock.
Believe me, l understand.
Everyone deals with tragedy
in different ways.
-You're looking for someone to blame.
-l'm not looking.
Hey, hey.
l'm sorry about your father. l truly am.
He was a good man, and he certainly
wouldn't have been my choice,
but you must realize,
none of this was my fault.
l didn't create the situation
that forced us here.
There was no other way.
(SOBBlNG)
Miss Armstrong, l know
you don't want to hear this just now,
but this ship...
This ship could be the most important
discovery mankind has made
since the stargate itself.
You know, the lcarus Project was
something your father truly believed in.
Enough to risk his career to support.
What difference does it make if we all die?
A number of people died
during the attack on the base.
Some of them l knew very well.
l'm sure some had more value than others.
As human beings,
all of them were invaluable.
Look, my point is, l promise you,
l will do everything l can to make sure
no one gave their life in vain.
No one.
Please give me a chance.
Colonel.
(YOUNG SlGHS )
-We've lost Senator Armstrong.
-Oh, my God.
-He's bought us some time.
-To do what?
We're working on it. First up
is trying to dial the gate back home.
-Should you even be on your feet?
-No.
Well, l am on my feet,
and right now we're trying to get home.
Camile, l need your help.
You know these people.
l need you to spread the word.
Try to keep things as positive as you can.
-l can do that.
-Good.
CHLOE: l can't believe my dad is gone.
l watched him die,
and l still just can't accept it.
-Tell me about him.
-Why?
Man died so l could live.
l'd like to know a little more about him.
No matter how tired he was,
or how long he'd worked,
or what was going on in his life,
he always had time to listen to me.
l'd go on and on.
He never preached.
He never told me what to do,
even though sometimes l wished he would.
He would just listen.
And then he would tell me
that he loved me.
The best part was if l'd had a fight
with my mom, he never took sides.
Hmm.
Oh, God. My mom.
He was her whole life.
She probably thinks we're both dead.
All l know is that he wanted you to go on.
l know.
l got to get back to the search.
You going to be okay?
l don't know.
Fair enough.
-RUSH: Eli?
-What?
What are you doing?
l just watched a man die.
Okay?
Don't you even care?
Of course l do, and l'm also trying to learn
as much as l can, as quickly as l can.
That is, in addition to running
nine separate searches
in the database in the hope
of solving our life-support issues.
Right.
Found anything?
Destiny:
As in ours?
The name of the ship.
Translated from Ancient.
l've also discovered
that they were never here.
l thought this was an Ancient ship.
lt is, but they sent it out unmanned,
planning to use the gate to get here
when it was far enough
out into the universe,
but they probably learned to Ascend
before that time.
Learned to what?
Ascension.
lt's a process whereby
consciousness converts to energy
that no longer requires physical form.
That wasn't in the video.
Well, there's more than one video.
We should get back to work.
Sorry.
Sir, l think l got it.
lt wasn't even that hard to find.
lt's right here in the dialing program.
-You're sure?
-Yes, it's an eight-symbol address.
You mean you can dial this thing
back to Earth?
There's no point of origin indicated,
but still,
there's only 36 symbols on this gate.
l'm assuming the ninth symbol represents
some X-factor distance equation.
Well, l don't care. Start dialing.
Sir, don't we want to
bring Dr. Rush in on this?
YOUNG: Well, you said
this wasn't that hard to find?
Sir, l think l got it.
-No.
-Well, then he probably already knows
and didn't tell us.
Who is this Lucian Alliance anyway?
Where did that come from?
l just want to know who to blame for this.
They're a human coalition
made up from various Milky Way planets,
lt wasn't even that hard to find.
lt's right here in the dialing program.
-You're sure?
-Yes, it's an eight-symbol address.
formed in the power vacuum left behind
when the Goa'uld were defeated.
They're criminals mostly.
A street gang with starships.
How'd they find out about lcarus?
Wasn't it supposed to be, like,
double secret?
l suspect there was a leak somewhere.
Someone working on the inside.
You mean you can dial this thing
back to Earth?
There's no point of origin indicated,
but still,
there's only 36 symbols on this gate.
The legend surrounding the ninth chevron
has been floating around our galaxy
for some time now.
We found that it meant various things
to different cultures.
Some said
it was a key to the universe itself.
And once unlocked,
you would gain untold power.
l'm assuming the ninth symbol represents
some X-factor distance equation.
Well, l don't care. Start dialing.
Now, if the Lucian Alliance
knew that we'd discovered
the address and a means to dial,
they'd want it.
This ship is a source of untold power?
No, no, not literally.
lt's more to do with what it's doing.
YOUNG: Well, you said
this wasn't that hard to find?
-lf you know how to use it.
-Yeah.
That's what you're after, isn't it?
Why you risked everything to get here.
You think this ship is going to make you
all-powerful or something crazy like that?
Eli...
-No.
-Well, then he probably already knows
and didn't tell us.
lf l could find a way
to send all these people home safely
and then return
with a properly skilled team
to pursue this mission as intended,
why wouldn't l want to do that?
-Oh, no, no, no, no.
-What?
Someone's dialing the gate.
-l don't know.
-Uh-huh. Now turn that thing off.
You saw that?
(ALARM BEEPlNG)
-Oh, no, no, no, no.
-What?
Someone's dialing the gate.
-Colonel Young. You're up.
-Nice to see you, too, Rush.
l did order you to report to me.
Yes, but what are you doing?
We're trying to dial Earth.
RUSH: That would be a mistake.
YOUNG: Riley thinks he's found
the address for home.
RUSH: His understanding of Ancient
is marginal at best.
RlLEY: With respect, Doctor, l know enough
to recognize a reference to Earth.
He says the address wasn't
that hard to find, Rush.
No, no. This is a complete
waste of power we may need.
We have the address back.
All we need is the right point of origin.
And we've got 36 tries.
We barely have enough power
to operate the main systems.
This ship simply doesn't have
the capability to dial Earth.
You see, that's news to me.
-He didn't tell me that, either.
-Well, l've only just learned myself,
-and you know what l've been doing.
-Even if it doesn't work,
the people aboard this ship
need to see us at least try.
So, what, you're going to drain
what little power we have
for the sake of morale?
How ridiculous.
(SHlP GROANS )
What was that?
(BEEPlNG)
YOUNG: Anyone near the observation deck?
Colonel, it looks like
we've dropped out of FTL.
-RlLEY: Because we were draining power?
-No, no.
lf l'm right, the gate should
begin to dial any moment.
How did you know that?
The ship detected a stargate on a planet
within range that may have what we need.
What? How the hell
are there even stargates out here?
The Ancients sent out a number
of unmanned ships ahead of this one.
They're programed
to gather data, resources,
to manufacture stargates
and deposit them in habitable worlds.
Any relevant information
is relayed back here to help plot the course.
You're telling me
that this ship knows we're in trouble?
Yes, because l told it we were.
Essentially, we're flying on autopilot.
This ship may have stopped
when it was within range of a stargate
regardless of our need.
But l have reason to believe...
YOUNG: So, what we need is
on the other side of that wormhole?
An educated guess, yes.
There's only one way to find out.
RlLEY: Sir, you can't do that.
We have no idea what's on the other side.
We can use the Kino to find out.
l expect that's the purpose of this device.
-l'm getting readings over here.
-What have we got?
Temperature, gravity,
atmosphere composition,
barometric pressure.
Oxygen, nitrogen, very little CO2,
extremely low humidity.
-Habitable, but just barely.
-Good enough.
BROD Y: Looks like four other addresses
came up here, too.
They could be other planets within range.
Maybe we should think about
dialing them up and seeing...
No, no, no, they're locked out.
The ship chose this one.
The stargate is open,
all we have to do is step through.
What we have to do is put a team together.
Dr. Rush.
RUSH: Looks like our time might be limited.
YOUNG: What is it?
lt's a countdown. Just over 12 hours left.
What happens then?
l suspect we jump back into FTL.
Palmer is a geologist.
Obviously she should go.
Franklin and Brody are
the best of the rest of what we have.
Thanks for the ringing endorsement.
He didn't even mention me.
YOUNG: Franklin goes. The others stay.
We're still going to need good people
working on the problem from this end.
ELl: l'd like to go.
Really?
lf l can help, then...
-Colonel Young, please.
-What? You don't think l can handle it?
He's going.
l've been off-world before.
You have made a habit out of
pulling our asses out of the fire.
Eli, you want to go, you're going.
The only one l'm questioning right now
is you, Dr. Rush.
(SCOFFS )
Well, besides Palmer, l'm the only one
who knows what we're looking for.
We have 12 hours to find what we need
and then get back on the ship.
You're sure you can't stop it?
No, we're just along for the ride for now.
Then we may all be better off on the planet.
Well, that's another reason
why l should go.
Someone to assess whether
long-term survival there is even an option.
Right. Okay.
l want everyone clear
that Scott is in charge of this mission.
Let's gear up, let's find whatever
supplies we have, and move out.
-Sir, about Eli...
-He volunteered.
He's not trained for this.
Just like a lot of people we got on the ship.
l'm going to need to know
what they're made of.
He'll slow us down.
Well, if he does,
you send him back to the gate.
Listen, if we're going to make it,
and l'm not just talking the next few hours,
we're going to need
everyone on board to step up.
Lieutenant.
Keep an eye on Rush.
Think there could be dinosaurs?
We'll be back, sir.
Good luck.
Anything's possible.
(CHUCKLES )
We'll be back, sir.
Good luck.
Hot.
(ELl LAUGHS )
Cool.
SCOTT: Make sure
we can dial back to the ship.
FRANKLlN: Already on it.
-PALMER: Looks like gypsum.
-That would be good.
Why?
-We're looking for calcium carbonate.
-RUSH: Calcite.
Gypsum is calcium sulfate,
which is 36% calcium carbonate.
ELl: Hmm.
Huh. lt dissolves.
Are you saying we can use this sand
to fix the scrubbers?
-That would be convenient.
-PALMER: (SlGHS ) No.
RUSH: Well, it's a fair indication
that the components may exist nearby.
PALMER: For the sake
of portability and efficiency,
l'm hoping to find
high-concentration granular limestone.
We are looking for the dried lake bed
or salt-water body all this sand came from.
lt's a desert.
Lime is formed mostly from
the remains of marine organisms.
-Huh.
-Are you saying there was life here?
RUSH: Not likely
anything we've seen before.
Yeah, the water may be gone now,
but this desert was formed by
H2O evaporating on a playa floor,
causing gypsum to be deposited
in a fine crystalline form called selenite.
-Where are you going?
-Higher ground.
ls that supposed to happen?
PALMER: lf this sand is high enough
in calcite concentration,
the solution would absorb the acid.
-Right.
-The liquid would turn clear.
lt's not.
We're good!
This is Scott.
Unfortunately, there's nothing useful
in the immediate vicinity of the gate.
YOUNG:: You have 12 hours, Lieutenant:
Make them count:
Copy that.
We're moving out!
Too bad we can't just use this sand.
There certainly is enough of it.
(YOUNG BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
-James.
-Yes, sir.
l'm looking for Chloe Armstrong.
She's still in there. She hasn't come out.
(DOOR OPENS )
How is she?
How about asking how l'm doing?
Well, you're trained for this, Airman.
Give me a...
l'm fine.
No, you're not,
and neither am l, but we're...
She just watched her father die.
My father may as well be dead to me, too,
'cause l'm stuck in some galaxy
that only God knows about.
Yeah. Okay.
You know,
l was supposed to go back to lraq again,
but they said that
this would be a better opportunity.
We're still alive because of what he did.
-Look, for what it's worth...
-Well, it's worth a lot.
You know, as long as we're still here,
l promise you...
-We're all going to die out here.
-Hey!
l want you to listen to me.
l don't want to hear that kind of talk.
Do you understand?
'Cause we're going to work...
We're going to work this out.
Just letting you know
how l'm doing, Colonel.
Colonel, l've edited enough
of my father's speeches
to know what you're going to say.
You don't have a clue
what l was going to say, because l don't.
Since you asked.
(DOOR OPENS )
We...
We brought along an Ancient device.
Communication stones.
l'm fine.
No, you're not,
and neither am l, but we're...
We're still alive because of what he did.
-Look, for what it's worth...
-Well, it's worth a lot.
You know, as long as we're still here,
l promise you...
Colonel, l've edited enough
of my father's speeches
to know what you're going to say.
-They allow us to...
-Yeah, l know what they are.
Good. Well, l'm about to use one of them
to report to my superiors on Earth,
You don't have a clue
what l was going to say, because l don't.
We...
We brought along an Ancient device.
Communication stones.
-They allow us to...
-Yeah, l know what they are.
Good. Well, l'm about to use one of them
to report to my superiors on Earth,
tell them our situation.
l want to tell her myself.
You've been sitting here
since Rush made contact.
Let somebody else take a shift.
(EXHALES )
l'm not leaving this chair.
l've been on this project
for the last six months,
and l'll be damned if...
Colonel?
This is strange.
MEHTA: Dr. Rush, is that you?
No, it's Colonel Young.
l need you to put me in a room
with General O'Neill.
l'm going to need you, too.
JOHANSEN: Sir, l told you not to get up.
(BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
TELFORD: What did he do to himself?
He's got cracked ribs,
more bruises than l can count
and a concussion
that resulted in neuropraxia.
-Oh, that's just great.
-Chloe?
-Dr. Mehta.
-Can you help me, please?
(GROANlNG)
You know, l had some of my
favorite arguments with your father.
Are you saying you won some?
Depends on who you ask.
Listen, Major Green'll be escorting you
to see your mother.
-Please give her my condolences.
-Thank you.
Yeah.
So, how is it going out there really?
l don't know what Rush has told you.
We may not have much time left.
The ship's very old. lt's falling apart.
-Fix it.
-We're trying.
Even if we can get the life support working,
we don't have much food and water.
-Then go get some.
-We're not supposed to be there, sir.
These are the wrong people
in the wrong place,
and as a group, they're just not qualified.
Oh, please.
l wasn't qualified to lead that first team
through the stargate...
-l understand that, sir.
-ln the past dozen years or so,
we've sent hundreds of teams
through that thing...
(SlGHS )
And l think the bottom line is,
none of us are qualified.
l just think we're going to get
to a point very soon
where everyone onboard
should get a chance to say goodbye.
Understood.
Save it.
FRANKLlN: That's not very smart.
Temperatures like these,
the human body needs at least...
GREER: Walk, don't talk.