General, we apparently have
a connection with the lab.
Dr. Rush would like to see you.
General O'Neill. l'm reporting to you
from onboard an Ancient spaceship
-somewhere far beyond our known...
-Just slow down, back up.
Who's with you?
Several dozen, l'm not sure,
but the point is, l did it.
l successfully made the connection
to the ninth chevron address.
You were supposed to be
evacuating non-combat personnel.
To Earth!
Colonel Young gave that order, yes.
l overrode that decision.
-Did you, now?
-lf you'd let me explain, sir.
Dialing Earth was not an option.
The core of the planet P4X351
had become unstable,
and if the resulting blast had transferred
through the wormhole to Earth,
the effect would have been catastrophic.
So let me get this straight.
lnstead of dialing up any one
of a number of other planets in our galaxy,
you took a bunch of unqualified people
halfway across the universe?
l took what l thought was our last chance
to dial the ninth and final chevron.
l was successful. At that point,
the gate couldn't be shut down again.
-Are you all right?
-l'm solid, Lieutenant.
Oh, my God.
Rush, get those people home.
l'm trained for this.
-Look, l didn't mean to...
-Look, not now.
-Are you all right?
-l'm solid, Lieutenant.
l'm trained for this.
-Look, l didn't mean to...
-Look, not now.
ON RADIO:: Rush, this is Scott: Come in:
Rush, this is Scott: Come in:
How exactly do we know
this ship is unoccupied?
Rush said the air came on
just before we got here.
How about aliens that don't breathe air?
Hello. This is Eli.
-Where's Rush?
-Bathroom, if he found it.
Okay.
ON RADIO:: Rush, this is Scott: Come in:
Rush, this is Scott: Come in:
Hello. This is Eli.
l'm at what looks like a bulkhead door.
lt won't open.
I was hoping
Rush couId open it from there:
Should l find him?
No.
-Where's Rush?
-Bathroom, if he found it.
l'm at what looks like a bulkhead door.
lt won't open.
I was hoping Rush couId open it from there:
Should l find him?
No.
-Here, give me a hand.
-What happened to being smart?
This could be the engine room
for all we know.
-Here, give me a hand.
-What happened to being smart?
This could be the engine room
for all we know.
We got to at least open a few doors.
Do we? Do we really?
(ALL GRUNTlNG)
We got to at least open a few doors.
Do we? Do we really?
(ALL GRUNTlNG)
(COMPUTER BEEPlNG)
ELI:: Hang on:
No, keep doing what you're doing.
l think l found where you are.
The door is flashing red.
SCOTT:: Can you open it from there?
Red is usually bad, isn't it?
Maybe it means the door is stuck: Just try:
Okay. You should probably step back.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, not good! Not good.
More red...
Close it!
-CIose it now!
-l'm trying!
(ALARM BEEPlNG)
Yeah. Okay. We established
why that hatch was closed.
Yeah. A lot of others are closed
for the same reason.
We're only occupying
a fraction of the ship right now.
It just goes on forever:
But if there are damaged areas of the ship
that aren't seaIed,
that could be our problem.
Oh, hey, good timing.
We just found... Hey... Really?
This is Dr. Rush.
Meet me in the Gate Room immediately.
Everyone.
MAN 1 : l don't know what's going on.
MAN 2: lt's over there.
(ALL MURMURlNG)
What's going on?
ln this case are
five Ancient communication stones.
They work over vast distances in real time.
-We can talk to the people on Earth.
-Yes.
MAN 1 : Great.
MAN 2: All right.
RUSH: You physically take control
of an individual at the other end.
l brought these with us in the event
we ended up somewhere out of range
of normal communication.
So let's use them.
MAN: Yeah.
WOMAN: Yeah.
l already have.
ALL: What? When?
-Are they sending help?
-No.
MAN: Why? Why are they not sending help?
The only means of dialing
this gate from our galaxy
was destroyed in the attack. We're cut off.
l want to use one of those stones now.
-l have spoken with General O'Neill...
-l am a United States senator!
l've explained our situation clearly.
ln light of my knowledge and experience,
he has placed me in charge.
He did what?
(ALL MURMURlNG)
MAN: How do we know?
l have faith in our ability to repair this ship
and to work together,
but if we're to survive this,
we need leadership
and a clear chain of command.
ELl: We only have a few hours of air left.
-Yeah.
-l want to speak to the General myself.
-Senator, please.
-Give it to him !
WOMAN: Yeah.
SCOTT: Give it to him.
(GROANlNG)
-CHLOE: Dad? Dad!
-Whoa, whoa, whoa. T.J.?
Excuse me, excuse me. Okay.
Okay, he's still breathing.
CHLOE: Oh, my God!
JOHANSEN: l saw him taking some pills?
CHLOE: Warfarin, for his heart.
Blood thinners are the last thing he needs
if he's bleeding internally.
-Please do something!
-Look, l told you, l'm just a medic.
Everyone, please, there's no need for us all
to congregate in the one place.
Ms. Johansen, please find
adequate accommodation for the injured,
-and everyone else...
-No, l don't recognize your authority,
-Dr. Rush. As an lOA representative...
-We have found quarters nearby
-much more comfortable. Please go there...
-l think you need to...
...and stay there until you're asked
to do something useful.
Something useful?
We do not want to settle in!
-We want to get back! Right?
-Yeah.
We should be working on getting home.
-WRAY: Exactly.
-l'm not sure if that's even possible.
What? You haven't even tried!
Maybe you should actually do something
instead of standing around,
-talking about being in charge.
-lf that's even true.
Everybody! Everyone, calm down!
Now, the fact is
Colonel Young put me in charge,
and l expect all SG personnel
to follow my orders.
As for the rest of you, you get out of line,
we will lock you down.
Now, Dr. Rush is right
about a couple things.
First off, we all have to work together,
and second of all, we don't all have
to stay here, so let's move out.
-Go on, move. lt's okay.
-SOLDlER 1 : All right. You heard him.
SOLDlER 2: Do as he says, people.
(PEOPLE MURMURlNG)
l think we need you,
so l've got your back for now,
but if l were you, l would find some way
to dial that gate back to Earth.
l've got some testing equipment over here.
Looks broken.
-We'll get back to that.
-What about all these Ancient crates?
lf it's not ours, don't touch it.
VOLKER: Did no one think
of labeling anything?
Every case has a bar code.
All right, anyone find a bar code reader?
l guess that got left behind
along with the food and water.
-Uh-uh. We got food.
-Yeah, protein bars and this powdered stuff.
Look, everybody.
Seeds? Volker, you've got to be kidding.
PALMER: l got a case of blank paper.
VOLKER: Maybe we should
start a suggestion box.
What are you staring at?
-You were in detention.
-Yeah.
-For good reason.
-GREER: What did you want him to do?
-Leave me there?
-Of course not.
l was just wondering
what to do about it now.
-That's not up to you.
-We'll see.
No, no, no. Don't do it, man.
SCOTTON RADIO:: Greer, I need you
to check for any open buIkhead doors
that Iead to damaged parts of the ship:
Rush wiII direct you:
Copy.
RUSH ON RADIO:: There shouId be
an eIevator directIy ahead:
Copy that.
-Are you there yet?
-This is Scott. Radio silence, please.
-Hey.
What's going on?
We almost lost you.
You were thrown clear across the room.
-Where are we?
-Sir...
(GROANS )
-Where are we?
-We're on a ship.
lt's Ancient.
Rush says it's thousands of years old
and we're pretty far off into the universe.
-What's he doing to get us home?
-He says he's working on it,
but we have bigger problems.
The life-support system
isn't working properly.
lf we can't get it fixed,
there's not much time.
You should also know that he used
the communication stones to contact Earth,
and he said General O'Neill
put him in charge.
l don't think so. l don't think... Oh...
Sir, you shouldn't be trying
to get up just yet, okay?
l don't think l have a choice, T.J.
l can't feel my legs.
-Whoa, jeez!
-ELl: Whoa !
What is that thing?
Come here, l'll show you.
(DEVlCE BEEPlNG)
lt's a... lt's a camera.
lt's a flying camera. l'm calling it a Kino,
you know, after the Russian...
-Yeah.
-Okay.
Well, l figure maybe we can use it
to check out the damaged areas of the ship.
-That's good.
-Yeah.
-That's good. Where's it going now?
-Oh, l don't know. lt's just doing its thing,
but there's lots more of them.
(ELl CHUCKLES )
-Yeah, it's cool.
-Yeah!
-Do you want one?
-lt's not a gumball machine, Eli.
Okay.
-Okay!
-Okay, so you figured out
where they keep the Kinos.
What else have you figured out?
Give me a break, man. This is my second
spaceship, and my first was yesterday.
l know. lcarus was my first SGC
assignment after training.
l haven't been at this
much longer than you have.
Did they beam you out of your house?
-(CHUCKLES ) No. You got me there.
-Got any food on you?
-No.
-Tylenol?
-Headache?
-Yeah.
Me, too.
Neuropraxia is temporary paralysis
that can follow a concussive injury.
You don't know?
You'd need an MRl and a qualified doctor
who knows how to read it
to know for sure if there's spinal damage.
We don't have either.
Hopefully, it's just the nerves in shock.
Best l can do is insist that you remain still.
Your tour was over two weeks ago.
You should be in some classroom
in San Diego.
Seattle. That's where my scholarship was.
-l'm sorry.
-That part's not your fault.
Tell Rush l want to see him.
Yes, sir.
-What's that?
-Flying camera ball.
-l'm calling it a Kino.
-Don't ask.
-That's marvelous.
-lt comes with a remote.
l thought we could use it to look around.
-What do you have?
-Well, it's not so good, really.
These processing nodes are scrubbers,
responsible for cleaning CO2 from the air.
Here, here, and here, it's indicating
malfunction. Others are failing.
Greer, this is Scott. l'm heading
for the Gate Room. Meet me there.
Look, l'm just saying
that she better stay out of my face.
l'll remind her of your personal space issues
next chance l get.
Dr. Rush? Colonel Young wants
to see you right away.
There should be a kind of grate
covering the node.
RUSH:: What do you see?
SCOTT: A problem.
We see a very big problem.
What happened?
You collapsed. We brought you here.
-What's going on?
-l'm not sure. l've been here with you.
l need to know what's happening, Chloe.
This is important.
Dad, l was worried about you.
-Okay.
-And l'm scared.
One step at a time, honey.
One step at a time.
-My pills...
-No, Dad, you can't take any more of those.
Your ribs are badly bruised.
You will bleed internally.
lf l don't take those pills, a bruise
is going to be the least of my problems.
l know.
Don't worry about me. Go.
Find out what's going on out there.
No, l want to be here with you.
And l want you here, but right now,
l want to know what's going on
just a little bit more.
Okay.
l'll be here when you get back.
-Okay.
(BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
-What's going on?
-l don't know, man.
The air filter's full of crap. Come on.
They want us to keep looking.
-Let's go.
-All right, okay.
Alkaline.
Everyone's heart rates are elevated,
people are reporting headaches.
-lt has to be.
-What?
The used-up residue
of whatever magic compound
the Ancients used
to scrub CO2 from the air.
So, now we have two big problems
relating to the life support.
Our first priority must be to
seal off any of the leaks.
lf we can manage that, then we can
maybe buy ourselves a day or so
before the buildup of CO2 kills us.
-As it stands, how much time do we have?
-l don't know.
Couple of hours at most.
Huh. Awesome.
Brody, there was some medical-grade
soda lime in the supply manifest?
-lt never made it.
-That's a pity.
Well, in a ship this old
there's bound to be systems
past their designed life.
Okay, let's say we find the leaks.
Can you fix this?
l doubt this stuff can be cooked off.
Perhaps if there were stores
of this substance in a clean form,
or something else capable of
CO2 sequestration, calcium carbonate,
lithium hydroxide, then yes, ''if.''
Okay, well, that's not going to matter
because you're going to get the gate
dialed back to Earth
before this becomes an issue,
-Rush, right?
-Lieutenant...
That's the kind of thing
you're taught to say in officer training,
presumably for the benefit of
those who don't know any better.
Please.
What makes you think l won't try?
Looks like a mess.
Lots of stuff to put food on.
But no food.
Greer, l found what looks like a shuttle.
Looks like there are two shuttles,
attached to individual docking sleeves.
Greer, l found what looks like a shuttle.
Looks like there are two shuttles,
attached to individual docking sleeves.
-We're all going to die.
-GREER: Shut up, Franklin.
l'm just saying
what everyone's got to be thinking.
l said shut up,
or else you're going to be the first.
-We're all going to die.
-GREER: Shut up, Franklin.
l'm just saying
what everyone's got to be thinking.
l said shut up,
or else you're going to be the first.
This the door?
Yeah, yeah, that's it. Can you close it?
lt won't close.
We can't close it from here, either.
There's something wrong
with the mechanism.
We can't close it from here, either.
There's something wrong
with the mechanism.
FRANKLlN: l think l found the leak.
There's another door
on the back of the shuttle,
but there's no control.
Then maybe we can close it off locally.
FRANKLlN: The shield keeping the air inside
is obviously not 100% effective.
RUSH: Probably wasn't
designed to compensate
for the amount of damage
the ship has sustained.
FRANKLlN: ls there a way of boosting it?
At least in the areas we need it?
RUSH: We haven't found a way yet.
lt seems to be operating
at maximum capability.
(ELl GASPlNG)
ELl: Open the door!
Well, that's not good.
That's very good, sir. A very good sign.
l don't have time for this, do l?
Two problems. We're venting atmosphere
from a damaged shuttle,
and even if we could seal it off,
the life-support system in this ship
is past its expiration date.
We'll build up CO2
to lethal levels within a day.
Well, that explains the headache.
You already had one.
They'll find a way.
That's what these people do.
Well, most of these people
aren't even supposed to be here.
-How did the ship get damaged?
-We don't know.
lt certainly looks like it's been through
a battle, at least the parts we can access.
We're still cut off from most of the ship.
lt's huge.
They tried jamming something into
the shuttle doorway to keep it open
long enough to let
the person inside get out...
But it just opens again.
Some sort of safety mechanism,
like an elevator.
Rush says he can't override it.
How long do we have right now?
As it stands...
Rush says if we don't get it closed,
we've got...
...just over an hour.
Bad air's better than no air.
Guess a day's better than an hour.
Someone's got to go in there
and close this door.
My head is pounding.
Heartbeat has accelerated.
lt's getting harder and harder to breathe,
as our very lives
are being vented out into space.
That is going to get old very fast.
-This needs to be documented.
-No one's going to see that.
How do you know?
We made it here. Someone else could, too.
lf we die, maybe this can help them
to find out what happened to us.
Yeah, well, we're not dead yet.
l'm starting to have slightly blurred...
-Eli!
-What?
So how are we going to decide who?
RUSH: l assume we're not going
to get any volunteers.
What's another day going to buy us?
Time, to find a way to survive.
May l see the list?
JOHANSEN: l marked the names
of anyone injured.
Right. We have to find out people's
skills, background, experience...
Doesn't take any special skills
to die from asphyxiation!
Look. What l'm saying is,
it shouldn't be someone
with potentially valuable knowledge
or abilities we might need
to help us survive beyond this.
Are you really suggesting
-what l think...
-Half the people on this ship
-already want to kill you.
-l don't care.
You can't ask someone
to sacrifice themselves, period.
Politicians ask military personnel
to sacrifice themselves
for the good of others all the time.
lf someone doesn't go in there
and close that door,
we're all going to die, period.
Franklin is still working at
the airlock controls locally,
but it doesn't look good, sir.
Camile's explaining the situation
to everyone onboard.
-l'll do it.
-Sir?
This isn't the kind of thing l can ask
somebody else to volunteer for.
lf we're going to make it past this,
we're going to need you, sir.
l don't know about that. You're doing
a pretty good job without me, Lieutenant.
Yeah? Well, look at the mess we're in.
-lf that's not proof that we need you, then...
-Look, l'm not sure anyone should do it.
l don't want someone sacrificing
themselves for me.
l say we figure this out together
while we still have time,
-or we all die trying.
-l want you to both listen to me.
lt needs to be done, and l'm doing it.
-Look, sir, you can barely stand.
-Help me.
Look, the paralysis is temporary.
-You know that now. You will recover.
-Lieutenant, l need your help.
-No, sir.
-l gave you an order.
-l know.
You can have me court-martialed
when we get home,
but l am not going to help you kill yourself.
My father's not in his room.
We'll find him. He does not leave this room.
-SCOTT: He can't have gotten far.
-l told him what was going on.
Greer, this is Scott, come in. Greer?
Greer, do you read?
Senator Armstrong is missing.
He may be headed your way.
He's here.
He's got a gun.
l don't want to shoot you.
l don't think you want to shoot me.
-Get out of the way.
-FRANKLlN: Just give me a little more time.
-Let me try and fix this.
-l don't have much.
ELI:: Guys, I'm not seeing any change:
Whatever you just tried,
it's not working!
The problem's obviously mechanical.
You can't fix it.
Tell me what to do.
Dad! No, wait!
Dad, no! No! No! No!
(MUFFLED ) Open the door!
-Open the door, please!
-l can't!
Please open the door!
(CHLOE CRYlNG)
-He was dead on his feet.
-Dad, no!
(SOFTLY) l love you.
(SOBBlNG) Please open the door. No!
Eli! Not him !
There's nothing l can do for him here.
HeIp him! Open the door, pIease!
Please! No. No! No!