This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
That ship is the best chance
we have of getting home.
- Are we done?
- We'll never be done.
You shouldn't have
left him on the planet.
You think I don't know that?
Everyone thinks we're safe.
They think that they'll never find us again.
Why did you take
one of our people prisoner?
We're not safe, are we?
They're coming!
- Who's coming?
Lucian Alliance,
they're coming to take Destiny.
There's only one way
this is gonna end if we wait.
I'm not
surrendering this ship.
I've managed to find a clue
which may give us control of this
ship once and for all.
It's the number of chromosomes
in the human DNA.
All we have to do now
is run through the variations.
I was never your conscience, Nicholas.
I haven't forgotten you, Gloria.
There can only be one
commander, and Kiva's dead.
What are we doing to get the ship back?
They're going to kill me.
I thought you were
going to get some sleep.
Yeah, so did I.
What's going on here, then?
Some sort of crash.
The interface is frozen.
Yeah? Why didn't you call me?
Well, I was going to try a restart first.
That's fixed it in the past.
- What did you just do?
- Seems I fixed the problem.
- Yeah, I can see that. How?
- Good night, Dr. Park.
Glad to see
you have everything well in hand.
Wait, where are you going?
For a walk.
You get into trouble next time, call me.
You're not going to tell anyone,
are you?
- Gloria.
- Your program finally worked.
Unlocked the master code.
You found the keys to controlling all of
Destiny's systems, everything.
And you're not going to tell anyone,
are you?
Ancient legend said the address
led to great understanding.
It could make you as powerful as the Gods.
Which Gods?
Don't ask me.
I assume it meant God-like power.
Like the ascended Ancients.
If you could control time and space...
Wait. You think that
Destiny is capable of that?
I don't know. That's what the legend said.
You asked me why the Lucian Alliance
wanted the ship so badly.
Why are you here?
I'm trying to understand your perspective.
You really want me to go over
the last 12 or 13 years?
The how and the why
of the Lucian Alliance?
They're warlords.
On my home planet,
they would burn our farms,
so we had nothing to eat
but the food they supplied.
They told our teachers what to teach.
Children were given weapons
and trained to fight.
Two years ago,
I was taken by a gang at gunpoint
and told if I didn't join the Alliance
Guard my family was going to be murdered.
So, you're saying that
you had no choice in any of this?
We're not getting enough food.
None of us are.
We haven't been able to replenish
our supplies in some time.
You're saying we could all starve?
Yes.
What are you going to do with us?
You can't keep us locked
in that hold forever.
That hasn't been determined yet.
Colonel Young,
he's going to make that decision?
I will have a say.
Some of us have been co-operative.
Yes, you have.
There is more we can do.
There are those among us
who are no danger to you.
Please, give us a chance
to prove it to you.
What are they going to do with us?
They didn't tell me anything.
I'm a traitor.
You know Young. What will he do?
I used to know him. Trust me, he's changed.
You've got to be kidding me.
It's hardly worth sitting down.
Yeah, maybe we shouldn't be
giving our rations to the enemy.
They're human beings. They have rights.
How we treat prisoners of war
says everything about us
as a moral and civil society.
Which pamphlet did you get that from?
It's what I believe.
I don't care how secure they are.
I can't sleep knowing
there's a room full of people on this ship
who would kill me first chance they got.
- You know, HR was my job on Icarus.
- And psych evals are T.J.'s responsibility.
She's going to need some time.
It's going to be hard enough for her
to fulfill her duties as medic.
Great. Fine. Thanks.
The IOA reports our conflict
with the Lucian Alliance
in the Milky Way is escalating.
Intel suggests
they may be planning an attack on Earth.
Have you learned anything
from the prisoners?
Not yet.
It would help if I could reassure them
that we're not just going to
pump them for information
- and then dump them on the next planet.
- Really?
Well, they dumped us on a planet to die.
Is everyone on board
willing to starve for them?
We haven't come to that point yet...
How ugly are you willing
to let this get, Camile?
I'm just asking because
I don't think this has anything to do
with the proper treatment of POWs,
and you know it.
They tried to kill us,
and we do not have the capability to hold
onto these prisoners over the long haul.
They're not all dangerous.
If you would just read my report...
"I was just following orders"
is a claim that I've heard before.
People will say anything
to save themselves, Camile.
So we're just going to
leave them on the next viable planet
and then wash our hands of it?
Let's hope we find a viable planet.
You thought this was going to be easier,
didn't you?
You thought all you'd need to do
was turn the key.
This ship, its systems were designed
to be run by an entire crew.
Well, you have a crew.
Yeah, a crew that knows
what they're doing.
This is what you wanted.
You know, the Ancients, they never intended
Destiny to operate on its own.
They were supposed to come here,
in person.
There was a point to this mission.
There had to be.
And yet, the first thing you did
was turn the autopilot system back on.
Until I can be sure
I know how to use each function.
I wouldn't want to stop accidentally in
range of another binary pulsar, would I?
Good plan.
You see, right now, I'm
trying to understand
why Destiny stops at some planets
and not others.
Maybe they're just rest stops.
Designed to let people get out,
stretch their legs, smell the roses,
but in the grand scheme of
Destiny's greater mission,
not very important.
Certainly environments can change
significantly through the years,
become dangerous, even.
But that would mean Destiny's got some
kind of real-time subspace link to the gates.
And look, here,
this planet we're approaching,
different classification entirely,
not merely locked out,
but it seems to be non-functional.
So it seems.
So very helpful.
Do you remember the long walks
we used to take in the gardens back home?
Wherever we were, we'd always find
a quiet place to call our own.
That's it. We need food now.
This planet we're approaching
should be rich in plant life.
A big red X generally means
"Danger, don't go there," doesn't it?
Is this your only purpose,
to question my actions?
So, what are you going to do?
Oh, well, I'll take that as a yes, then.
There has to be a reason
the Destiny dropped out.
There is.
- Where have you been?
Busy. We're in range of a planet that
looks like it may have food and water.
Riley says there are no gates.
Shuttle range.
Wow, look at that.
Well, how does Destiny have data
on a planet with no gate on it?
Well, there is a gate on it.
It appears to be non-functioning.
So Destiny just happened to drop out
close enough for us to use the shuttle?
- That's convenient...
- Well, it's not magic.
As I've been doing all along,
I've been telling Destiny any way
I can how short of resources we are.
Well, we'll send a team.
Okay, I suggest we land close to the gate,
try and determine why it's not working,
maybe even repair it.
Shuttle trip will take just under an hour.
Less than seven hours total
is not much time.
However, if we can get
the gate operational,
we'll be able to transport a lot more
food and water than the shuttle.
Two gates cannot dial each other
in this close a proximity.
This planet may well be in range
the next time we drop out of FTL.
If we can get the gate active, we might
be able to dial back down the line.
You want to go?
- No, no, I should stay here.
- Oh, what's more important right now...
Well, there's a number of systems
that's been malfunctioning of late.
I'm working on those, actually.
- Sir.
T.J.
I'm almost ready to go.
Just packing up my kit.
You...
You sure?
Well, I'll admit I'm not 100%,
but we're low on medicinals,
and I know we'll only be there a few hours,
so I should at least take a look around.
I'll take it easy.
Yeah. Yeah, I just... You know,
I wanted to make sure you're okay.
- Good luck down there.
- Thanks.
Dr. Rush has pinpointed
the Stargate's position on the surface,
and I've plotted a course.
Colonel Young, this is Scott.
All systems are go.
- We are ready for take-off.
- Go ahead, Lieutenant.
Roger that.
I'm worried about you, Nicholas.
Yeah, so am I. I've got work to do,
and I can't seem to leave myself alone.
You're missing things.
Dr. Franklin.
It's too much for one person.
I don't care how smart you are.
Okay, so tell me. What am I missing?
Well, for one, the data on the planet.
It's extensive. What about it?
You didn't notice the volcanic activity?
The atmospheric super-rotation?
A few minutes away now.
It'll be fine. They'll be fine.
You've based your calculation
on optimal structural integrity.
I based it on the specs in the database.
Which don't account for flaws
that were developed over,
I don't know, say, a million-plus years.
Lieutenant Scott, this is Dr. Rush.
Do you read?
Yeah, I hear you. Go ahead.
You're about to enter an area
of atmospheric super-rotation.
Okay, what does that mean?
Well, I've done some calculations,
and you will experience
some excessive turbulence,
but nothing
the shuttle wasn't built to handle.
Okay, thanks for the heads-up.
All right, you heard the man. Hang on.
It could be a little bit bumpy.
Not so bad.
Whoa!
All right, hang on, guys, hang on!
Lieutenant Scott, do you hear me?
Lieutenant Scott, can you hear me?
Yeah. Loud and clear.
We made it.
Glad to hear it.
Check back in once you've landed.
Will do. Scott out.
- Hang on!
- What's going on?
Just lost power!
Half of the systems are down.
Come on, come on...
You've got to give me something.
You've got to give me something. Come on.
- Pull up!
- I can't!
- T. J?
- Yeah?
Is anyone hurt?
- Over here.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
He's got a pulse.
- Everyone else okay?
- Yup. Yup.
- Dunning, you all right?
- Yeah.
Just relax. It's okay, just relax.
- Relax.
- I can't move.
Okay, don't try.
Now, just tell me where it hurts.
It doesn't hurt.
I can't feel my legs at all.
- Where's Rush?
- No idea. I called him.
This is Young. Go ahead, Lieutenant.
Still not sure
what happened, sir.
Like Rush said, it was a pretty rough ride
through the atmosphere.
Whoa, what do you mean, "Like Rush said"?
He called to warn us
on the ship's comm,
but it seemed like we made it through fine.
Then shortly after, I lost flight control.
Injuries?
Riley's legs are pinned for now.
T.J.'s working on him.
Everyone else is fine.
Right now we're trying
to get the back door open.
We took a lot of damage, sir.
One of the windows is gone.
Bottom line, I don't think we're
going to be flying out of here.
- Destiny is going to jump in six hours.
- And we can't stop it.
Lieutenant, this is Rush.
You need to find the gate,
get it operational.
Hopefully, the next time Destiny
drops out, we'll still be in range.
All right, copy that.
I'll check back in 30 minutes.
All right, you have a decent idea
which direction to go to find the gate?
- We'll figure it out.
- Hey, how's Riley?
I don't know.
All right, LT, you take
Eli, Volker and Greer.
Okay, let's go.
He's wedged in there pretty good.
I'm not sure
we should be trying to move him anyway.
We're gonna have to eventually.
I'm sure you're thinking
this probably wouldn't have happened
had we not been so desperate
for food and water.
- That doesn't matter now.
- I reported to the IOA.
- I don't care.
- They insist that you keep
- the prisoners on board... Colonel...
- Camile, I don't care.
We need backup
in the prisoners' hold immediately!
Stand down!
Back up against the wall!
Now!
Hold it right there!
Break it up!
Grab his arm!
Stand down now!
Hey, come on, over here!
Lieutenant! Sergeant!
I got him!
Hold him down!
Everett!
Leave it!
I don't see anything!
I've got no addresses coming up.
- Well, this is where it should be.
You sure?
No, if I was sure, there'd be a gate here.
Okay, stop, stop, stop!
Okay, I'm going to try and reach in there
and see if I can feel anything. Okay?
Lift it up.
T.J., we can't hold this...
- Okay!
His leg's stuck pretty good.
I think the pressure's actually helping
cut off circulation to a wound.
Okay. Destiny just jumped.
This is not good.
Oh, try not to panic.
Experience tells me
that this is a very good time to panic.
What are the odds it will still be in range
next time it drops out?
It's impossible to know.
Hey!
I found it.
The gate? You can see it from there?
Where? I... I don't see it.
Look down.
You need to sleep
or you're just gonna make more mistakes.
You know, it would be easier
if you would actually help.
What makes you think I can?
- Can I speak to Franklin?
- Who?
One of two things is happening here.
Either I'm losing my mind
or you and Dr. Franklin are somehow
being manifested by the ship
in order to communicate with me.
Now, he tends to be a little bit more
helpful when it comes to technical matters.
Let's see. What are you trying to do?
Figure out how to control
how long Destiny stops
when it drops out of FTL.
Okay, can't help you with that, sorry.
Right. I am losing my mind, then.
There don't seem to be any Stargates coming
up in Destiny's immediate path.
Now, I'll have to stop this ship soon
or we're going to be out of range
of the planet the team's stranded on.
And with no other gates in range,
you don't know how to explain
to everyone else why the ship has stopped.
Exactly. I can't just keep
dropping in and out of FTL.
I'm going to
damage the drives permanently.
They have to run for a minimum of
four hours each time they're activated,
which means, next time I drop out,
I've got one last shot at this.
Why don't you just tell the truth?
Ask for help?
No... No, I can't.
Because Colonel Young can't be trusted?
He let the Lucian Alliance
take over this ship.
The man is mentally unstable.
And he's getting worse all the time.
He nearly just killed a man.
Your negligence caused
the shuttle to crash.
The situation is desperate because of him.
He's not fit to lead this mission.
- Hey.
- How's Riley?
He's stuck pretty good.
He's... He's losing a lot of blood.
There's no way to get him free?
T.J. thinks the pressure from the wreckage
is what's keeping him from bleeding out.
There's got to be something we can do.
Let's get this gate uncovered.
Are you in any pain?
I'm okay.
You ever been in this situation before?
Stuck on an alien planet
after a shuttle crash?
No, this one's a first for me.
I meant having to tend to someone
that you knew was gonna die.
Yeah. I have.
Sounds crazy, but I came so close lately
with the explosion and then getting shot.
I kind of figured
that maybe it just wasn't my time.
I'm not all that spiritual,
but my mother's pretty religious.
Anglican.
She'd be praying for me right now
if she knew.
My dad, he always said it was stupid,
but he always went to church with her.
I won't leave you if it...
If it comes to it.
Do you believe in anything?
God? The afterlife?
I don't know.
Since we've been here,
we've seen some incredible things.
We know that there's so much
we don't understand,
beings more powerful than us.
Can I tell you something
that I haven't told anyone?
Sure. Who am I going to tell, right?
Remember that planet that we stopped at
that we thought was created by aliens?
Yeah.
I know this sounds crazy,
but I went back there.
I don't know if it was a dream,
a vision maybe.
They said that they came and got me.
They have my baby,
and she's safe there.
Do you believe that?
It felt real.
And I don't know how to explain it.
I want it to be possible.
It's just that little... Little bit of hope.
It makes things bearable, so...
So I let it live.
I want to apologize
for my people's behavior.
Next viable planet we stop at,
you're all going to be left there.
I expect co-operation until such time
or appropriate force will be used
to maintain order.
You know, I think I remember
reading somewhere
that a big enough explosion
close enough to a Stargate
can detonate the super-conductive material
that it's made of.
The resulting explosion
can take a chunk out of a planet.
Well, it's not going to...
It's not gonna be that big.
You're sure?
I... We don't have much of a choice, do we?
It could take weeks to dig this thing out.
Hopefully, the blast won't damage the gate.
Do you want me to flip the switch or not?
- Yeah, yeah. Oh, yeah, sure...
- I'm flipping the switch.
No, flip it already.
Fire in the hole!
That was pretty big.
I used the communication stones.
Okay. We'll just skip over the fact
that I didn't authorize that.
I have a short list.
Based on intel provided
by both myself and Camile Wray.
You're being ordered to keep a select
number of Lucian Alliance onboard
who may prove valuable.
And if I don't,
I assume you're going to tell me
that you've been ordered
to relieve me of my command.
You think you've earned the trust of
the men and women on this ship enough
for them to follow you?
Military personnel are still
in the service of Stargate Command
and expected to follow orders.
Rush, this is Young. Where are you?
It's less than three hours.
The address to the planet came up,
but it's still locked out.
The strange thing is that
there are no other planets in range.
- Nothing.
- Why'd we drop out?
- Exactly. It doesn't make sense.
- Suggestions?
Try to bypass the lock-out. Dial anyway.
It's a long shot.
It's all we got.
Rush, we're headed to the Gate Room.
- Where have you been?
- Engine Control Room.
Doing what?
Well, the FTL drive's still suffering
some effects from the pulsar radiation,
stopping at shorter intervals now,
but regardless of whether
we're in range of a planet or not.
You feel that?
Hey, science guys, this thing is shaking.
- Someone's trying to dial in.
- Oh, clear the event horizon.
- The address is here. We've got Destiny!
- Shaking's stopped.
Everyone, back away.
I'm going to try to dial them.
It's working. It's working!
Destiny, this is Scott.
Permission to come aboard.
Permission granted.
Glad to see you guys are okay.
Where are the others?
Riley's not going to make it, sir.
Sir.
Sir, I'm not just gonna let him die alone.
Can you give me a minute?
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
Sorry, sir.
You are a fine soldier, a good man.
None of this is your fault.
You know that.
Don't stay on my account.
Just make them leave.
I don't want anyone to
risk being stuck here.
I'm not going to be around
that much longer.
What can I tell your family?
Nothing really seems like enough.
How long do you think he'll last?
I don't know.
How much time until Destiny jumps?
No, we're good. We're fine.
I don't want you to worry, okay?
I'd ask for your gun,
but I don't want them to blame you.
Sir...
Please.
I'm in pain.
I'll get T.J.
No.
No!
Please.
He's gone.
You know, you'd figure
being stranded on this ship
in the middle of nowhere with a bunch
of strangers would be the problem,
but that isn't it exactly.
To Riley.
It's not, it's not so much
being out here as it is not being there.
For the birthdays,
the weddings, the funerals...
Simple things like just taking your
nephew to school on his first day,
or even taking the dog for a walk.
You now, just not...
Not being there.
There was nothing
that could be done for Riley.
Stalling Destiny any longer
wouldn't have helped him.
I know.
Well, you think I don't know?
All of this is my fault.
I was trying to save lives,
all of our lives, not just my own.
This database just confirms
what I knew all along.
This ship was named
Destiny for a reason.
It must be like Rush said,
another short jump
because of the radiation effect.
Something just came up on sensors.
This is Rush.
Meet me in the observation deck.
I heard the radio chatter.
What's going on?
There's an object out there.
It's just coming into range.
Well, what is it?
We're not sure,
but we're about to find out.
We're headed straight for it.
English - US - SDH