I may be on the verge of discovering
the true nature ofDestiny's mission.
You've had control of this ship
the whole time!
Why wouldn't you tell anyone?
The Lucian Alliance is planning an
attack on Earth.
I killed Riley.
I suffocated him with my own hands.
You are a good commander.
There is no mission other
than getting these people home.
It was never about going home, it's
about getting us to where we're going.
That is the mission.
And this is Varro, one
of our remaining Alliance guests.
I haven't seen you in a while.
Your kidneys are failing.
End-stage renal disease.
The only other option for treatment
would be a transplant.
He won't reject it.
Great, no pressure.
There might be a little infection
setting in there.
I'm fine.
- Eli, what the hell did you do?
- Goodbye.
I transferred the memory where
they were stored into quarantine.
They're cut off from the
rest of the ship now, and us.
That's what I did. To save you.
Wow. Space deer.
They're beautiful.
They're going to look
even more beautiful
slow-roasted and served up
with a side of Becker's mash.
You're not serious.
Uh... And how exactly would you cook 'em?
- I wouldn't. I'm a vegetarian.
- No.
For the past 10 months,
we have all been vegetarian.
I am dying for a steak.
I could use a steak.
No, you guys can't kill those creatures,
and this has nothing to do
with being a vegetarian.
I mean,
we don't know anything about them.
They could be intelligent.
We just saw one of them eat its own vomit.
How smart can they be?
Guys! I could use some help over here.
Okay, look, I'll tell you what,
if they can give me one good reason
why I shouldn't eat them, I won't,
but it better be a good one,
because I am mighty hungry.
- Lieutenant?
Let's do it.
Not cool.
- Want me to take it?
- No. No.
I got it.
- Damn!
- What the heck happened?
Something must've spooked them.
We've got plenty of time.
Want to go after 'em?
Hell, yeah.
- What was that?
- Hang on.
Shoot! Shoot it!
Shoot it!
It's heading for the camp!
By the time we got there, it was gone.
Was anybody hurt?
No fatalities, but plenty of injuries,
and two missing.
Reynolds and T.J.
- Permission to go after them, sir.
- Permission denied.
Sir, I know things may look bad,
but there is still a chance
that T.J. and Reynolds
could be alive down there.
Which is why we need to find them
as fast as possible.
I'm going to need you here, Lieutenant.
While I'm gone, you're in charge.
You got a problem with that?
No, sir.
Hey! What are you doing?
Checking to see what's inside.
Why, what does it look like I'm doing?
Come on.
I thought the whole point of exploring
unexplored sections of the ship
was to, well, explore them.
- We are.
- Yeah? Not really.
Well, what can I say?
Rush wants us to take a cautious approach.
Who cares what Rush thinks?
He's not our boss.
You tell him that.
- I will.
- No, you won't.
- I am not afraid of him.
- Afraid of whom?
"Who." I think it's "who." "Afraid of who."
Afraid not.
Hey, what've we got here?
This is one of the last
rooms in this section.
I'm guessing more Ancient containers.
I want to see them rescued
as much as anyone,
but we have to consider the possibility
that they may already be dead.
We swept the area. If they were dead,
why didn't we find the bodies?
Maybe the creature dragged them away,
took them somewhere
it wouldn't be disturbed.
Neither of them
are responding to radio communications.
Maybe they're unconscious,
or their radios were lost or damaged,
I don't know.
All I'm saying is we can hope for the best
as long as we're prepared for the worst.
You're right.
Why don't you guys meet us at the gate?
You mind telling me
what happened back there on the planet?
You had the shot, you didn't take it.
Why not?
I don't know.
If it's a moment of indecision
just one of those things,
then you can drop it,
but if there is a problem,
you need to find out what it is,
and you need to fix it. Fast.
Yes, sir.
- Stasis pods?
- Yeah.
Obviously designed
for lengthy intergalactic journeys.
We've got multiple rooms
exactly like this one, going both ways.
It's fascinating.
That's a bit of an understatement.
This is huge.
Agreed.
Okay, let's leave it for now. Let's go.
What? You can't be serious.
Well, given recent events, it may be wise
to check over the ship's data
on this compartment before proceeding.
Sergeant, hold up.
I think we lost its trail.
- We should double back.
- Well, we need to keep moving forward.
Well, not if we're headed the wrong way.
Back the way we came is the wrong way.
We keep moving forward,
we'll pick up the trail again. Trust me.
All right, you guys check out the area,
see if you can spot any tracks.
Sergeant. What's up?
We're up against the clock here, sir.
Which is why we can't afford
to make any more mistakes.
Listen to me,
I know this is tearing you apart,
but what's done is done.
And you let guilt
start dictating your actions,
you're just asking for trouble.
I don't know, maybe you needed more time
to recuperate after surgery.
I'm fine, sir.
Then get your head on straight.
James, Marsden...
Any updates from the planet?
They've lost the trail,
so they're doubling back.
I'd like to volunteer to help
with this rescue op.
Well, much appreciated,
but Colonel Young and his team
are more than capable
of seeing this through.
With all due respect, no, they're not.
They have the training,
but they lack the necessary experience.
Me and my people
have been hunting most of our lives.
We can track this animal for you.
We can do it better, faster than anyone
you've got down there
on the ground right now.
When this is over,
you're gonna wanna know
that you did everything in your power
to save them.
Right?
Well, it happened so fast.
One minute I was helping
to catalog plant samples,
and the next I was on the ground
and everyone was screaming.
Hey. I just heard.
Come to check up on us, huh?
Yeah. Yeah, I came to check up on you both.
- How are you?
- In constant pain.
I think my ankle's broken.
Every time I move...
Well, hang in there. How about you?
According to the medical scan,
a cracked rib.
Ha! I should be so lucky.
How do you...
How do you treat a cracked rib?
You don't. Speaking from personal
experience, snowboarding accident,
you just take it easy.
It'll heal itself in about a month.
In a month?
Okay. Is there anything you need?
Anything I can do?
Yeah, could you take off my sock?
- Are you serious, dude?
- My foot's swelling up!
I'll get that for you.
- Thanks for coming by.
- Yeah, it was nothing.
Rush had me up on the bridge
running diagnostics.
I really appreciate it.
Yeah, no, I just wanted to make sure
you were all right.
Lieutenant?
Lieutenant!
Oh, thank God.
- Where are we?
- I don't know.
How did we get here?
The thing that attacked the camp,
it took us here.
We must've lost our sidearms
in the commotion.
Your radio, too.
Here, I've got mine, but it's damaged.
We have to get out of here.
I can't put any weight on my leg.
I think it might be broken.
It could just be a fracture. Hang tight.
If this thing wanted to kill us,
we'd be dead already.
So I figure that's a good thing, right?
It wants us alive.
It's saving us.
Saving us? From what?
Not from anything.
It's saving us for later.
- I don't like it.
- Yeah, well, you don't have to like it,
just pretend you do,
at least until we get our people back.
Here they come.
It's about time.
We just wanted to check out the campsite.
- We appreciate your help.
- Don't mention it.
We're all in this together, right?
The fact that there's no significant blood
at the campsite is a good sign.
It suggests the creature wanted them alive.
Why?
Probably likes its meat fresh.
Which means we've got to move quickly.
The sooner we locate them, the better,
because this rescue op has the potential
to turn into a recovery mission real fast.
- Looks like it's going to get dark soon.
- Here!
Partial print there and there,
heading off in that direction.
You know, we finally unseal a new section,
make the biggest discovery
aboard this ship since the bridge,
and now we're supposed to ignore it
because Rush says so?
Man wants to be cautious.
Since when is Rush cautious?
Well, I guess having your consciousness
trapped in a simulation will do that to you.
- Screw this.
- Where you going?
To check out the stasis pods.
And don't tell on me, all right?
Wait for me.
- Wait, wait, wait. Where are you going?
- Relax, Corporal.
- How does it look?
- Not good.
That thing is still down there.
It's guarding its lair,
and you're in no condition
to make a run for it.
Look, Lieutenant, please,
I know you'd stand a better chance
out there without me, but I need...
Listen! I'm not leaving you behind,
and when the time comes,
I am going to need your help.
So I need you to calm down.
You need to get it together, okay?
- Can you do that?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
Oh, hey. I'm just on my way to the mess.
Can I get you anything?
No, I'm good, thank you.
Hey, how's the search going?
I don't know. I haven't heard anything
since Varro and his team went down.
- Let us hope that makes a difference.
- Yeah.
It's times like these that really
make you appreciate what you have,
- who you have.
- Yeah, for sure.
It's like...
Well, having Matt
has made such a difference,
knowing he's there for me no matter what.
I'm really lucky to have that someone.
So does Lisa know?
Know what?
How you feel about her.
I know it's probably none of my business,
but I saw the way
you two were together and...
We were? No, no, no. Lisa...
Lisa and I, we're just...
It's strictly... Professional.
Platonic. Professionally platonic.
We're not...
- Oh, I'm sorry. I totally misread...
- Oh, no, no, it's a simple mistake.
No, no, that happens,
you know, sometimes.
So you're going to the mess hall?
- Yes. Mmm.
- Yeah.
- That's where I'm going.
- Okay. Thank you.
I'm just saying, recent events
have made me put things in perspective.
Like, who made him de facto leader?
He did. He was lead scientist on Icarus.
You know, I'm the one who solved
the mystery of the ninth chevron.
Yeah, thanks for that.
So what are you saying?
You want to be lead scientist?
No. I just... I think it's time
that we all had more of a say
in the decisions that are being made.
I'm tired of him deciding
what's best for us.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Whoa! Hold on!
- Hey, hey!
- Whoa.
Thanks. Great. What did you do?
- I didn't do anything. What did...
- You accidentally pressed something!
- Now, hit the "open" button.
- Oh, 'cause there's a...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
I can't... Oh, that can't...
- Hey! Eli!
- Okay, hang on, hold on!
- Crap! I got it!
- Eli, what're you...
Maybe... Can we...
You guys do much
hunting back on Earth?
Not unless
you count fishing.
Well, growing up, my brother and I,
we learned from my father,
how to hunt, kill,
but the most important things he taught us
was respect for the wild.
There ain't nothing noble about
this thing. It's a monster.
Yeah, but unlike us,
animals don't know hate.
All they know is fear and hunger.
Hey, I got something here. The tracks,
they just stop.
Okay. There's been a lot of movement here.
Get down, get down!
Stop!
Get off me! We've got it on the run!
Now's our chance!
The hell we do!
Lt'll draw you out,
separate you from the group,
then pick you off!
What the hell do you think
happened back there?
It led us to that spot, it waited for us.
It's smart!
All this time we've been hunting it,
it's been hunting us.
- Are you ready?
- Do it!
- Got it.
- Yeah.
What?
Why didn't you pull that trigger?
There's no predicting how someone's
gonna react in a pressure situation.
Panic sets in. People freeze. It happens.
But not to you.
Something got inside your head. What?
I think I died.
After the kidney surgery,
during the recovery,
there was a point when I woke up
to nothing.
I couldn't hear, couldn't
see, couldn't move.
I was trapped in this darkness,
you know, like nothing I have ever known.
You were scared.
That's a normal reaction.
I've done some crazy things in my day.
Risked my life
without even giving it a second thought.
No fear.
But now,
all I know is that darkness
and the fact
that I don't ever want to go back.
T.J. had you under some pretty
heavy sedatives for that operation.
They shut you down.
Your brain was probably
the first thing to wake up,
and it just took the rest of your body
a little while to catch up.
You think that's what it was?
I can't claim to know
for sure what death is,
but I know in my heart it isn't that.
This should do till you
get back to the ship.
I'm not going back.
I'm not giving up on my people.
No one's giving up.
You've just got to think this through.
It won't take much
for those stitches to open up.
If you start bleeding out, then what?
I'm sorry, but in your condition,
you're a liability to us.
At best, you slow us down.
At worst, you die.
I'll get her back.
You have my word.
We need to get moving.
We can come back, bury the bodies later.
You listen to me,
you bring her back safe.
All right. Let's... Let's go.
Hello, Eli. Come in.
- Yeah?
- Good morning.
Is Mr. Brody with you?
Yep.
You two are supposed to be
in the control interface room
running diagnostics. Where are you?
We're just grabbing something to eat.
Yeah, well, hurry up.
I know it's not the most glamorous work,
but it needs to be done.
We'll finish up, be on our way.
Here?
This is good.
Good for what? Why are we stopping?
We've already established
this creature is smart.
It sees us as a threat,
so it's stalking us,
and sooner or later,
it's going to try to ambush us again,
but this time, we'll be ready for him.
Here we go.
How we doing for time?
We've got six hours till
Destiny jumps.
They wouldn't abandon us.
No, not unless they think we're dead.
Which is why I really need to get
this radio working.
Were you watching me sleep?
No, no. No, I was just
checking to see if you were...
If you were awake,
which you seemed not to be,
but then now... Then you are now.
- I brought you something to eat.
- Oh, that was sweet of you.
Dr. Park, how are you feeling?
I'm fine. Thanks.
How are getting on with those calculations?
Oh, yeah, I finished them.
I can't believe this.
You're making her work? She's injured.
Yes, her ribs, not her brain.
Dale, I asked him
to give me something to do.
I'm going stir-crazy just sitting here.
Good, good. See you back on the bridge.
Yeah, I'm just going to finish up
with my visit and...
Hey, take your time.
- Anything?
Nothing.
Not yet.
I got a bad feeling that this is a mistake.
I mean, while we're sitting here,
that thing is putting as much distance
between us as possible.
No, the creature knows we're hunting it,
so it needs to protect its lair.
To do that,
it has to make sure we never reach it.
Yeah.
Makes sense.
You know, but if you're wrong about this,
don't count on making it back to the ship.
You don't think I want to save them?
Yeah.
I'm sure you do.
You look like you got more to say.
Well, whatever you have in mind
for you and T.J.,
you can forget about it, you know?
'Cause that's not happening.
Why don't we let her decide that?
Varro.
- Go ahead, Tasia. - It's on the
move, it's headed your way.
Here we go.
Come on.
I'm right here.
I'm right here!
- Did you get it?
- Oh, yeah.
All right. We should get moving.
In a few hours,
it's going to start to get dark...
There are more of them out there.
Following their trail's
gotten way too easy.
It's almost as if
they're daring us to come after them.
They're luring us in to finish us off.
The thing that attacked us
back at the camp
is bigger than the ones we're tracking now.
These tracks are smaller.
These are the babies.
We're getting close to their lair.
The fact that we're dealing
with more than one of these things
reduces our chances
of finding our people alive.
Are you saying
you're having second thoughts?
Because, you know,
I can do this on my own.
Oh, no, you can't.
Hell, I don't even think
we can do this together,
but I'm gonna see this through.
Besides, this close to the nest,
we're past the point of no return.
That thing's too big, too strong.
I can't stand the thought
of being eaten alive.
When the time comes,
if I don't have the guts to do it myself...
What are you saying, Corporal?
I'm saying I don't want to die like that!
I'd rather you finished me off first!
Hey. Hey, you listen to me.
Now, you have two choices.
You can suck it up
and walk back on the Destiny
with your head held high,
or you can force me to save your sorry ass,
and live with the shame.
- Is that understood?
- Yes, ma'am.
This is...
This is Lieutenant Johansen. Over.
Is there anyone out there?
You remind me of someone
I used to run ops with.
First one into a firefight,
last one to leave enemy territory.
He was fearless.
He ended up volunteering
for what you'd call a suicide mission.
He wasn't afraid.
Turns out, he should've been.
He was wrong.
In those situations, when the odds
are stacked against you
and you're looking death in the face,
it's fear that keeps you
and the people around you alive.
This is Lieutenant Johansen.
- This is Greer. Over.
- Sergeant?
Lieutenant, what's your situation?
Corporal Reynolds and I are in a cave
on the side of a hill overlooking a ravine.
Somewhere north of camp.
The creature that attacked us,
it brought us here,
and it appears to be guarding its territory,
so approach with extreme caution.
The Corporal is injured and in
no condition to make a run for it.
Hang tight, Lieutenant.
We're coming for you.
Copy.
Sorry. Lost track of time.
Yeah, well, I'm not surprised.
You two obviously
enjoy each other's company.
I'm not sure if you meant anything by that,
but you should know there's nothing
going on between me and Park.
Of course not.
What do you mean "of course not"?
You say it like it could never happen.
Well, it couldn't.
Okay, I get it.
Because she's so attractive and I'm not?
No, no, no, no.
Let's just say that
you don't seem like the romantic type.
Oh, really? Okay.
Well, then what type am I?
The good friend type, obviously.
The trusted confidant.
The guy who's always there with the...
The shoulder to cry on.
And that's just life, I'm afraid.
We all have our predestined roles,
but, you know, on the bright side,
a life free of romantic entanglements,
well, it certainly benefits
the pursuit of science.
Seriously, Eli, I don't have time for this.
They need me in the infirmary.
Colonel Young and Lieutenant James
just got back. They're injured.
What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
He did this to himself.
- He was just in there pushing buttons...
- Is he okay?
Yes, according to the monitoring system,
he's fine.
Just frozen.
- Did you tell Rush?
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
And we're not going to. Not yet, anyway.
Just for once I'd like to solve a problem
without his help.
Eli, you have to get him out of there.
I know, which is why you're here.
You still have some of that
residual alien knowledge, right?
- Eli...
- Just do me a favor.
Take a look.
See if anything jumps out at you?
Um...
That's got to be it.
I'll go first, scout out the area.
If it's clear, I'll radio back.
I don't think so.
If you got something to say, say it.
I don't think you're up for this.
- You calling me a coward?
- No, you're not a coward,
but you're second-guessing yourself,
and that's a problem.
We don't have time for you
to sort through whatever issues
you're dealing with.
- So I'm going.
- No, I'm going.
But I'm going to need you
to create a little diversion for me.
We're going to be okay.
They're almost here.
- You ready, Corporal?
- Yes, ma'am.
Aim for its eyes.
Lieutenant!
- Don't shoot!
- What?
I don't think it wants to hurt us.
- I've got the shot, ma'am.
- No, the fire.
It recognizes intelligence.
Didn't stop it from trying to kill us.
That's because you were a threat to it
and its family.
It recognizes a threat and goes after it.
That's what I was counting on out there
to buy us some time
so I suggest that you start moving.
Slowly.
Let's go.
It's intelligent.
Smart enough to know
that I can cause it a world of hurt,
maybe even kill it,
and smart enough to know
that I'm choosing
not to.
Let's go.
No.
- So?
- I don't know, I'm not seeing...
doing?
What the hell?
That's that, then.
What's what?
I've just completed a thorough diagnostic
of one of the stasis pods.
Very informative.
How many of those things you take down?
About none, but I managed to lose them
and circle back.
I feel like I could sleep for a week.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Congratulations, I hear you're a free man.
Apparently, someone put in a good
word for me with Colonel Young.
As much as I'd like to take credit,
I really haven't had any time.
- I know. It was Sergeant Greer.
- Greer?
Mmm-hmm.
I'd love to thank him,
but I get the feeling he'll claim
he doesn't know what I'm talking about.
Yeah, probably.
Listen, I just wanted to come by
and say I'm sorry about your people,
and even though you may feel
like you're alone,
you're not.
I know.
Come in.
You had said you wanted to
lend your expertise to tonight's dinner.
Becker's ready.
You... You okay?
I'm good.
Good.
That completes this round of diagnostics.
Now we can move on to the fun part.
Fun part?
- Yeah, well,
it's time to go and check out
the stasis chambers now.
Whoa, whoa, not so fast.
Let's finish going through the data
on that section
before we start heading in there
and pushing buttons.
Yeah, of course, you're right.
Proceed with caution.
And what else?
- God, that's a good question.
- Yeah.
English - US - SDH