Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Hot.
Cool.
SCOTT: Make sure
we can dial back to the ship.
FRANKLIN: Already on it.
- PALMER: Looks like gypsum.
- That would be good.
Why?
- We're looking for calcium carbonate.
- RUSH: Calcite.
Gypsum is calcium sulfate,
which is 36% calcium carbonate.
ELI: Hmm.
Huh. It dissolves.
Are you saying we can use this sand
to fix the scrubbers?
- That would be convenient.
- PALMER: No.
RUSH: Well, it's a fair indication
that the components may exist nearby.
PALMER: For the sake
of portability and efficiency,
I'm hoping to find
high-concentration granular limestone.
We are looking for the dried lake bed
or salt-water body all this sand came from.
It's a desert.
Lime is formed mostly from
the remains of marine organisms.
- Huh.
- Are you saying there was life here?
RUSH: Not likely
anything we've seen before.
Yeah, the water may be gone now,
but this desert was formed by
H20 evaporating on a playa floor,
causing gypsum to be deposited
in a fine crystalline form called selenite.
- Where are you going?
- Higher ground.
Is that supposed to happen?
PALMER: If this sand is high enough
in calcite concentration,
the solution would absorb the acid.
- Right.
- The liquid would turn clear.
It's not.
We're good!
This is Scott.
Unfortunately, there's nothing useful
in the immediate vicinity of the gate.
YOUNG: You have 12 hours, Lieutenant.
Make them count.
Copy that.
We're moving out!
Too bad we can't just use this sand.
There certainly is enough of it.
I'm fine.
No, you're not,
and neither am I, but we're...
We're still alive because of what he did.
- Look, for what it's worth...
- Well, it's worth a lot.
You know, as long as we're still here,
I promise you...
Colonel, I've edited enough
of my father's speeches
to know what you're going to say.
You don't have a clue
what I was going to say, because I don't.
We...
We brought along an Ancient device.
Communication stones.
- They allow us to...
- Yeah, I know what they are.
Good. Well, I'm about to use one of them
to report to my superiors on Earth,
tell them our situation.
I want to tell her myself.
You've been sitting here
since Rush made contact.
Let somebody else take a shift.
I'm not leaving this chair.
I've been on this project
for the last six months,
and I'll be damned if...
Colonel?
This is strange.
MEHTA: Dr. Rush, is that you?
No, it's Colonel Young.
I need you to put me in a room
with General O'Neill.
I'm going to need you, too.
JOHANSEN: Sir, I told you not to get up.
TELFORD: What did he do to himself?
He's got cracked ribs,
more bruises than I can count
and a concussion
that resulted in neuropraxia.
- Oh, that's just great.
- Chloe?
- Dr. Mehta.
- Can you help me, please?
You know, I had some of my
favorite arguments with your father.
Are you saying you won some?
Depends on who you ask.
Listen, Major Green'll be escorting you
to see your mother.
- Please give her my condolences.
- Thank you.
Yeah.
So, how is it going out there really?
I don't know what Rush has told you.
We may not have much time left.
The ship's very old. It's falling apart.
- Fix it.
- We're trying.
Even if we can get the life support working,
we don't have much food and water.
- Then go get some.
- We're not supposed to be there, sir.
These are the wrong people
in the wrong place,
and as a group, they're just not qualified.
Oh, please.
I wasn't qualified to lead that first team
through the stargate...
- I understand that, sir.
- In the past dozen years or so,
we've sent hundreds of teams
through that thing...
And I think the bottom line is,
none of us are qualified.
I just think we're going to get
to a point very soon
where everyone onboard
should get a chance to say goodbye.
Understood.
Save it.
FRANKLIN: That's not very smart.
Temperatures like these,
the human body needs at least...
GREER: Walk, don't talk.
Just FYI, he's right about
the whole human body and water...
- Eli!
- Walk, don't...
Oh. Look. More sand.
FRANKLIN: This is pointless.
We should go back.
PALMER: We just got here.
I still think we should be checking out
the other planets in range of the ship.
RUSH: I still think you're wrong.
The solution's here.
ELI: I know. It was a mirage,
but when we were
walking over that last dune,
I thought I saw the Statue of Liberty
sticking half out of the sand.
Just for a second there.
I was all ready to yell, "Damn you!
"Damn you all to hell!"
Oh, come on. That was funny.
Was it?
Because it would mean
we were really on Earth,
but in the future,
and the apes had taken over
and then buried the Statue of Liberty
for some reason.
Eli? Have a drink.
Greer, hold up! Hold up!
- This isn't going to work.
- GREER: Not if we keep stopping.
I'm saying we need to split up.
Fine with me.
I agree. Franklin, you should come with me.
Nah. No, no, no, you're with me and Greer.
Sun's been moving that way,
we'll call it west.
Eli, Franklin, Palmer, and Curtis,
you head that way.
We'll test every 20 minutes or so.
After two hours, you head southeast.
That should take you back
in the direction of the gate.
Whoa, wait a second.
Do we really think
that splitting up is the best idea?
I say we head straight back.
There's no point in crossing over
the same territory we've just crossed.
Or we could just stick together.
Look, Matt, I'm sorry.
I just have this really, really sick feeling
that you're going to go that way,
and we're going to go this way.
Eli, I need someone that I can trust
to lead the second team, okay?
That is you.
Curtis is a good soldier. He's a tough guy.
He's not going to let
anything happen to you.
Truth is, I'm slowing you down
and you want to get rid of me.
I'm doing what I think
will best accomplish this mission.
You asked to come.
I'm telling you how you can help me.
Now suck it up.
Yeah. Okay.
Okay, guys, we're going this way.
Move out!
SCOTT: Radio if you find the lake bed,
we'll double back.
ELI: When you see the Statue of Liberty,
you know what to say, right?
Right. Now we can make some time.
She's here? Right now?
- Yes, ma'am, but as I've explained...
- Chloe!
Mrs. Armstrong...
I know I look different and I sound different,
but it's me.
Mom, please. I have something to tell you.
Mom... Stop!
I'm sorry. It's just...
The thought that
you're actually on some ship
so far away, I can't even imagine.
- Mom...
- Just tell me you're coming home.
I don't know.
Mom, please!
The ship is old and damaged.
We were losing air and somebody had to...
He's dead.
He's dead, isn't he?
MEHTA: Where is everyone?
Able bodies are searching the ship
for anything that might have
CO2 sequestration properties,
and the rest are in crew quarters.
Colonel, we were able
to dial out to the planet again.
JOHANSEN: Colonel Young and Chloe
are using the communication stones.
This is Colonel Telford, Dr. Mehta.
Uh... Right. Okay.
Did you make radio contact
with the off-world team?
Yes, nothing to report yet. They've split up.
How much time
before the ship jumps back to FTL?
Roughly nine hours.
Dial out every 20 minutes.
Maintain regular contact.
We do have power issues to be aware of.
Dialing the gate is a significant drain
on what seems to be
limited resources at this point.
The away mission is priority one
right now.
- Sir?
- I'm fine.
I understand that there are
other stargates in range.
Four other addresses
came up in the system,
but we seem to be locked out from here.
Well, have you tried working around it?
Dr. Rush didn't think that was a good idea.
I think it makes sense to know
what our options are, so do what you can.
There has to be a good reason why
these addresses are being disqualified.
If I wasn't being clear,
I was giving you an order.
If there are good reasons,
find out exactly what they are.
- Let's keep moving, I want to see more.
- You should rest.
Lieutenant.
Sir, Colonel Young's body
needs time to recover.
TELFORD: Give me something for the pain.
The body feels pain for a reason.
I would rather not mask it.
Just do it, Lieutenant. From the sound
of things, you need my help here.
All right, come on. Let's go.
You better save some of that.
- We need to slow down.
- We need to cover more ground.
RUSH: It's going to be impossible
to maintain this pace on the way back.
GREER: Maybe for you.
How tedious. Little boys playing soldier.
Well, I'm sorry.
I've no interest in playing your game.
I'm not playing anything,
I'm trying to save the lives
of everyone aboard that ship.
If we continue this pace,
we're going to die out here.
Yeah, maybe we will.
Light years away from the admiring eyes
of your father, or your drill sergeant,
or whoever's approval it is
you so desperately seek.
- How dare you!
- Get up and move.
Hey, did you see that?
What?
I don't know. Nothing.
Let's move.
One hour.
One hour, and then we start circling back.
All right, fine.
- Just hold that there.
- Thank you.
What did you...
That was supposed to be for the pain.
What did you give to him?
A strong sedative,
which we are desperately short on
and I should not have had to use
just so that Colonel Young
can return to a body in working condition.
You are out of line, Lieutenant.
Disregarding the health
of another human being is out of line.
I am well within my rights
as ranking medical officer.
He'll be out an hour or two.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
I don't care.
I have other patients to attend to.
Something wrong?
No, I'm fine.
Good a place as any to stop and test.
- I take it that's not good?
- No.
I don't know. I think that...
Hey, guys. Another negative over here.
I'll radio Scott
and tell him we're moving on.
Uh, yeah, but that's not what's going down.
- It's not?
- No.
There are four other viable addresses
in this thing.
I think I found an override
that'll allow us to dial from here...
- Yeah, but...
- Look around. This planet is a dead zone.
- ELI: But...
- We should've been trying
to dial these other planets from the start.
- Rush said...
- We don't care what Rush said.
We don't trust him.
Rush doesn't want us all to die.
That doesn't mean we trust him
to make the right decisions.
You, too?
What about the lake bed?
It could be hundreds of miles from here.
We could be blowing our only chance
at finding a decent place to evac.
Maybe the ship did bring us here
because there's lime on this planet.
For all we know, the Ancients had
a way of locating it that we don't.
For that matter, I'm sure
they could've stopped the ship
for longer than 12 hours to find it
and recover it with the proper tools.
The fact is, the Ancients
wouldn't have let the life-support system
get that screwed up in the first place.
Rush is set on fixing the ship.
He's deaf to any other logic.
We need to find a planet
we can survive on.
This might be our last chance.
Gotta keep going.
Here. Take it.
- I have my own.
- No, no. I can't go on.
I'm never going to make it back.
I know it's here.
You have to find it. Take it.
- We're going to leave him here?
- I'll make my way back to the gate.
- Go with him.
- I'm not leaving you here alone.
- Make sure he gets back alive.
- What difference does it make?
Because if I don't find what we need,
he's going to be the one to find
some other way to save his own ass,
and yours along with it.
You're losing it.
I'll be okay.
ON RADIO: Scott, this is Eli. Come in.
If you can hear me, please respond.
This is Scott, what's up?
We have a problem.
Franklin, Curtis, and Palmer have given up
and are headed back to the gate to try
dialing the other addresses in the remote.
They also have the Kino.
They don't think
we're going to find the lime here.
They want to look for another planet
that will support life.
They're going to get themselves killed.
Don't we need the remote
to get back to the ship?
That's not the point.
A few hours is nowhere near enough time
to determine whether a planet is even
safe, let alone viable for sustaining life.
The ship. The ship's our only real hope
of ever getting home.
Stop them if you can.
I'll turn back when I have to.
- Yes, sir.
- Go!
You lead.
I'm sorry, excuse me.
Miss Armstrong, we better be going soon.
You get my daughter home.
Everyone is doing the best they can,
I assure you.
That's not good enough.
Mom, it's not his fault.
I'm a personal friend
of the President and of the First Lady.
- Yes, ma'am.
- You tell your superiors
if anything happens to her,
I will go public with what I know.
Mom...
I'm sorry, she's upset.
My husband gave his life for my daughter.
You get her back to me,
or the whole world is going to know
what has really been going on
these past years.
- RUSH: I need water.
- We're almost there.
I thought since I gave Scott my canteen,
we'd share.
And you were wrong about that.
I should've known.
Yeah? You think you know me pretty well,
don't you?
I helped choose the personnel
for Icarus Base.
I read your file.
And neither you nor Captain Marvel
back there were on my list, I can tell you.
You think I care?
Give me some water.
Keep walking.
You think just because you were born poor
that it gives you the right
to be angry at the world.
- How pathetic.
- Mmm, yeah, yeah.
You think that's why I'm angry?
If it wasn't for the army,
you'd be in jail, or worse.
That's what all you rich people think.
Rich? My father worked
in the shipyards in Glasgow.
I earned a scholarship to Oxford
while I was working two jobs.
I have earned the right to make decisions
without explaining myself to you
or anyone else.
You give me some of that water!
Keep walking.
- Don't you ever touch me.
- Give me some...
And you do that again,
and I'm gonna put a bullet
- in your face.
- Oh, really?
I don't think so. You need me.
Otherwise, you'd have gladly
done it by now.
Right now, I pray to the God above
that dehydration will shut you the hell up.
Walk! Or die here! It's your choice,
Mr. Decision-maker.
Looks like it's worth a shot to me.
Let's do it.
ELI: Wait!
Stop!
Look, it's not perfect,
but it's better than here.
Vegetation, water, air.
It's not too late for you to come with us.
- Don't go.
- FRANKLIN: We'll dial back
when we know
it's safe to evacuate everyone.
- ELI: You'll never get back home.
- You don't know that.
Maybe there's a way we can use
the gate system to connect the dots.
There has to be a reason
the ship locked out those addresses!
Don't. Please.
Shoot him!
Why did you do that?
He told me to.
- I saved his life.
- By shooting him?
He'll live.
You just stranded Curtis and Palmer.
We'll send them another remote.
I wasn't taking any chances.
- Where's Scott?
- RUSH: Still looking for limestone.
ELI: It's almost halftime.
We only have six hours
before the ship leaves.
Lieutenant, this is Greer. Come in.
I hope he's turned back by now.
Lieutenant! Come in.
You must keep going, my boy.
Don't give up.
I don't need you to tell me that.
I'm not going to let anyone else down
the way I let you down.
You really don't have to follow me around
to remind me.
He has his plan for all of us.
He's either out of radio range
or he's lying face-down in the sand,
dead, or soon to be.
I'm going back for him.
- Well, that's great. Suicide.
- I'm not leaving him out here.
- I'll go with you.
- No, no, you're just gonna slow me down.
Look, this man has to get back to the ship.
He needs medical attention.
Dial. He can take Franklin back.
You wait here for me.
You have five hours to find him
and get back here.
Well, it's not been
a pleasure knowing you.
- What do I need that for?
- Just in case.
In case what?
I don't even know how to fire this thing.
You'd better be here.
I will.
I have a gun.
- Why do I feel like I've been drugged?
- Oh. Good to have you back, sir.
Son of a...
What the hell was Telford doing?
Well... You're going to need this.
BRODY: There they are.
RILEY: Hurry up, hurry up.
Come on, help him, help him.
BRODY: What happened?
Greer... Greer shot him.
Water. Water.
Hey.
That was my ration for the day.
What's going on?
Oh, we've had a lovely day at the beach.
How about you?
I have sinned, Father. I've failed you.
I've failed him.
I've failed myself.
We have redemption through his blood.
Curtis? Palmer? This is Eli.
If you can hear me, please come in.
Curtis. Palmer. Please, respond.
PRIEST: Do you love her?
- SCOTT: She's not going to have it.
- You're certain?
She's 16. We barely even know each other.
What are you going to do?
I don't know about anything.
I thought He was my calling.
But now...
I am sorry.
Why? I'm the one who's weak.
It's my fault.
No, it isn't.
It's not yours.
This is Scott! Come in!
I found it. I found the lake bed!
I've got the lime!
Oh, my God.
If you can hear me, wait.
Just wait, I'm coming!
Eli.
Which way?
Let's move out.
Scott...
Come on. Ready? Drink.
Come on, come on, come on, man.
Take the bag.
There's no time!
- You have to take it.
- Yes, you can.
- No, I can't make it.
- Get the hell up! Come on!
I can't make it.
I can't carry you and this!
Get your weak ass up! Come on!
Come on, soldier!
Less than three minutes
before the ship jumps again.
Incoming!
- I'll stay.
- It's okay. I got it.
- Sorry, sir.
- You did your best.
Less than one minute.
I see them!
They're carrying something!
GREER: We've got it!
Don't go! We've got it!
They've got the lime!
And they're not going to make it.
Forty seconds.
Give me the radio.
Eli, I want you to stick your arm
into the event horizon of the puddle.
Seriously?
Are you sure?
No. But I'm betting
there's some kind of safety protocol
that prevents someone
getting cut off en route.
And what if there isn't?
Twenty seconds.
Eli, do it now!
Come on, man. Come on.
Come on!
Five, four, three, two, one!
Eli, drink.
YOUNG: Scott, look at me.
Lieutenant, look at me.
Look at me! Look at me.
Well done, Eli. Well done.
In the quiet of a shadow
In the corner of a room
Darkness moves upon you
Like a cloud across the moon
You're a-wearing all the silence
Look.
Of a constant that will turn
Like the windmill left deserted
Or the sun forever burn
So don't forget to breathe
Don't forget to breathe
Your whole life is here
No eleventh-hour reprieve
So don't forget to breathe
Keep your head above water
But don't forget to breathe
I brought you some water.
I still have some.
- You really need to drink it.
- I'm fine.
Everyone appreciates what you did.
Rush say how long it will last?
He's not sure.
How are you?
My parents died in a car crash
when I was four years old.
- I'm sorry.
- And the priest who raised me,
he pretty much drank himself to death
when I was 16.
My God.
I'm sorry. I'm not trying to diminish
what you're going through.
- I... I know.
- I think my point is,
there's just some things
you never get over.
That's just the way it is.
You go on through.
As best as you can.
Don't forget to breathe
You know you are here
But you find you want to leave
So don't forget to breathe
Just breathe
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org