Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
RUSH: This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
YOUNG: We are going to survive.
We are going to make it home.
I'm telling you,
the ship came here for a reason!
RUSH: Destiny is powered
by the stars themselves.
WRAY: He and Young
are bumping heads, yes.
Not sure which camp is the better choice.
YOUNG: We just pretend
nothing happened?
We need to be ready
for the next encounter.
For the sake of the crew.
You dreamt you were the spy
who leaked everything about Icarus
to the Lucian Alliance?
RUSH: No, no, no, not me. It wasn't me.
I was Colonel Telford.
We know that the Goa'uld
had brainwashing technology.
It is possible that the Alliance
now has that capability.
Once you are on Earth,
you are on your own.
Whoever you are, you must be using
the Ancient communication stones.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Colonel Telford would never make
such a mistake.
We know that you are
a traitor and a murderer.
Now we know you're a coward, too.
RUSH: You've found another Icarus planet.
We're all very excited to have
Dr. Rush's full cooperation.
Kill me, and you kill Rush!
Begin venting the atmosphere
in Colonel Telford's quarters now.
Young!
Open this damn door!
We both know you're not going to kill me.
Mr. Brody, this is Wray.
- You need to restore the atmosphere...
- This is Young.
Please disregard that request.
WRAY: By letting this happen,
you are participating
in not only the murder of Colonel Telford,
but Dr. Rush, as well.
Okay. Sir, you've made your point.
I'm not trying to make a point.
- Come on. Open the door, sir, please.
- I know what I'm doing.
- What you're doing is killing him!
- I know that, Lieutenant.
- WRAY: Brody!
- What should we do?
The Colonel's bluffing.
He's not going to kill him.
What's happening to him?
All right. No. Sir, I cannot...
You've killed him.
Brody.
YOUNG: Come on, David. Come on.
David, come on.
TELFORD: You're all in danger.
YOUNG: What?
- They're coming.
- Who's coming?
The Lucian Alliance.
They're coming to take Destiny.
YOUNG ON PA: We've been informed
that this ship faces an incursion
by armed forces of the Lucian Alliance,
the group responsible for the attack
on Icarus Base.
All military personnel onboard
have been placed on high alert.
If the enemy has acquired the means
to dial Destiny,
their point of ingress will be the stargate.
Brody, we're clear.
YOUNG: So, the Gate Room is off-limits.
All surrounding corridors
have been placed in lockdown.
Come on! Come on, let's go!
YOUNG: No one may enter
without proper authorization.
I've provided Homeworld Security
with intel on the planet
from which the Lucian Alliance
intends to launch their assault.
They're dispatching forces as I speak.
YOUNG: The best-case scenario,
Earth forces take the launch point intact
and we gain a supply line from home.
The worst-case scenario
is that our forces don't make it
before the attack is launched,
in which case we'll have to deal with them
on our end.
In that event, all non-military personnel
will be ordered back to your quarters,
where you will remain
until the situation has been resolved.
Make no mistake, this will be dealt with
swiftly and decisively.
Thank you. That is all.
Colonel.
Only a couple of hours ago,
Colonel Telford admitted to being a mole
for the Lucian Alliance.
And now, suddenly, he's on our side?
YOUNG: Yeah.
WRAY: You trust him?
I didn't say that.
- What in the hell was that?
- "What in the hell was that, sir?"
- All you had to do was tell me.
- I was keeping you out of it.
You didn't have to.
If I'd known that killing him
and bringing him back
was the only way to beat
that brainwashing technology,
I'd have been behind you 100%.
So, you'll follow orders as long as
I explain everything to you beforehand?
- No, sir, that is not what I meant.
- Well, that's good,
because if it was,
we'd have a problem, Lieutenant.
Do we have a problem?
- No, sir...
- Good,
because now is not the time for that.
- No headaches or blurred vision?
- No. I told you, I'm fine.
Well, Rush is fine. I'll find out about me
when I switch back.
Look, I really need to go and...
T.J., can you give us a minute?
- Yes, sir.
- Thanks.
How are you feeling, David?
- Confused.
- I bet.
You went the whole nine yards.
To the brink and back.
I had to.
You know, in my defense,
it wasn't the first thing I tried.
Yeah. Thanks for that.
At least the brainwashing
explains why you've been such an ass.
I've read the SG mission reports
of that method being done in the past.
I just never...
You have no idea what it's like
to remember things that you've done,
that...
Terrible things.
You weren't yourself, David.
- You've got to send me back.
- Not yet.
- I've done all that I can on this end.
- I've already killed you once.
I'm more useful to you in my own body,
back there with them, Everett,
you know that. How the hell else
are you gonna get Rush back?
- Listen...
- You've got to get him out of there.
David, listen to me,
you've just come back from the dead.
I want you to get your strength back first.
Excuse us.
T.J., listen, when they come,
I want you here, safe.
Safe?
Look, if they break containment,
there could be wounded.
We're going to need you.
What we'll need is a real doctor.
- You're up for this.
- Not even close.
What are you planning to do?
Evacuate the atmosphere in the
Gate Room the minute they step through.
Kill them all, you mean.
You think I have a choice?
If you're asking for forgiveness,
I can't help you there either.
- T.J.
- I'll do my best.
KIVA: You're back.
That was me.
I had to see whether you were faking.
Well, I wasn't.
I apologize.
Back to work. I know.
Running planetary scans.
Whoa.
CARTER: Sir, it looks like the intel is good.
The planet's laced
with naquadria deposits.
We're also reading a huge energy signature
emanating from what looks like a pyramid.
Pyramid? That takes me back.
Unfortunately, the complex inside
is shielded against beaming technology.
So, Rush can't be beamed out.
No, sir. We'll have to go in
with ground forces from the outside.
All right, Colonel. You have a go.
What was that?
KIVA: We're under attack.
Can we dial the ninth chevron?
Not without blowing everything up.
Dial it.
Get ready!
We're going now!
JACKSON: The Lucian Alliance
is an organization of humans
from a number of sovereign planets
who have taken control
of the resources and technology...
The Alliance is made up of power-hungry...
...violence as a means
of enforcing their dominion.
- The Air Force video?
- ELI: Yeah.
I'm just seeing if there's anything in here
that might help.
...control a sizable army
and numerous Ha'tak vessels,
or former Goa'uld motherships.
- What's he going to do?
- The Colonel?
They're sending an army.
What do you think he's going to do?
This is it.
- It's happening now?
- Yeah.
Go! Radio back when you reach
the other side.
And take him with you.
Colonel Young.
I see them, Eli.
All personnel,
report to your designated areas.
This is not a drill. Defense teams stand by.
MAN 1: Copy that. Go, go!
- Which button?
- BRODY: This one.
How long will it take till we reach vacuum?
- A minute or so?
- That's about right.
BRODY: Colonel.
Defense teams stand by
to secure prisoners on my order.
Copy that.
Monitor from here. Stay on the radio.
Got it.
- RUSH: What happened?
- Colonel?
- No, no, it's me.
- Rush?
Yeah.
The ship, the Lucian Alliance...
Yeah, no, we know everything.
Telford told us.
So what are we doing about it, then?
Let's just say it'll all be over
in a few minutes.
Colonel, I'm reading a huge energy spike.
At this rate, they've got less than a minute
before their core goes up.
Get our people out of the shielded areas
and beam them back to the ship, now!
The core is going to go critical.
I can't stop it.
Still no signal from the other side?
Get as many of our people through
as you can.
- Load it up.
- Watch out!
- Watch it, watch it.
- MAN 2: Clear there.
Colonel, we still have two 302s
on their way back from the planet.
We can't wait. Get us out of here.
MAN: No!
Aren't we supposed to go to our quarters?
These are my quarters,
and I'm not going anywhere.
- Colonel?
- They brought Rush along with them.
We're going to have to do this
the hard way.
KIVA: What did you do to the gate?
TELFORD: It wasn't me.
You killed over a hundred of my men!
It was Rush!
Massin.
Massin, your father's name,
it was my password.
Gate travel must have severed the link.
It's me.
Telford?
YOUNG: Lucian Alliance forces,
you are surrounded and sealed in.
You will also find the intel provided
by Colonel Telford is now useless.
Lay down your weapons
in front of the doors
and step back into the center of the room
with your hands on your heads,
or we will vent the entire compartment
to space.
- Can they do it?
- Yes.
Then they should have.
Colonel, they're up to something.
Talk to me.
They've got something to open the doors!
Vent the atmosphere in the Gate Room.
Brody, do it now.
BRODY: Too late.
Take cover!
Get back!
YOUNG: Go!
Uh, Rush, you should stay here.
No, no. The ship's under attack.
Rush!
- Okay, Eli, it's time to go.
- No, just wait.
No, Eli, let's go. Now!
Yeah. Yeah.
ELI: There's an elevator this way.
CHLOE: Oh, God.
YOUNG: Go!
JOHANSEN: Rush! Wait!
BRODY ON KINO: You're welcome.
Want to get the hell out of there now?
ELI: Chloe, you've been shot.
Sorry, sorry.
See? It's okay.
You'll be... You'll be okay.
Eli, I...
Okay.
Hey, you'll be fine.
You'll be fine, all right?
Chloe?
I'll be right back. Okay?
MAN 4: This way. Let's go!
WOMAN 1: Over here.
Colonel Young?
Who is this?
Commander Kiva
of the Lucian Alliance forces.
We will not be complying
with your request to surrender.
We barely made hyperspace.
This time it was even closer.
What about casualties?
Two of my 302s couldn't make it back,
and if Rush was still on the planet...
I'm sorry, Sam.
Yes, sir.
Did any of them make it to Destiny?
I haven't heard.
MAN 1: Hands behind your back. Do it!
BRODY: So much for that.
Why didn't you evacuate
the compartment to space?
- That was the plan.
- He didn't do it to save you.
Not me.
The connection was severed
the minute I stepped through the gate.
Give me the lay of the land.
RUSH: This is the Gate Room.
They also occupy
the surrounding corridors.
They had advanced further,
but they pulled back.
Just took what they could hold
with limited manpower. That's smart.
BRODY: Once they retreated,
I locked down the area behind them.
Given the technology at their disposal,
it won't stop them,
but it should give us some breathing room.
RUSH: The prisoners are being held here.
Between them and us,
30 feet of corridor either way.
Well, the second we hit
that outside section,
those hostages are as good as dead.
- SCOTT: Colonel.
- Yeah?
I've done a head count.
We have 12 missing
and presumed captured,
including Riley, T.J., Eli, and Chloe.
ELI: Come on!
Eli?
Hey. Hey.
- What happened?
- You were shot.
I stopped the bleeding.
No, you're fine. Look up here.
Hey, look at me. Look at me.
Where are we?
I don't know.
I've never been to this part
of the ship before.
I don't think anyone has.
I just pressed some random buttons.
We can't get back.
I'm guessing someone
locked out elevator access.
Us or them?
Yeah, that's the problem.
I just need to get to a window,
get an idea of where we are
and then we can walk back.
Oh, no, no, no, no. I've got you.
Come on. Come here.
Ready? Here we go. One, two, three.
Okay. Okay.
- Lean on me.
- Okay.
- I've got you. Ready?
- Yeah.
There you go.
Colonel Young.
Go ahead.
Here's how I see the situation.
We have the Gate Room
and some of your people.
You hold the Control Interface Room,
which, I'm told, is the ship's nerve center.
YOUNG: What do you want?
We came here
for the same reasons you did.
We don't want to hurt anyone.
You're welcome to stay aboard Destiny
and help us realize the potential
of her discovery.
Lay down your weapons and join us.
Or, if you prefer, we can drop you off
at the next inhabitable world
of your choosing.
Or I vent the atmosphere
in the sections you're occupying
and keep the ship.
If you had that in you, Colonel,
you would have done it already.
The point is, I have the ability
to end this conversation right now.
- Sergeant?
- She wanted to see you, sir.
- Wouldn't shut up, in fact.
- As you were, Sergeant.
We are way past the point of fighting
our way out of this situation.
We need to negotiate with these people.
And I think I should be the one to...
Yeah, yeah. No, I think you're right.
Him. Him.
And her.
That's a mistake.
It's a demonstration.
All it will do is force their hand.
Do you want control of the ship or not?
WRAY: They have some of our people.
YOUNG: But we have some of theirs.
So the first thing we need to do
is suggest an exchange.
- Do you think they'll do it?
- No.
But I think it's worth a shot.
TELFORD: This is
the Control Interface Room.
This is the Gate Room.
If we cut our way through the wall here,
we can flank them. I can lead a team.
That will reduce our numbers here.
We take the Control Interface Room,
we won't need them here.
The ship will be ours.
KIVA: These sections are in red.
That section of corridor
is exposed to space.
The ship's shield will hold long enough
for us to pass.
We will slowly vent atmosphere
to space, yes,
but we could seal the corridor again
after we've taken the ship.
- KIVA: Take six men.
- I'll need twice that...
Six.
And if anything goes wrong,
these three die.
Not her.
She's a medic.
We can use her in the event...
WRAY ON RADIO: Commander Kiva.
- Who is this?
- My name is Camile Wray.
I am the civilian authority aboard this ship.
I'd like to act as an intermediary
to resolve this issue
without further bloodshed.
Colonel Young will not transfer control
of this ship to you.
KIVA: And you will?
No. But I will expedite
a prisoner exchange.
Your people for ours.
If I release my prisoners,
Colonel Young will not hesitate
to vent this compartment.
You have 12 of our people.
We have only four of yours.
I propose an even trade, four for four.
This way, you maintain your advantage
and gain some much-needed manpower.
Colonel Young agrees with this?
In our society the military takes orders
from civilian leadership.
I'll consider it.
Nice job. That should buy us some time.
Look, you're trying to save lives here.
Obviously, that's a good thing.
But even if she agrees to the four,
which is doubtful,
she won't go any farther than that.
Once the equation tips
to the point of acceptable losses...
No, no, no.
There will be no acceptable losses.
Colonel Young has already determined
what that number is.
He knows the chances of us winning
without loss of life are practically nil.
So limit our losses, yes, all that we can,
but eventually,
you're going to have to do something...
You don't know what you're talking about.
You forget, I've recently been
one of your acceptable losses...
You knew what you
were getting yourself into, Rush.
You should have disconnected the stones
and got me out!
You have no clue
what you're talking about!
Stop this now, please!
I am going to save
every one of those hostages,
and I'm going to retake this ship.
Do you understand me?
All right, Telford has convinced her
that he is still with them,
otherwise he would be dead by now.
Sooner or later he will make his move.
So, we are to gamble this ship
and all of our lives
in the hope that some traitor
has had a change of heart.
ELI: Look at that.
I guess those elevators go
more than just up and down.
Yes, right there.
- You good?
- Yeah.
I must have hit a few buttons
I wasn't supposed to press.
Is the air getting thin?
Life support isn't working out here.
How do you know?
I was the one who shut it off.
Rush's orders.
I mean, there's air. There just isn't
any new air being pumped in.
- So we need to keep moving?
- Yeah.
- Okay?
- I don't know if I can.
No problem.
I got you.
This is my lieutenant, Varro.
Save him.
He's badly wounded.
At even the slightest hint of trouble,
Lieutenant...
I'll bring you back, sir.
I need to speak to General O'Neill.
O'NEILL: Second-guessing a decision
is a waste of time.
I'm not there.
But I'm starting to wonder
if maybe I should be.
I can't speak to that, sir.
- This should be done, Colonel. Over.
- Yes, sir.
At the time, I believed
that venting the Gate Room
would kill both Dr. Rush
and Colonel Telford.
- They deserved a chance.
- We lost two 302 pilots
- sent to stop the attack.
- I'm sorry.
Colonel Carter knew she'd lose her ship
if she tried to save them,
but it was the right decision.
Yes, sir.
Are you up for this, Everett?
Because somebody will take your place
if you're not.
I'm not going to let anybody
take that ship, sir.
Then get your ass back there.
TELFORD: We're good.
What are you doing?
Just checking to make sure
we're headed in the right direction.
This way.
There's no countdown.
VOLKER: What?
We dropped out of FTL
because someone was gating in.
Why haven't we jumped back?
Someone just activated a console
in one of the access corridors.
Colonel, a console just came on
using Telford's code.
They're in a cordoned-off section
coming our way.
That's his move.
- It's cold.
- Really?
- ELI: Okay. Watch your foot. Good?
- Yeah.
We have to be careful
moving through sections.
There's a reason
we've never been out this far.
A ton of compartments are de-pressurized.
- Okay?
- Thank you.
Hang on. Okay.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
Okay.
More dark and gloomy. We're good.
Coming?
Gotcha. Good? Gotcha.
- ELI: How are you doing?
- I'm okay.
ELI: You sure?
Stand by.
Yes, sir. We're good to go.
Ready.
GREER: Just give the word, sir.
- It's locked down.
- I'll handle it.
Okay, get ready.
SCOTT: What was that?
MAN: This way. Let's go. This way.
YOUNG: Ready?
What happened?
- You didn't do that?
- What is that?
Just a minute ago, it was a man.
You need to stand down
till we figure this out.
This is Young. Everybody stand down.
- Throw me a radio.
- Radio?
Three clicks, go to channel six.
We're going to have to try this again.
CHLOE: Let's stop.
ELI: No. I'm fine.
- Eli, you don't...
- Seriously, this is nothing.
Once, I climbed the Redridge Mountains
on my way to Stonard
- with a full pack.
- Where's that?
World of Warcraft.
Wow, that...
That must've given you
quite the sense of accomplishment.
- Eli...
- Okay, okay.
- Okay, a little break. A little break.
- Yeah.
All right, all right.
So, what do you think is happening?
- We've probably won by now.
- You think so?
If we won,
then why haven't we been rescued?
Well, first, they have to figure out
what to do with the prisoners,
and then there's
that whole post-victory celebration.
I mean, streamers everywhere.
I'm so tired.
You're still... You're still losing blood.
- I wasn't able to stop it completely.
- Eli...
Hey.
I'm going to take care of you.
It wasn't them.
Now, I don't know
what happened to our man,
but I know that
they had nothing to do with it.
They don't have anything
that could do that to a person.
Are you telling me that
they had nothing to do with this?
TELFORD: What happened?
BRODY: Overload in the power relays
proceeded by temporary disruption
of all shipboard systems,
lights to life support.
- Well, how the hell did they manage that?
- They didn't.
- Well, then, what caused it?
- That's what I'm trying to figure out.
They're making their move.
It wouldn't be that obvious.
KIVA: Colonel Young. Would you care
to tell me what's going on?
We don't know.
One of my men is dead.
You need to know that
we had nothing to do with that.
Yes, so I'm told.
I'm going to ask for a show of good faith.
What do you want?
Colonel?
Lieutenant.
How are you?
I'm fine. We're all fine.
What is it that they want?
Some of their people are injured badly.
I'm going to need medical supplies
to help them.
What will this accomplish?
WRAY: A goodwill gesture
doesn't have to accomplish anything.
Of course it does!
So they lack medical supplies?
Who knows what else they might lack?
Food? Water?
Now, in time, they're gonna get desperate.
They'll make their move,
and when they do,
they'll be dealing with the hostages first.
There's only one way this is going to end
if we wait.
How do you know that?
We don't even know
what's going on with the ship!
All the more reason to act now.
Rush is right. We have to take them down,
and we have to do it right now.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org