Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
RUSH: This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
YOUNG: We are going to survive.
We are going to make it home.
I'm telling you,
the ship came here for a reason!
RUSH: Destiny is powered
by the stars themselves.
WRAY: He and Young
are bumping heads, yes.
Not sure which camp is the better choice.
YOUNG: We just pretend
nothing happened?
We need to be ready
for the next encounter.
For the sake of the crew.
- They're coming.
- Who's coming, David?
The Lucian Alliance.
They're coming to take Destiny.
They've got something to open the doors!
- Take cover!
- Grenade!
Fall back!
You'll be... You'll be okay.
- What happened?
- You were shot.
YOUNG: You are surrounded.
Lay down your weapons,
or we will vent the entire compartment
to space.
- Can they do it?
- Yes.
Then they should have.
JOHANSEN: Rush! Wait!
We will not be complying
with your request to surrender.
We have 12 missing
and presumed captured,
including Riley, T.J., Chloe, and Eli.
I am going to save
every one of those hostages,
and I'm going to retake this ship.
Do you understand me?
This is Young.
We've got the medical supplies
you requested.
We are prepared to give them to you
as a show of good faith.
KIVA: Thank you.
One condition.
You and I meet to make the exchange.
Agreed.
Let's do this.
Brody?
Ready.
Remember, quick kills, center mass.
Yes, sir.
All right.
You ready to do this?
We're ready.
Bring the medic.
Open the door.
I'm in.
- Who's this?
- Ronald Greer is also a medic.
KIVA: Another offer of good faith?
In exchange for Lieutenant Johansen.
First things first.
Go and check the supplies
and see they're what you need.
- Hold your fire!
- KIVA: Don't shoot!
No, no, no, no. Power just went out
throughout the whole ship!
I can see that, Mr. Brody.
Please step aside.
T.J., get behind me.
She takes one step in your direction,
and I will shoot her myself.
I've got the shot, sir.
My men have been ordered to
execute the prisoners if I am killed.
Step back in my direction.
Sir, I've got the shot.
Stand down, Sergeant.
Damn it.
- What happened?
- They surprised us.
What do you mean?
They surprised us.
Do you want me to explain it again?
The hostages are useless to us
if they're dead!
At least they serve a purpose.
Tell them. Tell them!
Colonel.
I'm here.
She just killed Rivers.
Understood.
Hey, don't fall asleep. It's dangerous.
That's a concussion.
Okay, then it's boring.
So, what do you think
they'll do with them?
Who?
The prisoners.
Probably drop them off on some planet.
I don't know.
I just hope everyone's okay.
I just hope it's over.
Well, not much we can do about it.
So, rest time is over.
ELI: Ah!
This feels familiar.
- What the hell just happened?
- We still don't know.
We're just getting systems back online,
then maybe we can analyze...
Screw analyze! Fix it!
- We've got to know what's broken first.
- Do it now!
- Rivers is dead.
- What?
Well, it was going to be someone.
BRODY: Whoa, whoa,
whoa! Whoa!
Would you prefer it was Chloe or Eli?
Lieutenant Johansen, perhaps?
Don't bloody tell me
you weren't thinking the same thing.
I want you to figure out
what's wrong with the ship and fix it.
Fix it now.
I have orders to help.
What's your name?
Koz.
I'll let you know what I need.
You do know there is a way to save them.
You're just not wired to consider it.
I'm not surrendering this ship.
And what exactly is so wonderful about it?
We give up, she kills everyone
except for those who have value to her,
and let me tell you,
that's not a hell of a lot of people.
Colonel?
This is Young.
I would like to speak to the civilian.
This is Camile Wray.
Colonel Young has proved
that he cannot be trusted.
Can you?
Yes.
Then why did you let them
plan an ambush?
I voiced my disagreement.
And you could not stop them?
No, obviously not.
For that, one of your men was killed.
If you fail to live up to your promise twice,
I will kill again.
Do you understand?
No, I don't understand,
but I do believe you.
Then I would like to take you up
on your initial offer,
with one modification.
Four of your men for four of ours,
and food and water for three days.
Will food and water be offered
to the hostages?
They're no good to me dead.
Then we're agreed.
Next time we take supplies with us
in the first wave.
If there is a next time.
Damn it. Flashlight, flashlight!
- What's happening?
- Well, I don't know, Koz.
I'm up to my wrists
in someone's body right now.
Do we have any answers yet?
Just the one.
Every crash has been exactly
46 minutes, 37.4 seconds apart.
So?
Well, it'll be easier to show you. Brody?
Okay, so, what am I looking at?
That's our problem. It's a binary pulsar.
It's the combination of
a rotating neutron star
and probably a white dwarf orbiting
around a single point in space.
What does that mean to us?
Pulsars give off gamma radiation
and x-rays as they rotate,
short, deadly bursts of ionized radiation.
The shield and the hull are
protecting us right now.
Right, but the pulsar is literally
feeding off of the white dwarf,
stripping off material and
creating an accretion disk.
And the white dwarf plows through
that material every orbit.
Which gives off
an even bigger gamma ray burst,
on top of
what we're already getting hit with,
and that's why our systems
are shutting down.
The shield has to draw extra power
in order to compensate.
And that happens every 46 minutes,
37.4 seconds.
It's what killed their man,
and it's going to be what kills us.
The Lucian Alliance just happened to
dial in when the damn thing was in range.
Destiny had to drop out of FTL
to make the connection.
It's bad timing, bad luck.
Well, then, why are we still here?
Our FTL capability has been compromised.
- Compromised?
- Don't yell.
We don't know why yet.
The shield is what's keeping us alive,
but sooner or later,
it's going to fail, and when it does...
We're dead.
Yeah.
The radiation burst is what's
causing the system malfunctions.
Which will only get worse.
Because the shield will fail eventually, yes.
Unless we can find a way
to make the jump to FTL.
How much time?
Well, according to Rush,
we can withstand two more of the bursts.
People will start dying by the third.
TELFORD: I saw what one of those bursts
did to a man
when he wasn't protected
by the ship's hull.
First we'll make the trade,
and then we'll discuss this new problem.
Has their medic completed
Varro's surgery?
Not yet.
Well, then find out what's taking so long.
I'll do it.
Lieutenant, she told me to
check on your progress.
Tell her it'd be a hell of a lot faster
if the damn lights didn't keep going off.
Well, that's a whole other problem.
The Destiny came out of FTL
within range of a pulsar.
We don't have much time
before the shield fails.
Colonel Young and his people are
trying to solve it, but...
She won't let them.
I'll do my best to convince her.
You do that.
Lieutenant Scott?
We've got the supplies
that they requested,
and we're ready to make
the prisoner exchange.
Copy that.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
And Varro?
I've done all I can for him.
SOLDIER 1: Hold it steady.
Here, use this one.
- Will he live?
- I got the bullet out
and stopped the bleeding,
so he should have a chance.
I'd like to take a look
at the other wounded.
Fine.
Let's go.
- You got it?
- Camile? Camile?
What's this?
A flak vest. Just in case.
How can I expect them to trust me
if I can't even demonstrate
a willingness to trust them in turn?
With all due respect, ma'am,
I don't think they can be trusted.
You tell Colonel Young
I appreciate his concern.
Yeah, the Colonel said
you wouldn't take it.
I just thought I'd try anyway.
- Are you sure about this, sir?
- No.
Good enough for me.
I hope you make a better impression
than I did.
Commander Kiva, are you ready?
We are.
Brody, open it.
Lieutenant, thank you.
I'll take it from here.
Okay, Mr. Brody.
I asked for civilians.
- These are the two we had.
- We agreed on four for four.
Four.
- What about Lieutenant Johansen?
- She stays.
Even if we figure out a way
to jump back into FTL,
and right now, the odds are not good...
Then we'll be right back where we started.
Yes, but this doesn't have to end
with one of us losing.
If we could just figure out a way
to work with each other...
I can see that you're someone
who enjoys talking through problems,
but if you don't solve this new one,
then neither of us will have
anything to talk about.
Brody.
All right, get in the infirmary.
Where's Chloe and Eli?
She said they were the only two civilians.
Then where the hell are they?
It's gonna be just...
Sorry, sorry. Sorry.
Take a break, Eli.
No, no, no, no.
We've got to be getting close by now.
You know what?
We should do this twice a week.
This is the kind of exercise
that really motivates me.
Carrying a wounded person the length
of the whole ship in low oxygen?
Good times.
CHLOE: Thank you, Eli.
Wait till it's your turn to carry me.
You're an amazing friend.
ELI: You can never have too many of those.
Unless you're one of
those people on Facebook
who just accepts
everybody's friend request.
It's like, come on, you know,
be a little selective.
Eli!
Damn it!
Sorry. Sorry.
- It's okay.
- Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Okay, thanks.
- There's no sign of Eli or Chloe.
- You know, maybe they...
There's no fatalities on our side
except for Rivers.
- They must be hiding somewhere.
- I hope so.
Look, that boy would take a bullet
before he'd let them
touch a hair on her head.
Lieutenant, don't get distracted.
I'm not, I'm not, I just...
I just want to get this done with.
And I wish the Colonel
would give the word
so that we can go in there
and properly resolve the situation.
Look, he'll do the right thing
when the right time comes.
You got to trust that 100%.
I don't know how you do it, man.
Well, you need to learn.
Thank you.
Your Commander already showed
her appreciation by not killing me.
It must be difficult to be forced
to save the life of your enemy.
No. I would have done it anyway.
- How's the pain?
- Bearable.
- Look, I'm trying to say...
- I don't really care.
I've been on my feet for far too long,
and I have other patients, so excuse me.
Conserving air or unconscious?
Just thinking.
About what?
I used to think I had a lot of friends,
but I don't.
They're a billion light years away,
but they're still your friends.
No, they don't really care about me.
- And I don't really care about them either.
- That's nice.
No, no, because until I met you,
I didn't really know what a friend was.
Do you know what I mean, Eli?
No.
A friend is someone
who will support you no matter what.
- Like you.
- Chloe, why don't we...
And I am not just saying that
because I feel like I'm going to pass out,
- and even if I do, I just want to say it first.
- And you did, so...
But whenever I say stuff like that to you,
you always react like I've just awarded
you some runner-up prize,
and it's not.
I know.
- It's just that...
- I know.
Of course you do.
Hey, there's a console over there.
I didn't notice that when we came in.
And it's got power.
- Can you call for help?
- I can try.
Dr. Park?
Look, it's not much of a solution,
but we don't have to shield the entire ship.
- Just the side facing the pulsar, right?
- Right.
We'll have to leave some shielding
on the underside of the ship,
but we should be able to transfer
something like 90%.
Should buy us enough time
to restore FTL capability.
So why haven't you guys done it yet?
Because it can't be done from
inside the ship.
Well, it could, if we had control of
the core systems, but we don't, so...
No, no, look, look, someone's gonna
have to go for a walk.
RUSH: I can tell you where to go,
what to do.
The mechanics of it are relatively simple.
Yeah, well, then why don't you
put on a space suit and do it?
Well, you get the FTL drive back online
while I'm gone, and you got a deal.
- We'll get it done, sir.
- I know you will. Gear up.
WRAY: They have only the time between
the gamma ray bursts
to complete their work.
The next one is less than
20 minutes from now,
so obviously time is an issue.
So what do you need from us?
There's a hull breach in the access corridor
that's under your control.
It's the exit point closest to the array.
We need you to let us in.
Transfer control of
all the ship systems to us,
and we will let them in.
You do understand that
if you don't help us save this ship,
we will all die.
Oh, I understand completely,
and I want you to transfer
the ship's systems to us.
When was the last time
you ran a security sweep in there?
Never mind, I'll do it. Radio?
Calvos, this is Telford.
Give me access to the damaged section.
You tell me. You think she's bluffing?
She doesn't have to.
She knows who she's dealing with.
But to be fair,
you don't have much of a choice.
At least they'll keep some of us alive,
for a while, anyway.
Yeah, like you.
You forget I've recently been
in their employment.
I wouldn't envy me just yet.
David?
Yeah, Everett.
It's about damn time.
Listen, do it.
Transfer control of the ship
and surrender yourselves.
Everyone but Rush and Brody.
Have them retreat to one of
the auxiliary control rooms.
They're going to notice Rush is missing.
Tell them he panicked and ran away.
They'll believe it.
By the time they start looking for him,
it'll be too late.
At the first available opportunity,
I'll access one of the Gate Room consoles
and transfer control of the ship
back to Rush.
The second they find out,
they're going to start shooting prisoners.
Then I won't let them find out.
Not right away, anyway.
I won't lock them out completely.
They can have control of the ship
until I decide they can't.
They'll herd all of the prisoners
into one compartment.
If they don't, I'll suggest it.
When they do,
I'll contact Rush on this channel.
I'll tell him which compartment,
then he can vent the atmosphere
from all the surrounding ones.
Where are you going to be?
You let me worry about that. I got to go.
It's all clear.
Best not to stick around.
This is Colonel Young.
I am prepared to surrender control
of this ship
provided certain conditions are met.
KIVA: Go ahead.
I need you to guarantee me
the safety of my people.
Agreed.
Nobody gets hurt during the changeover,
and no retribution afterwards.
Anything else?
That's all.
Well, Mr. Brody, time to panic and run off.
VOLKER: Hold on a sec.
We just got a message from
an unexplored part of the ship.
It's Eli. What are we going to do?
Well, you got to go. Good luck.
Yeah, you, too.
Transfer control to them.
Anything?
I wrote it in Ancient,
so it could take a while for somebody to...
- What is it?
- We got a message.
What's it say?
Oh, no.
We better stay put.
- Transfer complete.
- Open them.
No shooting. That's a good sign.
I think the stitching is torn.
You're moving around too much.
I understand your anger at losing the ship,
but it wasn't really yours to begin with.
When all this is settled, past sins
on both sides will have to be forgiven.
Truce?
Open them.
Forty-six minutes, gentlemen.
Yes, sir.
They're in.
Attenuating the shield strength
in that compartment.
Dialing back artificial gravity.
Commander, one of the power relays
just went down.
- Is something wrong?
- We just lost a power relay.
Then why aren't you dealing with it?
Go. Go. I can open and close doors.
This is it?
Yeah, it's where he said it was going to be.
- No, no, no, no.
- What happened?
The transfers just stopped.
What's the matter?
It won't lock.
Colonel Young, this is Scott.
How are we doing for time?
14 minutes.
This is Calvos.
Kiva and Telford have both been shot.
The Commander is still breathing,
but unconscious.
DANNIC: Get them to the medic.
CALVOS: Yes, sir.
- Is there any sign of the enemy?
- None.
- Where are your men?
- What?
Your soldiers.
How did they get into the Gate Room?
I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
I've got people outside this ship!
The enemy has somehow
breached our lines.
Both Telford and Kiva have been shot.
I'm assuming command.
Colonel Young, this is Scott.
Ready to come back in. Lower the shield.
I repeat, this is Scott, over.
The shield is still up.
We cannot get back inside.
They just saved our damn lives.
Lower the shield.
- Keep moving.
- Lower the damn shield!
Lower the shield.
Try a different channel!
This is Scott. Please respond!
Lieutenant, something's gone wrong.
We have to find you another way
back inside the ship.
No, no, no, there's no time for that, Rush!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what other way is there?
There's an airlock in forward section.
Yeah, we think it's an airlock.
It's in a totally unexplored part of the ship.
- Besides, we can't open it from here.
- Eli.
Eli.
Lieutenant, I need you to head back
towards the front of the ship.
Negative, negative!
Listen to me, that's the way in.
We're looking at the way in right now.
You need to go there
as quickly as you can.
Go right now.
We're on our way.
- What's going on?
- I'm getting a message.
- What's it say?
- That I got to go.
- What do you mean?
- I'm telling them where you are,
so you'll be safe until they come.
- Where are you going?
- Whatever happens, you know, right?
Eli, you're scaring me.
- I got to go.
- Eli!
Calvos. What happened?
Come on, come on.
DANNIC: Separate the civilians.
Take them to another compartment.
This is Varro. What are you doing?
I'm going to put an end to this.
DANNIC: Bring their injured soldiers to me.
Not if you expect me to
save your Commander.
They're not going to make it.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org