Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
RUSH: This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
YOUNG: We are going to survive.
We are going to make it home.
I'm telling you,
the ship came here for a reason!
RUSH: This ship is powered
by the stars themselves.
WRAY: He and Young
are bumping heads, yes.
Not sure which camp is the better choice.
YOUNG: We just pretend
nothing happened?
We need to be ready
for the next encounter.
For the sake of the crew.
Dad! No, wait!
RUSH: You know, the Icarus Project was
something your father truly believed in.
CHLOE: A son?
- What's his name?
- Matthew.
RUSH: The few times I was conscious,
they were probing my mind.
That's something
I'd rather not think about, really.
JAMES: There a reason your radio's off?
What, you couldn't find a broom closet?
I feel love
A filthy flavor
One man's weakness
Is another man's pleasure
I've got no feeling
I don't know how
We make no sense out of this
But I got to, somehow
So, what you want me to do?
What you want me to do?
What are you doing?
I should go.
What? Why?
I can't be doing this.
Right.
You say that now that you're done.
You knew what you were getting into.
You know what? No. Screw that.
I am not going to let you kick me aside
like you did before.
Yeah, well, whatever.
Move.
Me or her. You can't have both.
I never said I wanted both. Now, move.
Me or her, Matt.
Get out of my way.
Oh, for...
This is Dr. Volker.
Anybody in the Control Interface Room?
How about anybody at all?
Hello?
Anybody?
You okay?
Yeah. The door control doesn't work.
No, you don't have to... Okay.
Stupid ship.
Where is everybody?
I don't know.
The room was empty when I got here.
Can I help you with something?
- What are you doing?
- Nothing you need to worry about.
I like to worry.
I was just updating some personnel files.
In the Gate Room.
Colonel Young and Dr. Rush know all
about it, in case you'd like to talk to them.
I'll do that.
ELI: Greer.
Have you seen Matt?
I have not.
YOUNG:
Lieutenant James, come in.
Lieutenant James, this is Colonel Young.
Please respond.
Yes, sir.
You're late with
the current ammunition count.
Lieutenant, what are you doing?
Nothing, sir. I'm fine. I am...
I just lost track of time,
but I'm on my way now.
James out.
So I heard that Colonel Young's
calling off the search for Franklin.
Yeah.
It's not like anyone was really looking
for him. The man just vanished.
Weird.
Dunning, come on.
What the hell?
SCOTT: Dr. Volker?
You okay?
Something weird's going on here.
What is it?
You look tired.
Maybe you should go lie down.
Yeah. Maybe I will.
Matthew?
- Nicholas.
- Hi.
Something wrong?
I need to talk to you
about something that...
YOUNG: Just the two I need to see.
WRAY: Colonel.
Am I interrupting something?
No.
Good.
WRAY: I wasn't even
in the Gate Room today.
RUSH: He said it was empty?
YOUNG: Only person in the room was Wray,
working at one of the consoles,
updating the files.
Said you told him that
Rush and I knew all about it.
RUSH: No, I don't know
anything about this.
And I don't know what to tell you,
Colonel, other than he's lying.
He has no reason to lie.
Please.
Sergeant Greer has had it in for us since
the first day we came aboard this ship.
Correction. Since the day the two of you
led a mutiny to take it over.
I can understand the suspicion.
I was not in the Gate Room.
Hey! Are you all right?
You didn't pass anyone
in the corridor just now?
No.
Oh, my God...
Matt, what happened?
PARK:
We need help in the work-out room!
Anyone from military,
as many as possible! Now!
DUNNING: Get it out!
Oh, my God.
Get it out! Get it out! Get it out!
Help!
He thinks a snake is
crawling under his skin.
YOUNG: A snake?
He said it was crawling around
under his skin, but no one saw anything.
He just flipped out.
I can't find anything
physically wrong with him
other than the wounds
that he inflicted on himself.
Have you noticed any unusual behavior
from him lately?
No, he's been his normal self.
As far as I can tell.
All right, well, let's... Let's keep him here,
close eye on him, and let me know
when the sedatives wear off.
I want to talk to him.
ELI: No warning or anything?
- He just... Just went nuts?
- CHLOE: Yeah.
Some kind of nervous breakdown.
It was pretty scary.
Tearing gashes in your own arms?
That's... That's intense.
RILEY: The stress of life on this ship,
day after day of not knowing
what's ahead...
It's a wonder more people
aren't cracking up.
I'm just glad he took it out on himself.
And he didn't start shooting people.
Hey, you all right?
Hello? Earth to Greer?
I'm fine.
I always figured he'd be the first to snap.
Sergeant Greer?
If you want to accuse me of something,
come forward.
No need for spying.
BRODY: Who you talking to?
Apparently no one.
No. No.
No! Help!
Someone help me, please!
Get me out of here!
Hey! Get me out of here!
Well, where the hell is she?
I don't know, sir. I tried to radio her.
She's not responding.
Oh, for God's sake.
Lieutenant James, come in.
Lieutenant James, this is Colonel Young.
Please respond.
James!
I'm so sorry.
You can't be real.
Why did you leave me?
YOUNG: Lieutenant Scott.
Yeah, Colonel, go ahead.
YOUNG: I need you in the infirmary.
- You're alive?
- YOUNG: She thinks she killed you.
How did you... You were in my room.
You're hallucinating.
Just like Airman Dunning.
- What the hell is going on here?
- YOUNG: We don't know yet.
JOHANSEN: I can't find anything
physically wrong with either one of them.
I'm seeing things, too.
Hallucinations.
My son. I keep seeing him on the ship.
I just... I just talked to him.
Your away team.
James and Dunning went offworld
with you to the last planet.
Maybe they picked something up.
We didn't ingest anything that...
It could've been airborne,
any number of possibilities.
Corporal Barnes was on
the away team, as well.
So was Dr. Volker.
VOLKER: Help!
Oh, please, somebody help me!
Colonel, we got him.
- Nothing?
- No.
No weird things out of the corner
of your eye?
- YOUNG: Disorientation?
- No.
Feeling pretty much the way I always do.
Hungry, tired, but I'm not seeing things.
Maybe she's immune to whatever it is
the others picked up.
Maybe her symptoms
are just taking longer to show up.
Thanks.
- But physically, they're okay?
- So far as I can tell, yeah.
He's doing fine, but I'm going
to quarantine the entire away team.
Hopefully isolate the hallucinations
until they pass.
What if they don't pass?
What if it gets worse?
I'm sure whatever it is, T.J.'ll figure it out.
I mean, she's done pretty damn good
so far.
- Is there anything I can do?
- No. No, I'll pass the word.
I'll let everyone know what's going on,
but the situation's been contained,
so there's no need for anybody
to get alarmed.
As soon as I know anything...
JOHANSEN:
Colonel Young, come in.
Yeah, T.J.
Can you come to the infirmary?
I just discovered something.
You see?
JOHANSEN: So, it's difficult to see,
which is why I missed it
on my initial examination.
- You see right there?
- YOUNG: Hmm. Yeah, it looks like a tick.
JOHANSEN: Yeah,
I just checked the others.
They all have one, same spot,
the top of the neck there.
All except Corporal Barnes. She's clear.
CHLOE: Welcome to our new galaxy.
So, the ticks are causing
the hallucinations?
I don't know for sure, but I think so.
Maybe they inject a venom, some sort of
toxin that affects the brain's chemistry.
VOLKER: Okay, I want out.
Please, just get me out of here.
I want out of here, T.J.
Okay, okay, just relax, okay?
Can you remove it?
They seem similar to Earth ticks.
I could try and remove it the same way.
You up for going first?
JOHANSEN: Okay.
JOHANSEN: Lieutenant Scott?
CHLOE: What happened?
JOHANSEN: I don't know.
He's crashing. Let's start CPR.
He's breathing.
He's back.
YOUNG: All right.
Did we get it? We remove it?
JOHANSEN: It's dug in even deeper.
His pulse is normal. BP's back in range.
YOUNG: Listen.
- Is removing them impossible?
- No.
It's just that when I tried to pull it off,
it must have released more toxin.
I just have to figure out another way.
YOUNG: Get to it.
CHLOE: Hello?
Hello, sweetheart.
It's all right. It's really me.
No. No, you're... You're not real.
- Chloe.
- Oh, God.
No, this isn't happening.
Hey. Chloe.
Look at me.
Whether I'm real or not,
aren't you at least happy
to see your old man?
I have missed you, sweetheart.
I missed you so much.
RUSH: So, where do you want to put them?
WRAY: If we do this, then we could...
RUSH: Just... Okay.
Hey!
- What's going on here?
- What do you mean?
- We're just talking.
- About what?
Is something bothering you, Sergeant?
I don't know. Should there be?
If you've got something to say,
why don't you just go ahead and say it?
You're not taking over this ship again.
We've no intentions of doing so.
You're being paranoid.
I know you're up to something.
RUSH: And you have proof of this, do you?
Of course you don't.
Are we done here?
CHLOE: We haven't had any luck yet
figuring out a way home.
God knows if we ever will.
We do have the communication stones.
I was able to use them to go see Mom.
How is she?
Strong. Fragile.
Doing her best, considering.
She's a fighter. Like you.
Sometimes I see you in my dreams,
but they always end the same.
I'm trying to get through this,
but it just gets so...
Hey, one step at a time.
Look at that view.
God, I've never seen anything like it.
I've always dreamed that you would live
a life of adventure. Travel the world.
I know. You told me frequently.
Well, look at you now.
Sailing through the universe,
exploring galaxies and planets.
You're living my dream, kiddo.
YOUNG: Hey, what do you got?
The venom we extracted
from the jungle planet creature.
It worked as an anesthetic on Rush
during his surgery.
I think that if I apply it topically
to the tick...
YOUNG: Knock it out,
- give you time to remove it.
- Yeah.
YOUNG: That's great.
Oh, he's coming to.
What happened?
You got a jolt
when we tried to remove the tick.
Relax, just relax.
We're going to try to anesthetize it,
and then I'll try and see
if I can remove it safely, okay?
Okay, let's just take a look here.
It's gone. The tick.
- It just died off?
- JOHANSEN: I don't know.
- Theirs are both still attached.
- Volker, as well?
Could it have jumped?
Yeah, no, I remember.
Gosh, that's so funny,
I feel like that was forever ago.
Hey.
What are you doing?
What's wrong?
Chloe?
- I'm fine.
- Really? 'Cause you don't seem fine.
My father's here.
I mean, I... I know he's not here. I'm just...
Just hallucinating?
It's really strange. He's so
real.
- You're seeing him right now?
- Yes.
- Where?
- Right beside me.
- Hello, Mr. Wallace.
- He can't hear you.
Okay. Chloe, we've got to
get you to the infirmary,
just have T.J. take a look...
No, I already know what's wrong.
There's a tick on me.
Matt and his team picked them up
on the last planet.
- One must have jumped to me somehow...
- Wait a minute. What?
An alien tick? Are you kidding me?
T.J. thinks it might inject some
kind of toxin that causes people to...
- Look, we have to go. Chloe...
- No! No, wait!
- It doesn't hurt.
- That's not the point...
And he's not hurting me either.
He? You mean your imaginary father?
I'm not crazy. I know what's going on.
I know that he's not real, but I can't...
I'm not ready to lose him again, okay?
You can't let that thing stay on you.
I know, okay? I know.
Just humor me, all right?
Give me some time.
I'll go see T.J. soon, I promise,
but for now, just don't tell anyone, okay?
Please, Eli.
Okay, Sergeant, I've...
Help! Help!
I don't see anything. You're clear, too.
What happened to it?
Listen, I want you to go back
to your quarters,
- and stay there until...
- No.
Just a precaution. Make sure nothing...
- I need to be here.
- Cole can take over for you.
No, Colonel, please, I'm fine.
Look, we'll check ourselves periodically,
and if I start having
any hallucinations, then...
Chloe. She was in here earlier.
I'll go find her.
Ready?
Okay?
Colonel Young, come in.
Colonel Young, do you read?
Eli.
- Hey. Are you okay? I heard you...
- I'm fine. Have you seen Chloe?
Eli?
Yeah.
- Matt.
- Hey.
I need you to come with me
to the infirmary.
There's a chance that the tick
that was on me jumped to you.
Have you been seeing any weird things?
No.
- I'm fine...
- Chloe.
- She's seeing her dad.
- CHLOE: Eli!
We need to get you to the infirmary.
No, just wait a minute.
I just need a little more time...
We can't risk letting that thing
stay on you.
- Don't leave me. Chloe!
- No. Wait! I'm not...
SCOTT: Come on, Chloe. Chloe?
- Come on. Come on. Come on.
- No. No.
SCOTT: Come on. It'll be okay.
Can I help you with something, Sergeant?
You can start by wiping that smile off
your face.
What smile?
I'd appreciate you not telling lies about me
to Colonel Young.
Lies?
Telling him that I was in the Gate Room,
messing with the consoles.
I don't know what kind of game
you're playing, Sergeant, but...
What are you doing?
There it is.
I don't know why you have to remove it.
- It's not hurting me.
- You don't know that.
It's making you hallucinate.
Who knows what else it's doing?
It's too dangerous to leave in place.
Guys, this discussion needs to end now.
Let's... Let's remove it.
Tell your mother that I love her. I miss her.
I love you, Daddy.
ARMSTRONG: I love you, too, sweetheart.
You're living our dream. Remember that.
GREER:
Colonel Young, come in.
Go ahead, Sergeant.
Colonel Young, we have a problem.
The civilians are trying
to take over the ship again.
- What?
- I'm pursuing Rush.
He and Wray are actively trying
to seize control of the ship.
Now, I don't know who else
is working with them, sir,
but we need to mobilize now.
Sergeant, I need you to listen to me.
Do not do anything. I will talk to them.
Permission to use deadly force.
What? No. Did you hear what I said?
I need you to stand down.
Do not do anything.
YOUNG: Permission granted.
Use whatever force necessary
to stop them.
Copy that.
Sergeant, we don't know
if these channels have been compromised.
Go to radio silence.
Yes, sir.
Greer, acknowledge. I said stand down.
ELI: You think
he might be hallucinating, too?
How? All the ticks
have been accounted for.
Unless there was more than one tick
on each of you when you guys got back.
- Go find Greer.
- Yes, sir.
YOUNG: We need to examine
everyone on this ship.
- Quarantine anyone who's clear.
- Yes, sir.
Sergeant Greer.
I know you're in here, Rush.
Show yourself!
WRAY: No!
What are you doing? Open that door!
You're not taking over the ship again.
SCOTT:
Colonel Young, come in.
Go ahead, Scott.
No sign of Greer.
Still not responding to any radio calls.
Well, keep at it.
Sir, Rush and Wray
are also unaccounted for.
No one knows where they are.
Rush isn't responding to his radio, either.
All right.
I'll put a few more details together.
- T.J.
- Excuse me.
So, listen, I got to go help look for Greer.
You going to be okay?
Yeah, fine.
But if you feel any different,
you see anything out of the usual...
No, believe me,
I'm as concerned about this as you are.
- Okay. Fine, but keep me posted.
- Yeah.
Thanks.
ELI: More than one tick
attached to you would explain
why some of the hallucinations
were more intense than others.
The toxins,
maybe they target the limbic system.
It's the area of the brain
that's responsible for emotion.
So, fear, anger, remorse...
Matt's guilt over his son.
Claustrophobia.
My dad.
Let me guess, issue with snakes?
And you?
Listen to me.
I can't stop the bleeding.
You have to open that door.
If I don't get medical attention...
Yes, Colonel.
No, sir, I do not know
who else is involved in the mutiny.
She's refusing to cooperate.
You're not talking to anyone.
Your radio is off!
What is the matter with you?
Yes, I will continue the interrogation,
but at some point, sir, we are just
better off ending this once and for all.
Sergeant. Sergeant, listen to me.
Sergeant Greer!
We are not taking over the ship!
What do you got?
Can't get the door open.
Must have been disabled from the inside.
I heard Wray's voice.
- Camile? It's Lieutenant Scott!
- Scott, help!
I'm wounded!
Sergeant Greer has got us hostage...
Shut...
Quiet, now.
Sergeant Greer, it's Lieutenant Scott!
Stand down!
- Colonel Young. This is Scott, come in.
- YOUNG: Yeah.
We found him. He has locked himself
and Wray in one of the storage rooms.
I think he's holding her hostage.
That's it.
I'm done with you.
Please.
Sergeant, don't.
Do it.
I said do it.
Colonel Young.
Colonel, we got them.
Send T.J. We have wounded in here.
- How you doing?
- Okay.
JOHANSEN: I was able to stop the bleeding
and stitch the wound,
so we'll keep an eye out for infection,
but she should be okay.
- The rest of the crew?
- I checked everyone.
It looks like we got them all, so...
Hopefully things will get back to normal
around here.
Whatever that is.
Am I gonna be all right?
No, I'm not gonna be all right
Nothing is all right now
Am I gonna see the sun come up?
Or am I going down?
'Cause every day I'm here
All I feel is sheer agony
Friends telling me
That maybe I need some psychiatric help
Yeah, they're always so quick to tell you
Just how to get on with it
But I look into the mirror
And all I see is ancient fear and agony
What do we got?
Well, the atmosphere is good.
Ten hours on the countdown.
Shall we send a team?
Yeah.
Our luck's got to change at some point.
Just remember the bug spray.
Scott, this is Young.
Get a team ready. You're going offworld.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org