Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
RUSH: This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
YOUNG: We are going to survive.
We are going to make it home.
I'm telling you,
this ship came here for a reason!
RUSH: Destiny is powered
by the stars themselves.
WRAY: He and Young
are bumping heads, yes.
Not sure which camp is the better choice.
YOUNG: We just pretend
nothing happened?
We need to be ready
for the next encounter.
For the sake of the crew.
Eli, do not let that man
take over a single system.
He's doing it anyway.
We've sealed off Colonel Young
and most of the military personnel.
We've taken the ship.
You've got our attention.
What do you want?
All military personnel
to hand over their weapons immediately.
I'm just a little surprised
you're taking Rush's side.
Rush was an inconvenience,
so Colonel Young left him
on that planet to die.
ELI: He has a transmitter
implanted in his chest.
That's how they've been following us.
Even if we survive to the next jump,
they'll just track us again.
WRAY: Obviously, we need to
find a way to work together.
YOUNG: Pretend it never happened?
You shouldn't have left him on the planet.
You think I don't know that?
Should you be out of bed?
There's too much work to be done.
We'd best get on with it.
"We"?
Ready.
All right, go ahead and re-pressurize.
PARK: Re-pressurizing.
BRODY ON RADIO: It's holding steady.
And we've got atmosphere.
RUSH: Very good.
Continue with the repairs,
beginning with navigation and propulsion.
BRODY: Roger that.
YOUNG: What the hell are you doing?
Repairing the damaged shuttle,
if that's all right.
- I mean, you just had surgery.
- I'm fine, thank you.
You look like you're ready to drop dead.
And that would be a bad thing?
Yes, Rush, that would be a bad thing.
Listen to me, the civilians aboard this ship
didn't try to take over
because they thought
I was doing a bang-up job. I get that.
Well, good for you.
I also get that I have to make this work.
So, I've ordered my people
to make a special effort.
I would like to do the same, even with you.
Wow. That must have taken
quite the effort.
You have no idea.
Lieutenant Scott,
we just dropped out of FTL.
- Please have a team ready on standby.
- SCOTT: Yes, sir.
- But the gate isn't dialing.
- YOUNG: Why not?
- Because there's nothing there.
- What?
It appears we have dropped out of FTL
into empty space.
No planets, no stars, nothing.
SCOTT: You might want to re-check
that data.
The ships that are seeding the gates
ahead of Destiny,
I thought they send a record
of the star systems in our path.
They do.
That star is not supposed to be here.
SCOTT: Sit tight, guys. Gate's not dialing.
They think it might be
some kind of a glitch in the database.
And here I was worried
I'd have to cut short my delicious meal.
You okay? Look like you might be
coming down with something.
I'm fine. Just tired.
We call that cold. Yeah.
Yeah, it's going to take a little time.
And "a special effort on our part
towards a spirit of cooperation."
The Colonel's right about that.
We have to live with these people.
Doesn't mean I got to like it.
Yeah, you do.
At least, you have to look like you do.
Good luck with that.
All right, am I wrong?
Does she look like
she's coming down with something?
RUSH: It's a G-2 star.
Yellow dwarf, similar to our own sun.
Because Destiny didn't know it was here,
the star's gravity well disrupted
our propulsion systems,
causing us to drop out of FTL prematurely.
It's a glitch in the technology.
So, what happens now?
We've entered a parabolic course.
Once we're around the star,
we'll be far enough away
from its gravitational influence,
back into FTL, and on our way.
How long's that going to take?
A few weeks.
There is, however, a silver lining.
A planet?
RUSH: Only one in the solar system,
so far as I can see.
About the same size as Earth.
- Looks close.
- RUSH: It is.
Within shuttle range.
Atmosphere?
In a word? Perfect.
I've been over the database a dozen times.
No evidence of any glitch or anomaly.
ELI: Yeah, I couldn't find anything either.
It's like this star
just appeared out of nowhere.
Well, vigorous surface activity,
strong stellar winds, bipolar outflow.
It's brand-new, all right.
It's straight out of T Tauri phase.
Which would still make it like, what,
100 million years old?
It's 200 million.
And how far ahead of us
are those gate-seeding ships?
It doesn't make any sense.
The ships would have noticed it.
And dropped a shiny new stargate
on the planet.
That's the weirder thing about this.
I mean, if this star really is this young,
then that planet should still be
a ball of molten rock.
All right, we're through the upper
atmosphere. Everything looks good.
I'm going to set her down
on that land mass directly below us.
- No sign of any wildlife.
- CAINE: That we can see.
It's pure.
How you feeling?
Great. A little sunshine, fresh air, water.
Just what I needed.
GREER: Yo, check this out!
There's a whole grove of trees back there
loaded with these things.
JOHANSEN: Hmm.
It's like a kiwi.
We'll take it back and do an edibility test...
- I'll do one right now.
- Greer!
What the hell are you doing?
Oh.
- That's nice.
- We don't even know if it's poisonous.
We will.
SCOTT ON RADIO: We're getting
a ton of plant samples.
T.J. thinks there's all sorts
of medicinal possibilities.
Well, that's great, that's great.
We also found some fruit.
Greer went ahead and ate one.
So far he hasn't had any reactions to it.
How about water?
Tons of it. Pure, too.
Bring back as much of it as we can.
No alien creatures slithering around?
No, nothing.
It's weird, but it's daytime,
so who knows what comes out at night?
All right, load up the shuttle,
and head on back.
Do a fly-over of the area on your way.
Copy that. Scott out.
SCOTT: There you are.
JOHANSEN: This place.
It reminds me of home.
We used to go camping,
Olympic Peninsula.
My dad and I,
we'd go hiking for days at a time,
find these amazing vistas and canyons,
waterfalls.
Time to go, T.J.
Damn near perfect.
It doesn't make any sense,
the ship not knowing about this place.
Of all the planets to put a stargate on,
I would think that...
Looks like we weren't the first ones here.
SCOTT: It's massive.
2,000 feet high, at least.
We detected a faint EM field around it,
but nothing else.
Those markings,
like some kind of alien language.
Do you think it's the same ones
we keep running into?
Not with this level of technology.
- What, to build this thing?
- No.
To create a planet.
They actually built this planet?
The Genesis device.
The end of Wrath of Khan.
The reason why Destiny
had no knowledge of this star system
is that it was placed there
after the gate-seeding ships
had passed through.
Wait, you're telling me
they built the star, too?
That would make them the number-one
all-time advanced civilization.
RUSH: That would be an understatement.
Okay, so what do we do about this?
We send a team back down there.
What?
Look, our orbit has been refined.
It's going to be four weeks, two days,
seven hours before we jump back to FTL.
I'm proposing
we take advantage of the wait.
I thought you said
we were almost out of shuttle range.
We are,
but we're going to swing back into range
once we circle the star
and before we jump to FTL.
We send a team down now,
pick them back up in a month's time,
loaded with supplies.
We time it right on the return,
we could take two, maybe three trips.
What about the aliens?
We didn't see them.
Well, it doesn't mean
that they're not around.
Look, we have three hours left
before we're out of shuttle range.
If we're going to do this,
we have to do it quickly.
Okay, okay, just to say this out loud,
assuming that this star
and this planet were created
by the most incredibly
advanced aliens ever,
maybe they don't want
anyone messing around with it.
We need the food and medicine.
RUSH: I agree.
The gains outweigh the risks.
ELI: Do they?
We're 0-for-3 on close encounters
of the third kind.
What makes you think that
these guys are going to be any different?
I'm not sending anyone down there
without protection.
And we'll have the shuttle
in case we got to bug out.
Eli.
Everything we do out here is a risk.
- WRAY: T.J.?
- Hi.
I heard you found some plants
with possible analgesic properties?
Yes, high concentration of salicin.
Similar to aspirin. You got a headache?
Only since I've been on this ship.
Take these, steep them in hot water,
and drink it.
So, you're joining the team
going down to the planet?
Yeah, all types of medicinals.
I can't pass it up. How about you?
I don't know.
I mean, part of me wants to,
but what if Rush's calculations are off?
Can we trust him?
You tell me.
YOUNG: I want round-the-clock watch
on camps.
Guard details on every science team
going into the woods.
SCOTT: Yes, sir.
YOUNG: Hopefully we'll be able to fix
the damaged shuttle before you return,
and double up on supplies
we can bring back.
- Good luck.
- SCOTT: Thanks.
You're coming, too?
- Is there a problem with that?
- YOUNG: No. Happy camping.
- You all set?
- Yes, sir.
Cole will be looking after Franklin
in the infirmary while I'm away.
I told her to contact me
if there's any change in his condition.
- Is there anything else?
- No, sir.
SCOTT ON RADIO: We're clear.
YOUNG: We'll see you in a month.
All right, folks, you got the whole month
to enjoy the scenery.
We need to set up camp,
establish a perimeter.
Sun moves that way. Guys? Over here.
Sun moves that way, so that's west, okay?
River's back that way
about half a klick... Kilometer.
We'll sleep in the shuttle for now,
but I want shelters built ASAP.
How many of you guys
have gone camping before?
Well, okay, that's fine.
Just watch, ask, and learn.
You guys know your team assignments.
Let's get going.
MAN: Okay. Let's go.
WOMAN: Yeah, I got it.
Um...
I don't have a team yet.
Yeah, right, sorry.
Do you feel like helping T.J. with plants?
- Sure.
- Okay.
GREER: Hey, hey, hey, hey!
What's going on over here?
I'm not digging the latrine.
- Is that what you told him to do?
- Somebody's got to do it.
True enough. Start digging.
- What? No, you can't make me.
- You, too.
- But, Sergeant, I...
- You're going to dig, okay?
You're both going to dig,
and you're going to
love every moment of it,
or you will keep digging until you do.
The spirit of co-operation.
We're all friends now.
So, we'll photograph
and log every plant we find.
Don't ingest anything
until we do a proper edibility test.
- You all right?
- Yeah, just...
It's passing. I'm fine.
The amount of food and water
we get on that ship,
it's a wonder we're not all fainting
from malnutrition.
Yeah.
SCOTT: Well, I just got the word.
Destiny is now officially out of range.
No turning back.
We are stuck here.
- WRAY: Hey.
- Hey.
How's it going?
Well, I hope they bring back
tons of food.
The last of that fruit
that they brought back is already gone.
Or so you think.
Snuck this earlier.
I'll split it with you
if you promise not to rat me out.
Deal.
So, tell me... Thanks.
You think it's possible to create a star?
No. No way.
Now, being transported to a ship
on the other side of the universe
by a wormhole,
that's totally doable.
Look, that star just appeared
out of nowhere
and the planet's age doesn't match.
If some all-powerful alien beings
didn't create it,
who did?
Jeez, hey, I'm sorry.
I'll go somewhere else.
Oh, no. No, no, that's okay.
Hey, I wanted to thank you.
I know all the military personnel
are trying to mend fences,
but you're one of the few
who actually seems to mean it.
Yeah, well, we've got to work it out, right?
It's interesting that we've now been
given the time down here to do that.
Yeah, well, we were pretty lucky
to find this place.
My mom used to say
there's no such thing as luck,
only the hand of God giving you
a little help when you need it most.
Somewhere along the line, I mean,
I stopped believing all that.
But now, I look at this place...
I mean, put right in our path for us to find.
Tell me that isn't a miracle.
Hey, how's it going?
- Terrible.
- Great.
Which is it?
Propulsion's almost completely shot.
Might be able to get to the point
where we can fly down to the planet,
but there's no way it's going to have
enough power to get back up.
So, there's that. We're making
some progress on navigation.
We can turn left, but not right,
or up, or down.
Okay. Why did you say "great"?
We can turn left.
RUSH ON RADIO: Colonel Young.
- Go ahead.
- While Destiny's engines are off-line,
I'd like to use the extra power
to strengthen the shield,
maybe explore some damaged areas
in the ship, possibly make some repairs.
Reclaim some real estate.
Exactly.
You go ahead. I'll have Lieutenant James
put a team together.
You two, you keep at it.
You have a month to get this thing
to fly to and from that planet
and do more than make a left turn.
- Fate brought us here?
- I don't know, maybe.
Maybe that's what brought us to Icarus,
and then Destiny.
JOHANSEN: You don't believe that?
What, you miss your flight
and the plane crashes?
You weren't spared for a reason.
God doesn't have a master plan for you.
Things just happen.
So we're born, we live, we die?
It's all random?
Yeah, and along the way, you do the best
with whatever crap you happen to step in.
WRAY: I'm starting to get a bad feeling.
ELI: Me, too.
I'm afraid we made a mistake
sending those people down to that planet.
No.
The mistake was not going with them.
I have been searching
all of my days
All of my days
Many a road, you know
I've been walking on
All of my days
And I've been trying to find
What's been in my mind
As the days keep turning into night
Well, I have been quietly standing
in the shade
All of my days
Watch the sky breaking on the promise
that we made
All of this rain
And I've been trying to find
What's been in my mind
As the days keep turning into night
Hey. You okay? Here...
I thought you were feeling better.
Yeah. I am.
Here, let me help you back to camp.
You should lie down.
No, Chloe. I'm not sick.
How far along?
About 15 weeks.
Right before we left Icarus.
But nobody knows,
and I'd like to keep it that way.
- Eventually, they're going to...
- I know.
I know, but not now.
I'll figure out when the right time is. Okay?
Yeah. Sure.
Back on the ship, I wasn't doing well,
getting anemic, but out here,
with all the food and water.
Actually, the morning sickness
is a good sign.
What about the father?
- What the hell is it?
- RUSH: I don't know yet.
JAMES: Looks like a robot.
Figure it out.
RUSH: Yeah, no problem.
Once I've attended
to the other 100 things on my list.
You can always put somebody else on it.
I'm not going to have anyone
touch this thing without me present.
I'm going to get to it, Colonel.
- Close it up.
- JAMES: Okay.
SCOTT: Hey.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Homesick for Destiny?
Only a few more days till we head back.
Honestly?
No. I'm not.
I like it here.
I'm starting to wonder if Dr. Caine is right.
That it's no accident we found this planet.
- We were brought here by God?
- Or whoever. I don't know.
I mean, if some alien beings
are powerful enough to create this place,
maybe there is some kind of higher power
in the universe
that knew we were in trouble,
put this planet here for us to find.
Maybe it's time we stop thinking about...
Hey, what's that?
YOUNG: When?
SCOTT ON RADIO: Tonight, just now,
coming from the obelisk,
shooting straight up into the sky.
Dr. Volker detected
some kind of a strange radiation.
He's working on it, but it's like
this whole thing suddenly came to life.
Why now?
Why not when they first got there?
Perhaps their initial impact wasn't
enough to trigger an alert. But now...
So, this light, you think
it'll bring the aliens back to the planet?
YOUNG: You won't be there to find out.
SCOTT: Destiny is almost in range.
Colonel Young wants us
to start breaking up camp,
- get ready to head back.
- VOLKER: What about the obelisk?
- I still need time to figure...
- SCOTT: We don't have enough time.
We need to be ready to fly
as soon as Destiny is in range
so we can make a couple trips,
and get all that food back to the ship.
All right, people, you heard the man.
Move your asses! Let's go!
- Yes?
- Yes.
- Well...
- BRODY: No.
Again with this?
The shuttle can fly. It can now go both left
and right and up and down.
But like I said before,
too many problems with propulsion.
Fact is, we may never be able
to fully repair it.
JAMES: All kinds of citrus-type fruits,
beans, potatoes...
Sweet potatoes.
Scott says they're amazing.
They cannot get back here fast enough.
You seem concerned, Dr. Rush.
- Something we should know about?
- No.
No problems with your calculations, right?
The shuttle will return as scheduled?
Yeah, and Destiny will leave this system,
never knowing who created it or why.
You might want to give her some time.
Well, we're breaking camp,
and she just takes off without telling me?
She's thinking about staying here.
A lot of people are.
Come on, you can't be surprised.
You've heard people talking about it.
- They like it here.
- I like it here, too, but we cannot stay.
- It is out of the question.
- Why not?
If people want to stay, they have the right.
Where the hell have you been?
We've got to move.
I'm not going.
Okay, look, I understand
how you feel. I like it here, too.
But we cannot stay.
The Colonel gave us orders.
- Matt, don't.
- I can't go back there.
- SCOTT: Why not?
- It's safer here.
Safer? The aliens who built this rock
may be on their way back!
CAINE: Then good.
I mean, if they're advanced enough
to build a solar system,
I know they can help us get back home.
Not if they don't wipe us out first.
CHLOE: Why do you immediately think
they're going to harm us?
I'm sorry, do you not remember
what the last aliens did to you?
This planet was created for us.
We were led here for a reason.
For God's sake...
What if they don't come back? Then what?
I'm okay with that. I'm healthier here.
There's food and plenty of water.
And we're bringing a ton of it back!
And eventually, it'll run out.
Okay, what about the winters?
Dr. Volker, you said you found evidence
it gets very cold here.
Yes, well below freezing. For months, T.J.
So, we'll build better shelters.
CAINE: I don't even think
it will come to that.
The beings who created this world
will return,
and they will help us get back home.
I know it.
You would rather take your chances
out here than on Destiny?
CHLOE: We don't know
where that ship is going,
or if we'll ever even make it home.
There's a stargate on it.
As long as we have the potential
to connect...
JOHANSEN: Matt.
I'm pregnant.
I can't go back there.
I can't stand the thought
of raising a child on that ship.
We are in range.
You are clear to make the first trip back.
We only have the one shuttle,
so time is of the essence.
SCOTT: Sir,
we have a problem down here.
What is it?
Some of the people have decided
that they would like to
stay behind on the planet.
- Well, you tell them no.
- I tried, sir.
They have pretty much
made up their minds.
Who are they?
Eleven people total.
Dr. Caine, Chloe,
- Lieutenant Johansen...
- What?
- No! Scott, you tell them...
- And me.
- Eleven?
- YOUNG: Including some of my own people.
And Scott, he has the nerve to ask me
to fly him back down to the planet
after he drops off
the ones returning to the ship.
Well, look, I can understand
some of them wanting to stay,
but Lieutenant Scott and T.J.?
Yeah, he says he feels an obligation
to help the people survive down there.
WRAY: What are you going to do?
YOUNG: What am I going to do?
I'm going to make sure
they don't stay down there,
that's for damn sure.
WRAY: No, no, you cannot force them
to come back.
I think he can.
We're going to lose more people
through attrition aboard this ship.
We simply cannot afford to shed
that many people at one time.
So, what do you expect him to do?
Bring them back at gunpoint?
Well, if it comes to that, yes.
You allow Lieutenant Scott to return
with those who want to come back
to Destiny,
then send down a military detail
and round up the rest.
That's great, Rush, coming from you.
First you want to kick the military out,
and now you want us
rounding people up at gunpoint.
Colonel, those people have the right
to make their own decisions
about their future.
Not all of them.
Did you...
Did you tell him about me?
I'll let you do that. It's not my place.
He is the father, right?
I caught a few looks between you.
I don't think anyone else knew.
I haven't heard any rumors or anything.
Hey. Hey...
You are going to be okay.
I'll be here, and I'm not going to
let anything happen to you.
RUSH: Have you gone mad?
Man, look,
I really don't want to argue with you.
- RUSH: You're letting them stay?
- Not all of them.
- And you're giving them a shuttle?
- The damaged shuttle.
It's not damaged anymore!
Didn't you say that the shuttle
may never be fully functional?
We may need the shuttle
for any number of reasons...
I'm not going to leave those people
down there with nothing.
- You cannot let them stay, Colonel.
- I have made my decision.
Is it ready?
Yeah, but there's still some issues
as to whether it can hold up
through atmospheric entry.
Questions that are about to be answered.
Eli just radioed.
Colonel Young is on his way down here.
- Why?
- VOLKER: How?
We're entering upper atmosphere.
ON RADIO: So far, so good.
Come on, hold it together.
Yeah, right there!
Destiny, this is Young. I made it through.
Has anyone changed their minds
about returning to the ship?
No.
All right. Here's the deal.
I am leaving the damaged shuttle behind
for those who want to stay.
You can use it for shelter and power,
fly around in short hops on the surface.
You will not be able to leave
the atmosphere, so don't even try.
What it will do is give you guys
a fighting chance while you are down here,
especially with winter on the way.
- Thank you, Colonel. I know this isn't...
- I'm not finished.
I will leave it for you
only under one condition.
All military personnel
will return with me to Destiny.
- What?
Reject my proposal,
and we'll take you all back by force.
You can't do that.
That's not something
you want to test, Doctor.
SCOTT: Sir, some of these people
just don't feel safe on board.
None of us feels safe.
That doesn't mean we give up.
They're not giving up.
That ship is the best chance we have
of getting home.
CAINE: I disagree, sir.
I believe we were brought here
for a reason,
and that whoever created this planet
will provide for us.
They are our best chance
of getting back home.
Okay.
What's it going to be?
- GREER: Colonel.
- Sergeant.
You want to stay here out of obligation
to these people, to protect them?
I can respect that. But there are people
back on the ship who don't have a choice,
and you have an obligation to them
as well, Lieutenant.
T.J., they need you.
Welcome home.
Well, as predicted,
we've corrected our course
and jumped back into FTL.
I'm sorry you didn't get your wish.
And what wish was that?
Aliens advanced enough
that they could build a star system.
Finally somebody you could have
a decent conversation with.
I enjoy chess.
- Colonel, do you have a moment?
- Can it wait?
I wanted to better explain my reasons
for choosing to stay behind.
Look, I realize you're probably
not hungry, Lieutenant, but I am.
I hear they're serving up a feast
in the mess,
so why don't we talk about it later?
- Sir...
- Later.
What if we were meant to stay there?
All of us?
What if that planet was a lifeline,
and we just let it go?
I can't pretend to answer that, Matthew.
No one can.
Even breathing feels all right
Yes, even breathing feels all right
Now even breathing feels all right
Yes, even breathing
Feels all right
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org