This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
That ship is the best chance
we have of getting home.
- Are we done?
- We'll never be done.
You shouldn't have
left him on the planet.
You think I don't know that?
Everyone thinks we're safe.
They think that they'll never find us again.
Why did you take
one of our people prisoner?
We're not safe, are we?
They're coming!
- Who's coming?
Lucian Alliance,
they're coming to take Destiny.
There's only one way
this is going to end if we wait.
I'm not
surrendering this ship.
I want to know how long you
plan on keeping us locked up.
What do we have to do to earn our freedom?
Prove to me that you're not a threat.
My mom was a nurse.
She got stuck by a needle trying
to restrain a junkie in the ER.
She got HIV.
Do whatever you need to do
to get yourself back home,
'cause I'm going to be here.
What happened?
- You were shot.
There is no leg wound.
It's almost completely healed.
How is that possible?
I don't know.
Hey. What are you doing in here?
Are you okay?
I don't know how I got here.
The last thing I remember,
I was lying down for a nap.
Sleepwalking?
I used to do it all the time as a kid.
My dad had to put an alarm
on the front door to make...
- I'll see you later.
- O...
kay.
Seriously.
And it's not just this one thing.
She's been acting a little odd for a while now.
You know what I'm talking about, right?
It's not just me noticing...
No, no. You're right.
She's been acting... different.
She's quiet and withdrawn.
We should talk to her about it.
I did. I mean, I tried, yesterday.
And?
And nothing. She wasn't in the mood.
She was too busy writing in her diary.
She keeps a diary?
It's kind of a therapy for her.
It's all the stress of being on the ship...
And what about that gunshot wound
on her leg?
No one heals that fast.
How do you explain that?
Eli, I can't.
You need to use the stones.
Your mother's sick.
What... Is she...
I don't know the details. Just that
they want you to go back as soon...
You need to sleep, Nic.
- Nicholas...
- Yes, yes. Soon.
Manipulating the countdown clock is
complicated, to say the least.
So many variables tied into it.
Well, that's the problem, isn't it?
A myriad of systems,
each as complicated as the next.
Made worse by one man trying
to do the work of an entire crew.
Well, for now, I just need to control
the countdown clock,
and if you are indeed the ship,
why aren't you helping me?
What are you really hoping to gain?
Control of the ship is key to the mission.
Dr. Rush, this is Brody. Come in.
Go ahead.
We just dropped out of FTL.
Yes, I'm aware of that, thank you.
But again, no gates in range.
And now we're banking left,
changing course again.
It doesn't make sense.
Dr. Rush?
Look, I'm sorry.
I can't get away right now.
- Where are you?
- What are you doing?
Rush, out.
This is getting ridiculous.
Getting old, is what it is.
She stopped taking her treatment.
Unfortunately, her counts dropped,
dipping below 300.
Opening the door for pneumonia.
We've re-started the AVR therapy,
and we're successfully
treating the pneumonia.
Her counts have leveled off,
so physically, she's on the mend.
But if she stops taking
her treatment again...
Don't let her.
- Okay, when she returns home...
- Don't release her. Keep her here.
We will monitor her condition closely,
but what concerns me is she is still
clearly suffering from depression.
One of our psychiatrists
has been treating her,
but hasn't made much progress,
which is why we sent for you.
Look, whether here or at home,
she has to want to get better.
There's no room for error now.
If her counts drop below 200...
Yeah, yeah, I know.
AIDS.
I'll be down the hall if you need me.
Hi.
I'm
Airman Tracy.
I've been working with your son, Eli.
Is he all right?
Yeah, he's fine.
He really wanted to be here, but the
military, they've got him pretty tied up.
He's doing great things, though,
working really hard.
Anyway,
he heard about you being in the hospital.
Tell him I'm fine.
No, but see, he...
He knows you're not fine.
He told me about your condition.
He heard you stopped taking your meds,
and he's really...
Really worried about you.
Not enough to be here himself.
Yeah, it's me.
I was just checking.
Where are we?
What?
You and me. Our relationship.
I mean,
if we had met in a different situation,
away from this ship,
would we still be together?
Of course.
It's just...
This is all kind of new to me,
you know?
I've never been all that great at
relationships and...
I just want to make sure
that I don't mess this up.
You've been kind of quiet lately,
so I start wondering and thinking,
"God, she's..."
Matt.
Ta-da! Your favorite.
Mmm! I am really missing your cooking.
Microwave's getting a lot of work, huh?
Yeah, and take-out. Mostly take-out.
You know me. I work most nights, so,
a lot of pizza.
Everything okay?
Of course. You're here.
Everything is perfect.
Mmm! It's really good.
Go.
You're releasing them?
We can't keep them
locked up forever, Sergeant.
Sir, I beg to differ.
We're not doing it
without strings attached.
They've been giving us intel.
The more they give, the more they get.
The decision's made, Sergeant.
I've put an escort
on each Lucian Alliance member,
so it's not like they're
walking around free.
Excuse me, Colonel? Have you seen Chloe?
No.
I've been searching everywhere for her.
She's gone.
Mornin'.
Yeah, so the clock says.
Well, apparently it's Sunday, too.
The colonel decided to release them
into the general population.
We'll see how that turns out.
Whoa!
Doesn't look like it's off to a good start.
- Hey! What's going on here?
- Just making conversation.
No, no. You apologize to her.
- Why?
- Apologize!
- All right, take it easy.
- Think you can tell me what to do?
- As a matter of fact, I do.
- I'm not trying to...
What the hell are you...
You don't mess with my people.
- Just talking to the woman.
- No, see, you don't talk to anyone.
Oh, is she yours? I didn't know.
Put him back in the hold
till he learns some manners.
I'm sorry, I'm not trying to...
No, no. See, the more you talk,
the longer you'll be locked up.
You okay?
Chloe's missing.
Colonel wants us to form search teams
and look for her.
You work yourself to exhaustion.
Much work to be done.
Lack of sleep leads to carelessness.
I needn't remind you
that two lives have already been lost.
Colonel... I know. I'm sorry.
- My behavior, unacceptable.
- Yeah, it was.
I know it's important to fit in.
To get along with your people,
and I can do this, I promise.
We made a deal.
We give you information,
you give us freedom.
And I intend to hold up
my end of that deal.
You can trust me.
Chloe.
What are you doing in here?
Lieutenant Scott,
we found her.
Copy that.
What are you looking for?
- My keys.
- You can't find your keys.
- No. I thought they were in my purse, but...
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is a first.
You know, you've never misplaced
anything as long as I can...
Are you going to
help me find them or not?
I'm sorry.
It's just, I'm late, and I can't...
I was bringing the groceries in yesterday.
Idiot.
- It's okay.
- No, it's not.
Because anyone could've walked in here
and taken all of our things...
Sharon.
I'll be an hour at most, maybe two.
I'll call you if anything changes.
Morning.
You up for company?
Sure.
You're looking better.
Doctor said you'll be
out of here in no time.
Why doesn't he call me?
It's been months now. Nothing.
It's not like him.
Okay, okay.
What's your favorite movie of all time?
What?
Just go with me on this.
Your favorite movie.
Grease.
No, there's another one.
- Sound of Music?
- No, what...
Your favorite science fiction movie?
- I'm not a fan of...
- E. T.
Right?
- That's your favorite.
- Yes.
I love that movie.
You rented it and showed it to him
when he was a kid.
You wondered if aliens really existed.
If it's possible to fly spaceships
to other planets in other solar systems.
- What has this got to do with...
- It is
possible.
Not just to other solar systems,
other galaxies.
You see, the government,
they have this program,
the Stargate program.
And what a Stargate is,
is it's like a doorway.
It allows you to step through
and travel great distances through space,
halfway across the universe
in some cases...
- Why are you telling me this?
- Because I am Eli.
I'm on a ship, far, far away,
but my consciousness
is in this person's body.
It really is me, Mom. I am your son.
You have no memory
of going into the storage room?
No, I fell asleep in my quarters.
Next thing I know,
I'm talking to Lieutenant James.
This isn't the first time
this has happened, is it?
It's like I black out from time to time.
Those aliens
used the communication stones
- to take control of Lieutenant James.
- Because we forgot to reset them.
I was just in the communications lab.
The stones are clean.
Listen, there doesn't seem to be anything
physically wrong with you that I can tell.
I'd need an EEG or a CAT scan
to be more thorough.
I would like to keep her overnight, though,
for observation.
That's a good idea.
And once the stone is in place
and the device is turned on,
you actually swap consciousness
with the person on the other end.
You go into their body
and then they go into yours, and...
And...
You don't believe me.
- I don't understand.
- I know. I know it's weird.
Where is Eli?
He's on a ship, okay, the Destiny,
on the other side of the universe.
When is he coming home?
I don't know, it's a long, long way.
Billions of light years from Earth.
- How did he get there?
- The Stargate, Mom!
Okay. Okay, Mom...
Stop calling me that. You are not my son.
The day Dad left,
I was 14.
I ran up to my room, crying.
You came up,
told me that I needed to be strong for you.
You said I needed to be the man
that he wasn't.
Remember?
How could I know that if I wasn't Eli?
He could've told you.
How could he possibly have told me
every little thing about his...
- Leave me alone!
- Please, Mom. It really is me.
- Nurse, nurse!
- I know it's a lot to take in. Mom?
- Nurse! Please leave.
- Please.
What is it? Ancient?
Some of it.
Those symbols, they looked familiar to me,
and then I remembered where I saw them.
In the crashed alien ship.
Some of this I understand,
but most of it's too far advanced.
They must've done something to her,
planted something in her brain.
You said she didn't have
any tracking devices in her.
No, she didn't. Not that I was aware of.
There may be something happening
to Chloe on a cellular level.
Some kind of genetic manipulation
gradually changing her.
- Into what?
- You think she's changing into one of them?
I want her quarantined.
We don't know for sure
if that's what's going on here.
- We cannot just lock her up.
- Until we know what's wrong with her,
I can't risk letting her walk around free
on this ship, can I?
I think the risk might be worth it.
If we can monitor her behavior,
the frequency of her blackouts,
where she goes, what she does,
we might gain more insight
into what's actually happening.
Certainly quicker
than isolating her in a room.
She's not to be left alone, ever.
Yes, sir.
Hey.
Thanks for coming.
I didn't have anyone else I could call.
Well, how's your mom doing?
Physically, fine.
Her pneumonia's healing.
Her T-cell counts are stable now that
they've restarted her therapy, but she's...
I was always worried she might give up
if something happened to me,
- and now, she's...
- Nothing's happened to you.
She doesn't even know it's me.
I tried to tell her.
But as far as she's concerned,
the military took her son away,
won't even tell her where he is
or won't let him talk to her.
I would give up too.
Eli,
no one is giving up.
You know, whether she believes you or not,
she has to take her meds.
And you need to make her understand that.
I can't go near the Control Interface Room
or use the stones to visit my mom.
It's only temporary, just till we figure
out what's going on here.
Lieutenant, time for a shift change.
I'll take over from here.
- Oh, it's okay. I don't mind.
- Colonel's orders, I'm afraid.
I promise I won't let her out of my sight.
It's all right.
Okay.
I'll check in on you later.
Come with me.
What is this?
A place for study.
Problems to solve.
Does any of this look familiar to you?
Take your time.
Look closely.
- Settling in?
- Yes.
Nice quarters. Come in.
The Ancients probably figured
they'd be here a while,
might as well give themselves
some measure of comfort.
How long will they
be tagging along with us?
As long as you give them reason to.
- One of your men, Simeon.
- Yes, I know. I heard. And I'm sorry.
He's not the most diplomatic person
in our group.
The culture on his homeworld
was rougher than most.
Colonel Young has decided to release him,
but if he slips up again...
I'll talk to him.
We're trying to make this work.
He needs to try harder.
Hey!
Oh, there you are.
Been looking all over for you.
You didn't answer your
radio, so I thought...
Sorry. Lost track of time.
She's all yours.
You okay?
Yeah. Fine.
What were you doing?
He wanted me to look at some equations,
- see if I understood them.
- Did you?
I don't know.
Hey, sorry I'm late.
It's just that Eli, you know,
when he gets to talking...
- How's his mother?
- Oh!
Doing okay, physically. It's just emotionally.
This is all starting to take its toll.
You okay?
Your dinner's in the oven.
You cooked?
Mmm. An attempt.
- Looks good.
- Famous last words.
So, how was your day?
Mmm, long.
Exhausting. The usual.
I'll get another.
Give us a minute. Back inside.
- I won't let you ruin this for us.
- I was just talking to the woman.
- You wanna get us all locked up for good?
- What difference does it make?
Sooner or later they're gonna realize
the information we've been feeding them
is just a bunch of lies anyway.
The information you've been feeding them.
What are you talking about?
I thought we were all giving them
the same misinformation...
We're cooperating with them, all of us.
We have to find a way
to get along with these people.
You want me to play the game, I'll play it,
but I'm not taking... I'm not taking...
Don't play any game at all.
Don't play any game at all!
Just keep your mouth shut.
Damn it.
Again with this?
- No gates.
- Altered course.
Bet you a day's rations he doesn't answer.
Dr. Rush, this is Brody. Come in.
Dr. Rush, please respond.
- You owe me.
- I never agreed to that.
I don't think
it's because of pulsar damage.
There would be a pattern to the jump
intervals, however frequent they are.
There's also the changes in the
ship's course once we drop out of FTL.
It also seems too coincidental
that every time this happens,
we can't seem to get a hold of Rush.
He's doing this? How?
Outside of cracking the master code?
- I don't know.
- Figure it out.
- Yeah. We could really use Eli for that.
- Eli's not here right now.
- Well, you can get him back.
- He needs to be where he is right now,
so I need you to figure it out.
Why is your radio off?
- Sorry, I was in my quarters sleeping.
- Wrong.
You didn't answer my call,
I sent Corporal Barnes to your quarters.
Where were you?
Okay, so what's happening? What's wrong?
Just trying to figure out
what's going on with Destiny.
Where the hell were you?
What's this?
I come here to think.
And write on the walls?
Working on problems that have confused us
since we set foot in this ship, Mr. Brody.
This one has been particularly frustrating,
and yet Chloe,
she solved it in a minute flat.
Whatever alien influence she's under,
it's studying this ship.
So you think she's hijacked the ship's
system during one of her blackouts?
Something she could have set in motion
days, perhaps even weeks ago.
This section's off limits.
- Wasn't earlier.
- It is now.
- Why?
- Back to your quarters.
You're going to keep doing this, are you?
Pushing me.
Get me to do something
so you can lock me back up.
Back
to your
quarters.
You're talking tough, you're armed,
you got your men here covering you.
That's true.
Dismissed.
You were saying?
You okay?
Just let me know
and we'll get you whatever you need.
Colonel's just doing this as a precaution.
What do they think is happening to me?
They don't know yet.
I feel like I'm slipping away,
bit by bit.
No.
No, no. We're going to figure this out.
We're going to fix it. I promise.
You can't sleep?
I look at you, and
I know it's you, but still,
I miss
your face,
your voice.
This is hard.
Probably worse on you than it is for me.
This situation,
it's so easy to lose hope.
I've seen it in others.
But what keeps me sane
are these few moments we're together.
Being able to come home and see you and...
And hold you.
Even if it's just for a day or a minute,
it's... It's what's keeping me going.
- I'll be okay.
- I know.
- I'll be okay. I'll be okay.
It's coming up now.
There.
- And she just sits there the whole time?
- Yes.
In her earlier one, she wrote in the diary.
But mostly she just sits or lies still,
staring at the walls.
I still can't detect
any physical changes in her.
Without proper equipment,
I don't really know what else I can do.
Colonel, I know you're just doing this
to keep her away from others,
but quarantine is not a long-term solution.
I know.
- Nurse?
- Wait, no.
Please, just listen, and then I'll leave.
I promise.
Whether you believe me or not,
the fact is, I'm worried.
Eli's worried.
I can't leave you here like this.
He was all that I had.
He's why I got up in the morning.
Never realized it fully until he was gone.
Just tell me,
will I ever see him again?
I don't know.
I can't leave her like this.
I can't go back to that ship.
- If I leave her, she's going...
Eli. Eli, listen to me.
Whatever happens,
you will get through this.
Maybe you could talk to her.
Someone else from the Stargate program.
Maybe then she'll believe me.
I've got a better idea.
I'll call you right back.
I know it's
beyond her clearance.
You're just going to have
to make an exception.
He unlocked the ninth chevron.
He's quite possibly
the most important person on that crew.
We need him to be emotionally healthy,
focused.
You know what, I'm not asking you.
I'm telling you, make this happen.
Mrs. Wallace, welcome
to the Destiny.
Hi, Mom.
Yeah. I'm real.
Eli.
Come here.
I want to show you something.
The other side of the universe, Mom.
Pretty cool, isn't it?
Yeah.
I know.
I was speechless at first, too,
if you can believe that.
It's an amazing ship.
We're still trying to figure it out.
See if there's some way
we can get back home.
I'll never stop trying. I promise.
We're going to be okay, Mom,
you and me.
I'm so proud of you.
Yeah, blew her mind, didn't it?
Oh, yeah.
She's leaving the hospital tomorrow.
Thanks for letting her come here.
And don't worry,
she knows it's a one-time thing.
She won't be asking to come by every week.
Anyway, I owe you one.
You owe Wray.
She's the one who made it happen.
Colonel
Young, come in.
Yeah, go ahead.
I think I have a solution
to Chloe's condition.
Well, let's hear it.
The neural interface.
The chair?
I believe it can cure her.
Look, it's relatively simple.
From what I've learned so far,
I believe the chair will not allow
any non-human to interface with it.
There are safeguards built in
that would destroy
any alien life form that tries to use it.
So the chair kills off
any potential alien matter inside her,
- while leaving her human side unaffected.
Exactly.
You "believe," meaning you're not sure?
- Well, no, I can't be absolutely certain...
- It's too dangerous.
Look, I've made improvements
to the program I developed
when I used the chair.
They should prevent her from being harmed.
I'm now able to sever the connection
externally, at any time.
She shouldn't have to sit in it very long,
a few seconds at most.
- If you can't be 100% sure, I don't...
- It's the best option anyone's come up with.
The only option.
Colonel, you can't force her to do this.
Well, then, I'll ask her.
Are you sure you're okay with this?
Yes, I'm fine.
It's all right. The chair won't activate
till I input the proper command.
- We're ready.
- Okay.
Go ahead.
She's breathing and her pulse is steady.
- Did it work?
I believe so.
But we'll soon find out, won't we?
- Hey.
I just wanted to thank you for pulling
the strings to let my mom come here.
I know it's something that
a lot of people here would want.
Does she believe you now?
Yeah.
Yeah, she does. They're discharging her
from the hospital today.
- Oh.
- Anyway,
it was great having you there to talk to.
Someone who gets
what we're going through.
We'll keep an eye on her, 24/7.
You okay?
- Yeah.
Can I get you anything?
No. I'm good.
Just want to lie down for a little bit.
I'm fine, Matt.
- Mrs. Wallace?
- Yes.
I'm Sharon Walker.
- Your son Eli suggested...
- Oh, yes.
Hello.
We need to talk.
I'm not cured, am I?
No.
Do you really think
she can help you?
I do, yes.
If she values her freedom,
she'll play along without telling anyone.
I need her to be this way.
For now, anyway.
But can you trust her?
English - US - SDH