Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
RUSH: This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
YOUNG: We are going to survive.
We are going to make it home.
I'm telling you,
the ship came here for a reason!
RUSH: This ship is powered
by the stars themselves.
WRAY: He and Young are
bumping heads, yes.
Not sure which camp is the better choice.
YOUNG: We just pretend
nothing happened?
We need to be ready
for the next encounter.
For the sake of the crew.
I want to see the alien ship.
ELI: Were you just trying to distract me?
So that I wouldn't notice
what Rush was doing?
Look, I knew it was coming,
but I didn't know when.
Navigation, propulsion, and many
others have been locked out entirely
by a master code,
which we have had no luck in breaking.
YOUNG: An Ancient device like this
is pretty much a death sentence.
I'm not stopping you, Rush.
Go, sit, be my guest.
Have you seen my glasses?
Bread box.
- You're up early.
- Am I?
- I thought you'd sleep in.
- I've got things to do.
- 4:00?
- What?
Dr. Browning.
Oh, yeah, that's today, right.
Listen, I won't be able to make it today.
- Nicholas...
- Nothing to worry about.
Okay, who can tell me the significance
of Shor's algorithm?
BOY: It's a quantum algorithm
used for integer factorization.
It's important because it can,
in theory, be used to
"break" the widely used public-key
cryptography scheme known as RSA.
RSA is based on the assumption
that factoring large numbers
is computationally infeasible.
This assumption is valid
for classical computers.
No classical algorithm is known
that can factor in polynomial time.
Professor Rush?
Yeah. Very good.
CONSTANCE: Nicholas!
Nicholas? What are you doing here?
I'm sorry, Constance, not now.
I thought you were taking Gloria
to the oncologist today.
She wanted to go by herself.
That doesn't sound like her.
Are you sure she really meant it?
Oh, yes, quite sure.
Nick, what's wrong with you?
I thought you'd be worried sick.
I am. Very concerned.
Yes?
It's back.
I had a feeling.
You did? You never said so.
No.
I can't go through this again. I can't.
Nick? Nick, are you there?
Yes, yes.
Are you coming home?
Nick?
Yes, soon, soon.
Professor Rush? Professor Rush.
Hi, I'm Dr. Daniel Jackson.
- So you are.
- I'm sorry to accost you here.
I dropped by your office, they told me
you hadn't come in for the day.
Do you know
I really don't have time for this?
Actually, I think you're going to
want to hear what I have to say.
Is there some place
more private we could talk?
You're going to tell me
about the stargate program.
Your current dilemma. How to unlock
the stargate's ninth and final chevron.
Specifically, how much energy
will be required.
How do you know that?
Those details are highly classified.
The project hasn't even been named yet,
has it? How about "Icarus"?
I know because it's already happened
and you're just a figment
of my imagination.
Reliving all of this is just a necessary evil,
an unfortunate side effect
to a process I can't control.
And it keeps getting in the bloody way
of what I need to do.
You, the University, the clouds in the sky,
all just a dream, a distant memory,
and one I'd really rather went away.
YOUNG: What the hell's going on?
His pulse is strong.
BP's elevated, but not dramatically.
He didn't want to involve anyone else.
I am in command of this ship,
and that means
you don't do anything without
involving me. Do you understand?
What is all this?
We modified the interface.
We were hoping it would allow us
to use the chair
without causing damage to the subject...
And?
Rush is the first subject.
- Let's wake him up.
- I can't.
Severing the connection externally
could be very dangerous.
He has to do it himself.
Look, with or without me,
Rush still would've done it.
JOHANSEN:
Even after what happened to Franklin?
BRODY: This is the only way
to unlock control of the ship.
The code has to be
in the databank somewhere.
YOUNG: Let's forget
about Rush for a second.
If he wants to kill himself, so be it.
How do you know
this modification you've made
is not going to backfire,
put the whole ship in jeopardy?
- I don't.
- How does this new interface work?
We created a buffer to slow down
the transfer of information.
We also limited the connection to a narrow
range of the subject's subconscious.
That should protect
the vast majority of his brain.
In a worst case, we hope only the
memories that we targeted could be lost.
And if it works,
the data stored in the ship's computer
should be made available to Rush
through a dream.
- A dream?
- A semi-lucid one.
Sort of a stimulated recall
of the memories in question.
- How does he wake up?
- There's a built-in trigger.
It should appear to him
as a distinctive door.
All he has to do is open it
and walk through.
He seems stable for now.
Okay, let's say this is working.
Do you have any feedback?
Do you know what Rush is
actually doing in there?
- No.
- Anything goes wrong, I'm pulling the plug.
Get on a plane. Go.
- I don't want to go alone.
- CONSTANCE: I'll go with you.
Thank you.
The truth is, as much as I'd like to, I...
I don't think I have the strength.
Nicholas?
My God, Nick...
Don't worry.
I haven't lost my mind, not yet, anyway,
but as you can see, I am rather busy.
Ignoring it isn't helping anyone.
Burying yourself in work this way...
- She needs you.
- You know, thank you for your concern,
but, you know, I really cannot deal
with any distractions at the moment...
Is that what your dying wife is to you,
a distraction?
No, no, no, of course not.
She wants to go home one last time.
You should take her.
Constance.
I know you mean well, I really do.
But I can't go anywhere, not now.
Hey.
Are we okay?
Sure. Why not?
You chose to sit here by yourself
instead of with me.
You looked busy.
I need to know that
we're going to be okay.
I know you think that I betrayed you,
and I'm sorry.
I never meant to hurt you.
It will never happen again.
Your friendship means too much to me.
Never a dull moment.
Shall we see where we are now?
- What do we got?
- Take a look.
CHLOE: Are those buildings?
ELI: Were.
They look like ruins.
It's the first sign of civilization
on a planet out here.
- Human?
- No signs of any life.
We should go check it out.
Six hours on the clock.
- Why don't you guys gear up?
- Yeah.
- I'd like to go.
- Me, too.
Chloe has been studying
all of Dr. Jackson's work.
- Really?
- You have?
- I have.
- Say something archeological.
- Stratification.
- That's good.
- Thank you.
- Plus,
didn't you say you took Ancient History?
- I did.
- At Harvard.
Well, I don't see how that helps us
billions of light years from Earth,
- but I get it.
- I'm pretty sure we've established
that this ship is no safer than any planet.
Kidnapped by aliens, right here.
I don't have a problem with
either of you going. I never said I did.
Just be careful.
Yes, sir.
Every code that's ever been cracked,
every cipher
in the last two millennia has been based
on those that came before them.
This code, however, is so old
there may be no known predecessor.
You're talking about a proto-encryption?
Exactly. Right.
Well, how do we attack it
with no basis, then?
None of you?
Nothing? None of you see
any pattern in this?
So, what good are you lot, then?
Why are you here?
There are symbols up there
I've never even seen before.
Yes, you have! Yes, you have,
because I have, and you are all me!
Get out! All of you just get out!
It's not their fault.
Yeah, I know.
I'm the one who can't solve it.
Despite the fact it's right in front of me.
Have you given any thought
to what we talked about?
Oh, yeah.
- I'm going to fail at that, too.
- I'm sorry?
Solving the issues of dialing
the ninth chevron.
I'll devote two and a half years
of my life to that.
Meanwhile, my wife is going
to spend her dying days alone
while I'm off, out,
trying to solve that little problem.
And then some kid, some big child
with no meaningful education is
going to jump in at the last moment
and solve it, just like that.
No sense of ambition.
He spends most of his time
playing ridiculous games,
yet he's the genius I'll never be.
He's the one who should be here now,
seeing what I'm seeing.
Look, obviously
you're not yourself right now.
I do understand
what it is you're going through.
Yeah, I know.
I lost my wife and there was nothing
I could do to save her.
It's a terrible, helpless feeling.
Yeah, my wife's not the answer.
Data does come quicker when I'm with her,
but quicker's not going to help me
if I can't interpret it.
There's patterns I'm just not seeing.
I'm just saying if you need time,
take it, be with her.
That's more important right now.
That's more important than anything.
Yeah, thanks, you've been really helpful.
Your nose is bleeding.
Wow. The Kino really couldn't
do this place justice.
- It's pretty incredible.
- Awesome.
Yeah, it doesn't look like anybody's
been here for a long, long time.
Well, we have about six hours
to figure out what happened.
Let's look around.
YOUNG: Progress?
His nose was bleeding. It's stopped now.
What does that mean?
I don't know exactly,
but it can't be good for him,
the way this thing messes with the brain.
His heart rate and BP
have been fluctuating.
You said he was stable.
I said, "For the moment."
That was over an hour ago.
No way at all to tell
if he's having any success?
No, all I'm able to monitor is the rate
the data's flowing into his mind,
and that's been fluctuating as well.
What are the odds that
yanking him out of there will kill him?
I wouldn't even hazard a guess.
I've spent most of the last 20 years
watching what I ate,
denying myself the things I most loved,
and now,
I could eat anything I want,
and nothing seems appealing.
Yeah.
Why are you here, Nick?
Because this is what happened.
You have work to do. Go and do it.
I am doing it.
It doesn't seem to matter where I am.
You have the chance
to change so many things.
The one thing you can't change
is what's happening to me.
Don't let that hold you back.
When the time comes,
I know you'll be there.
Okay, every time I turn, I see another wall.
So what do you think that means?
What do you got, buddy?
Well, it's pretty cool. Looks like
a network of underground tunnels.
- We should check it out.
- Why?
Don't you want to know
who once lived here?
How does that help us?
Hey, so far Destiny has stopped on planets
that had something on them
that we needed.
I'm not saying it's always
going to be the case, but...
Did you see anything on the Kino?
No, but we...
What could possibly be down there
that we would need?
I don't know.
How about a power source
capable of dialing back to Earth?
- Come on...
- You never know.
These people don't look like
they were that advanced.
Actually, many advanced alien civilizations
found in the Milky Way
and Pegasus Galaxies lived in
what appeared to be
primitive stone architecture that concealed
extremely powerful technology.
I admit that was a big nerd moment,
but it's true, isn't it?
All right, you got the Kino footage.
Let's go.
Yeah, that's the thing.
We don't have the Kino footage.
What do you mean?
- It's a bit of a maze down there...
- You lost it?
No, I took a wrong turn
trying to steer it out.
I just need to take a look
and get my bearings.
The footage could be important.
Mmm. Just... Okay, okay.
All right, I'm going to stay up here
and cover your backs.
What, are you scared?
That was a joke.
I'm sorry, I must have mistakenly thought
we were on that level now.
You know, friends who can kid
each other like that?
- Please don't kill me?
- Come on, Sergeant,
you can take up the rear. We won't go far.
GREER: Yes, sir.
What's his problem?
I didn't think anything scared him.
He's a little claustrophobic.
- I need to sit down.
- Okay.
PRIEST: God is our refuge and strength,
a very present help in trouble.
Therefore we shall not fear
though the earth be removed,
though the mountains be carried
into the midst of the sea,
though its waters roar and be troubled,
though the mountains shake
at the swelling thereof.
There is a river,
the streams whereof make glad
the city of God,
the holy habitation of the most high...
- I want you to practice, okay?
- Okay.
God is in the midst of her.
She will not be moved.
God will help her
when the morning dawns.
- GIRL: Thank you.
- Mrs. Rush, thank you.
- What was that?
- Probably wind.
Anyone else think we've seen enough?
Weren't you the one
hoping for dead bodies?
Some evidence of
human skeletal remains, actually,
and there don't seem to be any.
Well. Oh, God, get it off!
Get it off! Get off!
Okay, that's it. I am out of here! God...
SCOTT: Good idea. Let's go.
GREER: Stop.
Why?
- Don't move.
- Oh, my God, what? What? What is it?
Run.
I think you got it.
Lieutenant Scott, this is Colonel Young,
do you read?
Lieutenant Scott, Sergeant Greer, come in.
This is Scott, sir.
I'm glad to hear your voice, sir.
We are in a bit of a pickle down here.
What's that?
We are trapped in an underground tunnel.
We were exploring the ruins.
Sergeant Greer was forced to fire
his weapon. The tunnel collapsed on us.
No one is hurt.
Eli and Chloe are looking
for another way out,
but if they can't find one,
we're going to need help
getting out of here, sir.
Why was Sergeant Greer
forced to use his weapon?
There was a spider, sir.
It was approaching Chloe.
A spider?
It was a sizable spider, sir.
I'll send a team. Young out.
Less than two hours
before we jump into FTL.
This is my fault.
We shouldn't have come down here.
So, the good news is,
we haven't run into any more spiders.
Did you find the Kino?
No, unfortunately,
these tunnels seem to go on forever.
We haven't found any other sort of exit
or access to ground level.
We heard wind howling.
No, no, that's what you said it was.
Me, I'm already having trouble breathing.
- No, there's air down here.
- ELI: My heart rate is very high.
Slightly dizzy. Whoa...
All right, calm down. There's got to be
more than one way in and out of here.
I take it the digging is not going well.
We got C-4.
That's not going to do anything
but make this worse.
Colonel Young just radioed through
the gate. They're sending a rescue team.
Yeah. And what are they going to do?
Lieutenant Scott, it's Lieutenant James,
do you read?
James, we hear you. Where are you?
We just found the tunnel entrance.
Is everyone okay down there?
Yeah, we're fine. Look, how bad is it?
I'm not going to lie to you.
It does not look good.
But we're going to get you out of there.
Okay, let's get to work!
Been to ancient worlds
I've scoured the whole universe
Caught the first train home
To be at her side
No matter where I roam
I will return to my English rose
For no bonds can ever keep me from she
Dr. Rush? I'm sorry.
I rang the bell several times.
The door was open.
Yes.
Your nose is bleeding again.
I've got some great news.
Our source inside the Lucian Alliance
has come through.
We've got the location of a planet that
just might suit our power requirements.
Well, that's terrific.
I thought you'd be more excited.
I mean, it's going to take some doing.
There's a mining outpost
being run by a small...
Dr. Jackson, do you understand anything
on that board?
No, not really. Why? Should I?
No. I don't either.
I didn't expect it to just present itself.
I mean, why should it?
It's a code. It's meant to be hidden.
A code for what?
Destiny.
This is all information
stored in her memory banks.
At least, I suspect, a small fraction of it.
All completely meaningless to me
in this form, without context.
And, unfortunately,
I don't think staying here any longer
is going to make it much clearer.
- Are you going somewhere?
- Yup, I'm done.
How's your wife doing?
She's dying.
Today, actually.
I really am sorry.
Yeah, so am I.
Shouldn't you be with her?
You keep saying that.
Yeah, well, it's true, isn't it?
What's the date today?
You say your wife is going to die today,
- but you don't remember what day it is?
- No, please, please, just tell me.
April 6th.
She's taken a turn for the worse.
The doctors say the situation's very grave.
They don't think she's going to make it
through the day. Thank you.
April 6th.
- What does that mean?
- I don't know,
but Gloria didn't die on April 6th.
Well, it's not the ultimate answer
to life, the universe and everything.
That's 42.
Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
Yes, thank you, you've been very helpful.
The address of this house is number 4,
not 46.
Why does it say 46 on the door?
Well, 46 divided by two is 23.
I'm sure you've heard of the 23 enigma.
Yeah, it refers to some ridiculous notion
that everything and anything is connected
to the number 23.
Most rational people acknowledge
the enigma is merely evidence
of the mind's power to perceive truth
in almost anything.
Yeah, if you look for it,
you're going to find it.
So, what is this?
Is this my mind playing tricks?
Am I seeing something that's not there?
Convincing myself this is somehow
significant? Significant...
JACKSON: Dr. Rush?
Lieutenant James, this is Colonel Young,
come in.
I wish I had better news for you, sir.
We're doing the best we can,
but things are pretty slow-moving.
YOUNG: You're running out of time.
JAMES: Yes, sir, we know.
Okay, can I panic now?
We've got less than half an hour.
We're not going to make it.
Seriously, what are we going to do?
Sir, he just suffered
some sort of cardiac event.
He seems somewhat stabilized, but I don't
know how much more of this he can take.
Leaving him in there is going to kill him?
I think so, sir. It's just a matter of time.
And you said pulling him out
could kill him, too.
I know I advised against it, but maybe
it's better to opt for risk over certainty.
Unfortunately, things are not going well
on the planet.
Looks like we're not going to have
enough time to dig them out.
However, if Rush can find the master code,
we may be able to stall
Destiny's jump into FTL.
We risk sacrificing Rush.
According to you, he's choosing to stay
connected to that chair.
He may not be aware of the danger
that he's in.
If we jump to FTL, Eli, Scott, Greer,
and Chloe are going to be left behind,
so right now,
looks like their best chance is Rush.
Hey.
We couldn't find any other access.
Maybe it's time we made one.
JAMES:
Lieutenant, we're running out of time.
Yeah, we know.
We're going to use C-4 to try
and blow a hole in the top of the tunnel.
How far back do you estimate you are
from the collapsed opening?
Not far. About 10 meters.
Move as far back as you can,
and let me know when you're clear.
Copy that. Let's go, guys.
- Good?
- We'll see.
- We're ready up here.
- Hopefully, we're clear down here.
Fire in the hole!
JAMES: Lieutenant, do you read?
Yeah, we're still here.
Doesn't look like
that had the desired effect.
No, sir. We just made things a lot worse.
- I'm sorry.
- No, it's not your fault, LT.
You did the best you could.
No, get your team back to the ship.
- Sir, we still have time...
- Not much.
That was an order, Lieutenant. Go.
You're not here for me.
I've already been through this.
No, you haven't. Not really.
I was here.
You can't lie to yourself.
You chose this memory because
it's one you'd rather just forget.
What you need is here now.
That's why you're here.
It's not for me.
You just want your answer.
I need an answer.
You're dying.
- I know.
- You'd rather die than fail?
What have you become, Nicholas?
The things you've done,
that's not who you are. It's not you.
I always had it in me
to make the hard decisions.
I have reasons.
- Good reasons.
- To hurt people?
Are you sure?
You tell yourself
my death gave you courage.
In truth, it made you callous.
You're not the man I loved.
He died with you.
I was never your conscience, Nicholas.
You still have one of your own.
You just need to listen to it.
Some people live their whole lives
and never find what we had.
Don't let what happened to me change
you this way. It's nobody's fault.
I know...
I know that.
It's one stupid gene.
Passed on to me by my mother,
incapable of performing its one simple
function, to repair damaged D.N.A..
That's it, isn't it? That's why you're here.
RUSH: Of course.
Go.
I know how much you loved me.
Stop taking it out on everyone else.
I haven't forgotten you, Gloria,
and I never will.
Dr. Rush?
YOUNG: Now, listen to me.
We got five minutes to stop this ship
from jumping into FTL.
- What?
- People's lives are depending on it.
I can't... I can't do that.
I can't do that.
I can't do anything about that.
YOUNG: Lieutenant Scott,
can you hear me?
- Yes, sir.
- We can't stop it.
Understood, sir.
God be with you, Colonel.
All of you.
It's not over, son. Don't give up.
They just jumped.
What are you doing out of the infirmary?
I got work to do, Colonel.
YOUNG: How about solving the access code
that's going to allow us
to turn this ship around?
Well, funnily enough...
I thought you didn't find anything.
RUSH: I didn't say that.
I said I couldn't stop the ship
then and there.
And even though it nearly killed me,
I managed to find a clue which may give us
control of this ship once and for all.
- A clue?
- BRODY: 46.
Well, that seems a little too simple.
It's the number of chromosomes
in human D.N.A.. Genetic code.
This helps us how?
Well, we know in other cases
with their later technologies,
that the Ancients used sensors
that restricted access
by detecting specific genetic markers.
The access code to the Destiny is not
like that. It's definitely numerological.
The problem we've had cracking it
is that we had no basis, nowhere to start.
We were just taking wild shots in the dark.
- And now?
- Now we know where to start.
They used their own genetic code,
likely a specific one.
More evolved than ours, no doubt,
but all we have to do now
is run through the variations.
We're still talking about
billions of possibilities here.
I've written a program which is going
to go through the permutations.
- So how long is this going to take?
- Several days.
- Really?
- Or several years...
You know, I was trying to be
a little bit more optimistic.
That's a little different for you.
Rush, all this, this was worth
risking your life for?
We'll see.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org