I may be on the verge of discovering
the true nature of Destiny's mission.
You've had control of this ship
the whole time!
Why wouldn't you tell anyone?
The Lucian Alliance is planning
an attack on Earth.
I killed Riley.
I suffocated him with my own hands.
You are a good commander.
There is no mission other
than getting these people home.
It was never about going home, it's
about getting us to where we're going.
That is the mission.
Ginn and I figured out
how to dial the ninth chevron back to Earth
while Destiny recharges in a star.
Wait three seconds, then follow me!
The connection was made,
but you were the only one
who made it through to Earth.
You're Matthew Scott.
And you're Ronald Greer.
How do you know our names?
I don't even know
how this is possible.
Their civilization was founded
2,000 years ago by the crew of the Destiny.
What's Novus?
The planet where you
founded our civilization.
But then one day something happened,
and we couldn't connect
to Novus anymore.
Will you take us home?
You see any
movement down there?
Negative.
But millions of people lived here.
Where did they all go?
Colonel?
T. J?
No.
It's Chloe.
Where's... Where's Steven?
I'm right here, Dad.
Sara's on her way.
She'll be here any minute.
I'm sorry.
Ash.
We just did a recon
of the city center.
Place is completely deserted.
Hard to breathe, too,
with all the ash falling.
So much for dropping
them all off down there.
I don't want you hanging around
if it's too dangerous.
Yes, sir, but Yaozu took us to the entrance
to an underground complex.
It's sort of like a giant fallout shelter.
Who knows, there could be people
holed up in there.
I think we should check it out.
- Be careful. Planet's unstable.
- Copy that.
Got a problem, though. Doors are sealed.
Pretty thick, too.
We tried to blast it open with C-4,
even used the shuttle's weapons,
but no luck.
We can use Destiny's main weapon,
blow a hole in it.
Yeah, and destroy the entire complex
in the process.
We'll dial down the power. 60%.
The doors are pretty thick,
and the actual bunker is way underground,
hundreds of feet. I'd say it's worth a shot.
Yeah.
All right, give us the coordinates.
I got a lock.
Lieutenant, we are ready to fire.
Are you clear of the area?
Yes, sir. Fire away.
Lieutenant?
Colonel, we're on-site.
Nice shooting. It worked.
There's still power. That's a good sign.
My father worked down here.
He would sometimes bring me with him.
I remember running through these halls
as a child.
Hello?
What is this room?
The Teneran archive.
The entire history of our people
is stored here.
Let's hope it can tell us
what happened to them.
- What the hell is this?
I don't know!
This isn't Earth!
Something obviously went wrong!
All right, Greer, James, organize teams!
We need to find shelter!
- Where's Telford?
He didn't make it!
- Why? What happened to him?
I don't know!
- You brought a Kino?
I know we weren't supposed to...
Find a planet!
Can you redialDestiny?
It's gone!
All right, everyone, stay calm!
Stay close!
Turn this off!
The first recording stored
in the Teneran archive.
2,000 years ago.
I'm still trying to wrap my mind
around that.
See what else they've got.
Okay, communications are up.
We should be able to talk to Destiny.
Just hit that button.
- This one?
- Yeah.
Colonel, this is Scott, do you read?
Yeah, we read you.
Yeah, we are in one of the archive rooms.
There's a bunch of them, on several levels.
Still no people?
Not a soul.
Well, we have power, though.
The grid draws from a combo
of solar, wind and geothermal energy.
- Is there anything worth salvaging?
Tons!
We found the Testament
people were talking about,
the entire Teneran repository,
thousands of Kino recordings,
historical documents,
a detailed account of when
we first got here from Destiny.
None of which is any good to us right now.
We've got a ship full of people.
We need supplies for life support.
There's also food storage.
Canned goods, survival-type rations.
Good, we'll use the shuttles to start
ferrying supplies to Destiny.
- You should go down, check the place out.
- Okay.
- Keep me posted.
Yes, sir.
Colonel!
People are starting to pass out.
- Atmosphere's way too thin.
- We've got four addresses.
Start dialing.
- Whoa, wait!
What if they're worse than this place?
We can't just walk through blind.
- We'll just send a Kino through first.
- What, there's more than one?
Six, actually. I wasn't the only one
who decided to sneak one through.
Start dialing!
- Long way down, huh?
- Yeah, my ears popped on the way.
I like the muzak, though.
So this is the archive room?
Yeah, the main one. Five others above us.
Above that, living quarters, tech
and other supplies, food storage.
Scott and Greer are already up there
scouting the place.
Where you going?
- To join them.
They don't need any help.
Young's sending down...
Yup.
- Colonel, this is Scott, come in.
Go ahead.
Yeah, this planet looks good.
You can start sending people through.
Copy that.
Well, this is it, our new home,
a planet known only to God.
Hell of a lot of data here.
Yeah, it looks like
they documented everything.
"It is easier to know where you are going
"when you know where you have been."
Eli Wallace.
You know, it's going to take years
to get through all this.
- We'll bring it back to Destiny.
- Yeah.
These drives are built
right into the structure,
so I don't think we're going to be able
to physically move them.
So we configure an uplink, stream the data.
My thoughts exactly.
- Brody.
- Hmm.
- Brody!
- Hmm!
Sorry.
Is it okay if I do this?
Uh... Maybe I should do it.
You are the founding father
of the enemy nation, after all.
Hmm.
Futura.
- That's just stupid.
- Enough with the name.
That's it.
- Some people brought through
clothing items, hairpins, bandannas.
We're going through it all.
Not much.
We just have to make do
until Rush figures out where we are
and brings Destiny back
in range so we can dial.
Seriously?
Adam, Destiny's gone. Destroyed.
We don't know that for certain.
No, we don't,
but we also don't know
if this is present day, either.
We were dialing inside a star.
It could've hit a solar flare.
For all we know, we could've gone back
in time, or forward, days, months, years.
The fact is, we're stuck here now
for God knows how long,
so we need to build shelter,
we need to find food. Let's move.
Rush, come check this out!
2,000 years
on the other side of the universe,
and beef jerky survives.
Hey, there you are!
Eli and the others are working on a way to
upload the archive back up to Destiny.
If we try to go through it all down here,
we'd never leave.
What are you reading?
There are thousands of books in here.
A bunch of school textbooks,
math, science, all written by Eli.
- The college dropout.
- Yeah.
So you've been sitting down here
reading textbooks?
No, I found my diary.
I know, weird.
My first entry when we got to this planet,
"The air is good. Plenty of trees,
fresh water, a lot like Earth.
"Two weeks have gone by,
and we now have a name for our home.
"Novus. It means new.
"We're trying to settle in,
get some decent shelters built.
"I'm still not sleeping well.
"Never thought I'd say this,
"but I miss Destiny."
Look, I already told you
we can't move there.
Why not? It's not far.
It's flat, wide open, plenty of room...
Because it's a flood plain.
First rain, and we're washed out.
We've got good protection here, up slope,
out of the wind.
Plenty of trees to build proper shelter,
homes...
How? We have no tools.
One of the springs on the plain
is seeping ferric hydroxide.
Bog iron deposits.
It should get us
jump-started on basic tool-making,
then we can really speed things up.
I still think it's a good idea
to look for a better...
You know what, it was your good idea
that got us stuck on this planet
in the first place!
What? You agreed with it...
We are here because of your calculations!
Both of you, stop this right now.
We're not doing this again, all right?
The decision is made. We are staying here.
Sir, we're going to have to build a fence.
There's wildlife on this planet.
We just saw
some nasty-looking creatures on our scout.
- Great.
I've got people out on patrol,
but we're going to run out of ammo
real quick.
- Yeah, hence the fence.
Right.
Sounds good. How about we do it. Let's go.
It's amazing.
We came here with hardly anything,
and 2,000 years later...
Our kids done good.
Kind of want to read the rest of it.
See who ended up with...
Under the table!
Uh, guys?
You might want to get moving
on that data transfer.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Whoo. I hate earthquakes.
Yeah? It's my first, actually.
Greer, this is Scott, you okay up there?
Yeah, everybody's all good.
We're sending down additional teams
to help with those supplies.
We need to pick up the pace.
Copy that.
"Six weeks on the planet.
"We've been doing okay,
for the most part.
"Until today."
Garden?
The fruit that Scott and Greer found?
Planting some seeds, see what happens.
T. J!
"Volker's condition is
getting worse.
T.J. doesn't know
what's wrong with him.
"She thinks maybe his
kidneys are failing,
"but without any medical equipment,
she can't be sure.
"And there's nothing she can do
to help him."
"Today we had our first funeral.
"Dr. Dale Volker."
Hey, Lieutenant Scott just radioed.
The shuttle's loaded
and ready to take you back to
Destiny to start the uplink.
A small cut,
but it may need a couple of stitches.
- I'm fine...
- You will be, once I patch you up.
You're not getting enough rest.
Nobody is.
The others follow your lead.
What is that? The stitches, what is it?
Tendons from one of those animals
Greer killed.
The needle could use a little work, though.
Best Brody could make on short notice.
You okay?
Yeah.
With all this construction going on,
people need to be more careful.
Not overdo it, know when to rest.
Yeah, I'll keep that in mind.
Okay, there you go.
- Take it easy and watch for infection.
- Got it.
Son of a...
You okay?
- Yeah, I'm good. I'm good...
Hey, listen.
Nobody blames you.
It is what it is.
We're here,
and we have our whole lives ahead.
Make the most of it.
- That easy, huh?
- No.
But beating yourself up every day
just makes it worse.
The stargate was destroyed
in one of the eruptions,
buried in lava decades ago.
Most of the people left the planet
before then,
but after they lost the gate,
they needed to figure another way out.
Both of the countries realized
they stood a better chance of survival
if they worked together,
so they pooled their resources
and they built ships. Huge, huge ships.
Not capable of FTL,
but big enough to evacuate
the rest of the population.
Where did they go?
They went to one of the planets they had
previously sent an expedition team to.
10 days travel for us on
Destiny in FTL,
but it'll take them a few hundred years
with their ships.
Good to know they got their act together.
Hey, look, we never really talked.
Don't worry about it. I'm okay.
See, this is always the time
I do something to sabotage things.
It's kind of a defense mechanism.
Tough to explain.
It's not tough at all.
Everything you've ever cared about
has been taken from you
so you're trying to make sure
it doesn't happen again.
This is a huge step for you, Matt.
I'm proud of you.
You should be proud of yourself.
Well, still, I'll understand
if you don't wanna come.
Are you kidding? First wedding on Novus?
Camile's gonna make a pie, so...
I wouldn't miss it.
"Today was a
good day on Novus.
"The best day yet."
So, everybody's hooking up.
Matt and Chloe are married.
Now rumor is Varro and James
are getting together.
Figures.
T.J. just had her baby boy,
named him Steven, after her father.
Yeah. Everybody's getting together,
except me
and Brody.
This is Eli.
Is Volker back on the ship yet?
Yeah, I'm here. Are you ready?
All set.
We're starting the transfer now.
Eli, look at this.
The factory where
they built their interstellar ships?
According to this,
there's one ship still in there.
It was still under construction
when they left the planet.
How close to completion?
Is it operational?
I don't know.
- What?
Let's see.
Come on. I'm documenting your progress.
You'll thank me for this later, I promise.
Come on.
- And how far along are you?
- Six months.
Matt's going crazy trying to build them
a house before the baby arrives.
I told him not to worry about it,
but you know Matt.
Sign he's going to
make a great father.
And you a great uncle.
Oh, crap.
I just accessed
the geothermal monitoring data.
It turns out their theory's right.
A black hole has entered this system.
The tidal forces
are ripping this planet apart.
- Is that a fault line?
- Yeah! Running right under the city.
Very active, and very shallow.
The crust is increasingly thin,
like shattering glass.
Magma bubbling up everywhere.
We can't stay here much longer.
The database is immense.
The transfer could take days.
37 hours with my compression algorithm.
Well, let's hope that's enough time.
Good, good, you're doing good.
Where's T. J?
Eli went to get her.
Don't worry, don't worry.
You're doing fine. I love you.
Just don't forget to breathe...
Shut up and leave me alone!
Oh, thank God! Come on...
- Okay, just breathe.
- Yeah, yeah,
- I've been telling her to keep breathing...
- No, you!
Okay.
- Wow, just on time. You're crowning.
- What can I do?
You can get ready to cut the cord.
Okay, Chloe, one last push. Ready?
It's a boy.
I can't believe it.
I'm a daddy.
You have any names picked out?
Dale.
Babies are being born.
Chloe, Park, James.
T.J. and Colonel Young already have
two: a boy and a girl.
It's good, you know, for the future
of our settlement,
but still, sometimes...
- It's a girl.
- Huh.
Mom and baby are fine.
You okay?
Yeah. Just, uh, tired.
Yeah.
Me and Corporal Barnes?
Something worth pursuing?
- Rush?
- Yeah.
- How bad?
Park says 6.2. Pretty strong.
The fault line they discovered
is getting wider.
The city's crumbling into it.
All right, well, be smart.
Don't wait too long
to get the hell out of there.
We won't.
We've got a pretty good eye on it,
and it looks like this bunker
was built to withstand a lot.
I think we're okay.
And?
- And what?
How was it?
- It was fine.
We had a very pleasant dinner.
Of all the dates I've had since we got here,
she's easily the most compatible with me.
- So then what's the problem?
- I don't know.
I mean,
I've already found my soul mate.
I don't need another.
Steven, no, don't eat that!
Don't eat that...
- That was a close call.
- Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah.
Records say there's actually
a ship still in the factory
a few kilometers outside the city.
Doesn't say if it's operational or not,
but if it is,
it'll be capable of holding
the entire group of descendants.
All right. Go ahead and check it out.
- How's the transfer coming?
So far, so good.
Just over 900 exabytes.
Still a drop in the bucket, though.
Perfect. I need you to take
me back to Destiny.
No, I'm flying them over
to check out that ship-building factory.
Yeah, fine, then you can take me back
to the Destiny.
My symptoms are getting worse.
It's affecting my legs.
I'm losing my balance, stumbling.
My speech is also...
I'm slurring words here and there.
I have trouble eating.
I wish I could do
a more accurate diagnosis, but...
It sounds like ALS, Lou
Gehrig's Disease.
Tamara, I just heard.
This disease,
just because the other you got it
when you came to this planet,
it doesn't mean you'll get it.
Yeah, it does.
It's not something that you contract.
I'm carrying it right now.
Is there anything you can do?
Any medicines?
There's no cure.
Coming up on the factory.
T.J.
Colonel, you didn't have
to come down here.
Volker's checking
Destiny's medical database to see...
To see if there's anything,
anything in there at all
on this disease, okay?
The first symptoms presented five years
after we arrived on the planet.
I died a few years after that.
This is Scott.
Has Colonel Young arrived there yet?
Yeah, Scott, I'm here.
Yeah, we just did a pass over the site
where the factory used to be.
It's gone.
The fault line cut right through it.
It's a river of lava now.
We need to leave this planet immediately.
Agreed.
Scott, get everyone back to Destiny,
then get back down here.
We'll start clearing out.
Yeah, but, sir, what about
all those people back on Destiny?
- Nearest planet is 10 days away...
- No, don't worry about it, they'll be fine.
Yeah, we don't have a choice.
We have to...
- We have to get everyone back on board.
- Copy.
About a third of the database
has been transferred.
Still a long way to go.
We're cutting it short.
I want everyone back to the surface
as soon as possible for evac.
But, Colonel, there's still so much
that we can...
Get down. Get down.
- You all right?
Yeah.
All right, get back to the surface.
Wait for Scott's shuttle.
You all right?
I heard the others talking about you.
The disease you carry, we have a cure.
You do?
Our scientists discovered it
over 200 years ago.
Cures for other diseases, as well.
All of them in the archive.
Rush, are you
back on Destiny?
- Yes, I'm here.
- Then why didn't you tell me?
I'm sorry, I wasn't aware
I had to check in with you.
You heard about T. J?
Yeah.
I'm searching the Ancient medical database
for anything on ALS,
and I could really use some help.
I'm sorry, I'm a bit busy at the moment.
- Doing what?
- Something more pressing.
I'll be with you when I'm finished.
Our son, Alan, just broke the news.
His wife, Claire, is pregnant.
Grandparents.
We're going to be grandparents.
- Well, it's that time again.
- The yearly family reunion.
Three kids and five grandkids.
Just drafted a rough outline
of a constitution.
People are responding well to it,
for the most part.
Oh, and we're converting
one of the storage houses
into a schoolroom.
Eli's teaching the kids.
He's actually quite good at it.
- A wonderful teacher.
Hmm. Thanks.
Four sons, three daughters,
15 grandchildren.
I'm tired.
All these kids, laughing and dancing.
Everybody dancing.
Tearing up my lawn. When I was a kid,
we had more respect for people's...
Touched down, sir. Greer and his team
are bringing up the next batch of supplies.
Copy that. Chloe and Wray
are also headed up with Yaozu.
Take Brody and Park with you.
I'll take everyone else on the other shuttle.
Copy that.
Eli, anything?
We had to compress the data
to speed up the transfer.
One huge file.
Which means I can't do a specific search
for ALS until we uncompress
what we've already uploaded,
and I can't do that
until we stop the transfer.
About a third of the database
has already gone through,
so there's a one-in-three chance
it's in there.
The longer we wait, the better the chances.
I say it's worth it to stay and...
"Colonel Young
won re-election.
"Most of us are happy, but some
still want to do things differently.
"Today a group of them announced
they're leaving.
"Whether they stay here on Novus or
gate to another planet, they didn't say."
Power's cut off. Data transfer's
shut down and communications.
A big section of stairs are out
about six levels up.
Scott, this is Young, can you read?
- Yeah, Colonel.
- Everyone make it out?
Yeah, everyone's okay.
They're all aboard. You all right?
Yeah, we're fine, but we're cut off.
No power to the elevators,
and the stairs are out.
We're gonna have to climb up the ladder.
Eli...
Great.
Colonel, this is Scott,
we made it down to Level 14.
Stairs are out below.
We got rope if you need it.
You should be
on your way back to Destiny.
We'll leave when you leave, sir.
There's Eli.
Platform!
Throw down the rope!
We just lost Varro!
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Okay, pull her up.
We got her!
Sending the rope back down.
Okay, pull!
He's alive.
Pull! Now!
Where are the rest?
- We put them on the other shuttle.
- Everyone hang on!
I'm sorry, Chloe.
Sorry for what?
I never got us home.
Got here as quick as we could.
Sara...
I'm here, Dad.
Colonel,
we are home.
For CO2 scrubbing.
- A highly advanced substance.
Much more effective than lime.
This one canister alone will last for years.
And you brought back cases of it?
We'll certainly need it
with all these extra people on board.
Well, it's just 10 days till we drop them off
with the people on the expedition planet.
Yeah.
It burns you up, doesn't it?
What?
We did all right after
leaving Destiny.
We got along just fine
without you.
Broken ribs. Lacerations, bruises.
He's stable for now,
but all we can do is wait and watch.
We've been searching what we were
able to transfer from the archive.
The ALS cure wasn't in there.
Well, what about
Destiny's Ancient database?
Nothing in there yet, either.
It's difficult.
Different names for diseases, procedures.
It's hard to do a quick search.
What about the ships
that they used to evacuate Novus?
They probably took a copy
of the archive with them,
so when we drop people off on the planet...
They won't be there yet.
The ships don't have FTL.
They won't arrive for 200 years,
and finding them
in the middle of empty space...
Yeah.
But, T.J., there's so much else
that did make it in the transfer.
A ton of other medical stuff.
We can learn from it,
from our descendants.
We will figure out a cure.
I know it.
I'd like to thank you all
for coming to this very special occasion,
the dedication of our beautiful new school.
My grandfather spent his life laying down
the foundation for our education system.
It's why this new school bears his name.
As principal, I'll do my best to uphold
his legacy of inquiry and discovery
and to carry it forward
to future generations.
Now, please help me welcome
our guest of honor,
two-term mayor,
the author of our constitution,
and the last surviving member
of the settlers from Destiny,
Camile Wray.
I want to begin
with a few words of greeting.
May all things go according to the wishes
of those that hear it.
When we first arrived here,
we thought we had failed.
We didn't achieve the
mission on Destiny,
but now, looking at all your smiling faces,
at this beautiful new school,
I can't help but feel a
great sense of pride
and success.
Because, as we discovered,
our mission is, and always will be,
the journey itself.