This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
That ship is the best chance
we have of getting home.
Are we done?
We'll never be done.
You shouldn't have left him
on the planet.
You think I don't know that?
Everyone thinks we're safe.
They think that they'll never find us again.
Why did you take
one of our people prisoner?
We're not safe, are we?
They're coming!
- Who's coming?
Lucian Alliance.
They're coming to take Destiny.
There's only one way
this is going to end if we wait.
I'm not
surrendering this ship.
We need to kill them all.
Everyone except the doctors.
And Lieutenant Johansen.
Remember that planet
that we stopped at?
They have my baby.
You have no idea what it's like
to remember things you've done that...
You weren't yourself.
Riley is not going to make it, sir.
You found the keys to controlling
all of Destiny's systems.
And you're not going
to tell anyone, are you?
There's an object out there.
What is it?
We're not sure, but we're
about to find out.
We're headed straight for it.
Do we know what it is?
Not yet.
Brody.
Colonel.
Ready weapons.
I don't think that'll be necessary.
It's a ship.
It looks like Destiny.
It's got to be of Ancient design.
- Colonel, this is Brody.
- Go ahead.
We're not slowing down.
We're on a collision course.
Ready main weapon.
We're going to hit it.
No, no, we're not going to hit it.
We're going to dock with it.
You got any more predictions?
Yeah. I suspect that, very shortly
you'll be assembling a team
to send over there.
How did you know
we were going to dock?
Call it a hunch.
Given the second ship's similarity
in design, our calculated approach,
well, I thought it was
rather obvious, really.
So, what's happening here?
Destiny is exchanging data
with the seed ship.
One of many traveling well ahead
of Destiny,
seeding planets with stargates,
gathering information.
This one obviously experienced
some sort of system failure,
allowing us to catch up with it.
What kind of data?
Difficult to say at the moment.
It may take a while to translate.
Well, then, you'd better get started.
Well, there's plenty of time
for that later.
For now, this is a fantastic opportunity,
and I want to explore it.
No, I'm sure you do, but I need you here.
I need to know what kind of information
we're receiving.
No countdown clock.
Yeah, I figure Destiny's going
to give us as long as it takes.
And how long is that?
Given the amount of data
and the rate of transfer,
I'd guess at least two hours.
Okay.
Brody, Volker, you are on the away team.
You have two hours. Make it quick.
With all due respect to Brody and Volker...
They'll be fine. Call it a hunch.
Camile.
I thought you were being debriefed.
Homeworld Command can wait.
What's going on with this seed ship?
Some sort of data
transfer's been initiated.
In the meantime, Colonel Young
is sending a team over to investigate.
David...
All right,
Colonel, we are good to go.
Stand by.
Heading in.
Okay, we are at the airlock.
Life support is active
over there, so you have a go.
Right.
That ship's older than Destiny
and could be in pretty bad shape.
Proceed with caution, Lieutenant.
Yes, sir.
It's incredible.
Okay, maybe not as incredible
as checking out a seed ship,
but still, pretty damned incredible.
There's no telling what kind of
information we're getting here.
It could be anything,
from Ancient history to details
of the Destiny's mission.
- Where are you going?
- The bathroom. Is that all right?
Hey. T.J. There you are.
Oh, God, I was supposed to meet you
in the infirmary, wasn't I?
About 20 minutes ago.
Sorry.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
You sure?
After everything that's happened to you...
Let's not do this here, okay?
Okay, but look,
you really should talk to someone.
And I'm not saying that it has to be me.
If there's someone else you'd feel
more comfortable confiding in...
It's not that.
Then why aren't you...
Because there's nothing
to talk about, Chloe.
Look, I lost my baby.
And now maybe she's in a better place.
And maybe it's for the best.
You can't mean that.
Let's go to the infirmary
and I'll take a look at your leg wound.
There is no leg wound.
That's what I was coming by to tell you.
It's almost completely healed.
How is that possible?
I don't know.
We'd cover a lot more ground
if we split up.
You heard the colonel.
"Proceed with caution."
We are not splitting up.
Fine. Then let's at least
turn the Kino on search mode.
Yeah, knock yourself out.
A fascinating bit of information.
Of course you know what this means.
We may have a way of getting home.
But you're not going to tell them that,
are you?
Well, I'm sure they'll figure it out
on their own.
And if they don't?
Well, well, well.
What do we have here?
Ship's control center, I'm guessing.
Huh. And I was gonna go with rec room.
Hey, what did the colonel say?
He said, "You've got two hours.
Make it fast."
Colonel, this is Scott.
Go ahead.
We've found what appears to be
the ship's control center.
Brody and Dr. Volker are bringing
systems online for study.
Keep me updated. Where the hell were you?
I stopped by the mess.
Well, I tried radioing you.
Yeah, I know.
Everett, can I talk to you for a second?
Sure.
- You sent a team over?
- Yeah.
Without bothering to run it by me?
Last time I checked, I was
the commanding officer of this ship.
- I'm not disputing that...
- Meaning, I don't have to run
anything by you or anyone else,
for that matter.
Look, I don't have a problem
with sending a team over.
I'd just appreciate being kept in the loop.
Let me help.
I don't need your help.
- Like hell you don't.
- David...
Damn it, Everett...
You've been going this alone
since the incursion,
and it's been taking a toll.
When are you going to realize
that this isn't just about you?
You have a responsibility
to the people on board this ship
and lately, you haven't
been up to the task.
Now you either shape up or step back.
You're tired, I get it. Let me help.
Oh, you're a persistent son of a bitch.
Hey, you saved my life.
I had to kill you to do it.
And I'm willing to do the same for you.
Okay. They've found what looks to be
the ship's control center
and they're bringing systems online.
What's the game plan?
The game plan is just get
as much information as we can
before our time runs out.
Colonel, I hear we've docked
with a seed ship.
That's right.
I'd like to offer my help.
I have some understanding
of Ancient technology...
No, thank you.
- But I can be of some assistance...
- I said no.
I'm not letting you or your people
anywhere near that ship.
You wanted to see me?
I want to know how long
you plan on keeping us locked up?
I didn't really have a plan.
I just thought I'd play it by ear,
see how things go.
We've been cooperative
with your Homeworld Command,
providing them with information
on the Alliance as requested.
You had no choice.
It was either that or get left behind
on some god-forsaken planet.
We took down Dannic
and gave you back control of this ship.
To save your own lives.
Ours weren't the only ones at risk,
and if you remember,
I stepped in and prevented the execution
of all military personnel aboard
Destiny, including you.
I think we were better use to you alive.
But for what it's worth, I thank you.
We can't spend the rest of our days
here on this ship as prisoners.
Should've thought about that
before you attacked us.
The way I see it, it could've gotten
a hell of a lot worse for you.
Colonel, just tell me,
what do we have to do to earn our freedom?
Prove to me that you're not a threat.
And how do we do that?
I don't think you can.
I'm not your enemy anymore.
Neither are my people!
I think you know that.
Told you.
Okay, so making any progress?
Sure.
All right, then maybe Sergeant Greer and I
will take a little look around.
Knock yourselves out.
Hey, am I reading this right?
If you have to ask, my guess would be no.
Seriously. Check out these power readings.
Oh, my God.
Dr. Rush, you'd better check this out.
It was you, wasn't it?
You're the one who told the prisoners
about the seed ship?
Any major developments aboard
Destiny concern them as well.
They had a right to know.
Oh, damn it, Camile, they're prisoners.
They don't have any rights.
Oh, I can't believe what I'm hearing.
They attacked the ship, they threatened us.
And now we have to live with them.
No, we don't.
We already got rid of most of them.
There's only a handful left.
Homeworld Command needs the intel
they're providing,
and in exchange for that information,
they made a deal.
That Homeworld Command
doesn't have to live with, but we do.
Then all the more reason we should be
showing these people some respect.
You know, if you would just
take the time to get to know them,
you'd realize that many of them didn't
have a choice but to join the Alliance.
You know what, I don't care.
And I'm going to be damned if I risk
the health and welfare of people
aboard this ship on marching orders
from the other side of the universe.
And what about the people back home?
Are you willing to risk
their lives instead?
Because that's what's going to happen
if you renege on this deal.
Homeworld Command
has received confirmation
that the Lucian Alliance
is planning an attack on Earth,
and it's quite possible that
these prisoners have information
that could help head off that attack.
Or they could be lying.
Yes, sure, they could be, but are you
really willing to take that chance?
Look, I understand.
These last few days have been hard on you.
Camile, do me a favor.
Just watch what you say to the prisoners.
We're planning a service
for Sergeant Riley later this week.
I thought maybe
you'd want to say a few words.
Of course.
So come on. Chen? Ramirez?
That redheaded civilian contractor
with the... Park.
Park?
Yeah. Remember that hamstring injury
I said I got doing squats?
Yeah.
It wasn't doing squats.
You wanted to see me?
We checked, we re-checked,
and re-re-checked just to be sure...
The seed ship has sizable energy reserves.
How sizable?
With the output of both capacitors in play,
enough to power the gate and get us home.
In order for that to happen,
I have to alter certain conduits
to open up a transfer channel,
but that's not something
I can do from here.
Go.
- What was that?
What?
We just lost the Kino feed.
Ready, Eli.
Eli?
Yeah. Right. Right.
Dr. Rush, perfect timing.
You're going to want to see this.
Okay, back in a flash.
Uh-huh. Wait. No, where are you going?
Looks like there's a malfunctioning
relay station one floor up.
I'm gonna see if I can fix it,
bring up that dead console.
I'll warn you, Lieutenant, I tend to find
surprises particularly underwhelming.
Not this one, you won't. Trust me.
Pretty darn cool, huh?
Yes. Of course.
This is where the stargates
were manufactured
before being transported
to the various planets.
Okay. Is that it?
Yeah, that's it.
Well, now we're done
with this little diversion,
could you escort me to the Control Room?
Didn't take you long,
but there's still more that...
Oh, my God.
I don't... I don't... Please.
What the hell?
If you're not careful,
that cut's going to open back up again.
I can't help it. I like to play rough.
How about you?
I got it. Yeah, I do.
Do you think you could handle me?
No.
I didn't think so.
Lieutenant
Scott, this is Volker.
Go ahead.
You might want to come back
to the Control Room.
You find something interesting?
Well, yeah, actually.
Something interesting found me.
Have a seat.
I'd like to take a look at your wound.
Looks like it's healing nicely.
Too bad.
I was kind of hoping for a manly scar.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry your child couldn't be saved.
It's difficult to lose someone you love.
I know.
My wife, Anthea, three years ago.
She was on her way back from the market,
when she was caught in a rainstorm.
She ended up taking refuge in a shelter.
It collapsed, killing her and six others.
I'm sorry.
She never liked me being in the Alliance.
She thought it was too dangerous.
I risked my life time and again,
survived missions
that should have killed me,
and yet she dies doing something
as mundane as getting caught in the rain.
You felt guilty.
Guilty. Angry. Despondent.
I was miserable,
until I came to an understanding.
And what was that?
That life is loss.
T. J?
Sir?
Grab your med kit
and meet me at the airlock.
You're heading over
to the seed ship.
- Is anyone hurt?
- Not exactly.
According to Scott,
the alien is alive but unresponsive.
How'd it even get on the ship?
No idea.
Okay. I'll do my best.
You sure you don't want me to use
the stones, bring someone else in?
No. Sir, I want to do this.
All right.
I'm going with.
The lieutenant
already has an escort.
I'm tired of sitting on the sidelines.
Put me in, coach.
Okay.
Eli.
Good luck. T.J.
I got it.
Hey.
You sure it's alive?
It's breathing.
At least that's what
we think it's doing.
Lieutenant?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Little help here, Rush?
Me?
You're the only one with any
experience communicating with aliens.
Different aliens.
However, I think a good first step
might be to lower your weapons.
Scott. Scott.
You? Understand?
No?
No.
Does anybody have any food? Anybody?
Yeah. No, I've got a piece of dried fruit
that I was saving for later.
Are you kidding? That stuff's horrible.
It tastes like rambutan.
- Tastes like crap.
- What's rambutan?
It's sort of like a longan.
- Longan?
- Are you...
Just give it here.
Mmm. Good.
What'd I say?
You know, it may be wise to find out
whether or not it came alone.
He's right. We should run a sweep.
You two keep our guest company.
Each of you take a corridor.
Radio check-in, 10 minutes.
Eli, this is Dr.
Rush. Come in.
- Go ahead.
- I'm initiating the transfer.
I need you to isolate the power
and direct it towards the gate.
It's working.
Power from both ships is being
transferred directly to the gate.
Colonel, Lieutenant.
Go ahead, Master Sergeant.
Yeah, it seems that the alien is not alone.
It's got friends,
and plenty of them.
Very shortly, we will be
making an attempt to dial Earth.
If a successful connection is made,
we will need to move quickly.
All crew members are to proceed
to the Gate Room immediately.
Come again?
Greer has discovered
several more pods, all empty,
suggesting there are more
of these things on board.
Well, how many more?
About a dozen.
Rush figures they were a research team
who were dropped off to do
a long-term study of the ship.
Well, let's get our
people out of there
before their ride comes back
to pick them up.
Making our way to the Control Room.
I want Rush and the science team
back on the Destiny now.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
I can't leave just yet.
What is it now, Rush?
I should stay here in case there's any
interruption to the power transfer.
We may only have one shot at this.
Well, what's the situation with the alien?
Docile. Not a threat.
You can't know that for sure.
Colonel, there's really no point
in arguing about this.
I have to stay here to
make sure this works.
All right, fine. I'll send reinforcements.
I would advise against that.
I'm sending them anyway.
Okay, I'll head back once a stable
wormhole has been established.
All right.
Airman Dunning, you're with Rush.
Everyone else fall back.
Go. Bring the alien.
Power buffers are at optimum.
We're good to go.
Commencing dialing sequence.
People, Homeworld Command
is expecting us. Here we go.
Bring the prisoners.
It's working.
The gate's dialing.
Let me know when you
secure the connection.
We're going home.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
Eli? Eli?
The power transfer's been interrupted.
Hang on.
Rush? Rush, what's happening?
I'm not sure, but it appears that
tapping this ship's energy reserves
seems more problematical than we thought.
Uh-oh.
Eli, what the hell was that?
We've got a problem.
The energy transfer's been reversed!
Dr. Rush, did you hear that?
The seed ship has begun drawing power
away from Destiny.
Dr. Rush?
Colonel Young,
we just lost contact with Rush.
Dunning. Dunning, are you there?
David, I need you to go to the Control Room
and find out why Rush isn't responding.
We're already on our way.
T.J., Marsden, and the science team are
headed back to Destiny with the alien.
Have you found any more?
Not yet.
Talk to me, Eli.
The seed ship is still drawing power
away from Destiny.
When the reserves are gone,
there's no getting them back.
Pretty soon, we won't even be
able to make an FTL jump.
- So we can't stop it?
- We're trying, but nothing's working.
What if we disconnect from the seed ship?
Yeah, that would sever the power flow.
Unfortunately,
we have no idea how to do that.
We've got to learn.
We've got to learn fast.
Colonel, this is T.J. We lost the alien.
Copy that.
Check them.
He's still breathing.
David.
We've found Rush and Dunning.
They're unconscious.
It doesn't look like we'll be able to
stop the power transfer,
so our only option is to sever the link
between the two ships.
We need you back here
in order to disconnect.
Negative.
This is our one shot at getting home.
There's got to be a way
to reverse the transfer.
Eli's tried and come up short.
Listen to me, David.
I want nothing more
than to get everyone back home,
but I'm not willing to risk
anyone's life to do it.
Put Eli on.
Go on.
Colonel?
Is there a way to reverse the
transfer from my end?
Eli?
Theoretically, yeah. Yeah, it's possible.
Tell me what to do.
You need to find anything that
resembles a schematic
or an active display,
possibly indicative of the power transfer.
Greer, Scott, get those two back to safety.
Sir, those aliens are probably
responsible for what's happened.
- If they come back here, you wilI...
- Go.
Go!
All right, I got it.
Okay, now,
I'm going to walk you through this.
Forget walking. Let's sprint.
I've got a basic knowledge
of Ancient systems.
Okay, you need to access
the ship's distribution network.
How are we doing for time?
Once we hit red,
we're at the point of no return.
We have less than 15 minutes.
We're locked out.
Wake up.
What the hell?
Forget it. Keep moving.
Eli, I'm done. What's next?
Now you need to open a secondary conduit.
It's not budging.
It's no use. We are cut off
from the Control Room. Fall back.
All right, you guys heard the man.
Let's fall back.
Less than six minutes.
Are we any closer to finding a way
to disconnect from the seed ship?
We need Rush.
Eli.
Lieutenant Scott. Come in.
We need Rush in the Control Room now.
Dr. Rush?
He is gone, sir.
He's gone where?
- I don't know.
- Find him.
Look, there's no way we're going
to figure out how to disconnect in time.
It's all up to Colonel Telford.
Less than four minutes.
David, how's it coming?
Almost there.
Okay. Next?
Okay, now, all you have to do
is override the power relay
and just re-route it back through
the channel you've just created.
Three minutes.
Almost there.
- What was that?
No idea.
- Eli?
- We just disconnected from the seed ship.
Wait a minute. I thought you said...
I didn't.
It wasn't me.
Well, then, how?
How?
I had no choice.
In order to save the crew?
Or did you do it to save your dream?
Which was it, Nicholas?
David, we just disconnected
from the seed ship
and we're about to jump into FTL.
I'm sorry.
Can't blame me for trying, right?
Yeah. Yeah.
Take care of those people.
And Everett,
take care of yourself.
Everett?
Destiny, are you there?
I understand that you made
saving me a priority after I was shot.
You didn't have to.
Of course I did.
Anyways, thank you.
In the dark it feels so real
And all this time we've
been sleeping on it
And who we are
And what we're going through
All this time spent saving for it
Come so far
Come so far, yeah
So just let me know
when we get there
If we get there
Let me know when we get there
English - US - SDH