Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
All right, get out of the way.
Get out of the way!
大丈夫、よけて。
よけて！
Come here! Come here!
こっちへ！こっちへ！
Move, move!
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
どいて、どいて！
こっちへ、こっちへ！
This is Scott. Slow down the evac!
We are coming in too hot!
こちらスコット、もっとゆっくり！
混乱してる！
Colonel, come in!
大佐、応答を！
MAN 1: Move it back!
MAN 2: Oh, my God, where are we?
男  1 : もどって!
男  2 : オーマイガッ！どこ？
WOMAN 1: What is this place?
女1 : ここはどこ？
SCOTT: Move away from the gate!
スコット：ゲートから離れて！
- Where are we?
- MAN 3: Where is this?
-どこ？
-男3: ここはどこ？
Why didn't we come through to Earth?
地球につながってたんじゃないの？
There's no time to explain. Off to the side!
説明している時間はない。端へ！
WOMAN 2: What's going on?
女性2:どういうこと？
SCOTT: All right.
Come on, come on, come on.
スコット:大丈夫
こっち、こっちへ。
This is Scott. Come in!
こちらスコット。応答を！
Colonel, come in!
大佐、応答を！
- I need a medic!
- Over here!
-医療班！
-こっちよ！
JOHANSEN: Can you move your fingers?
VOLKER: No. I think my arm's broken.
ヨハンセン:指を動かせる？
ヴォルカー:いや、折れてると思う。
Okay, just hold your arm there
and we'll put it in a sling, okay?
じゃあ、固定するわ、OK？
Keep calm. Keep coming.
落ち着いて、続いて。
Clear this area.
There could still be more incoming.
ここは安全だ。
たぶん、まだくるぞ。
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
-大丈夫ですか？
-あぁ。
We've got to move. Move!
-移動して、移動！
Where the hell are we?
どこなんだ？
- Greer? Where's Colonel Young?
- He was right behind me.
- グリアー？大佐はどこだ？
- 自分の真後ろにいました。
- Move. Move. Move.
- SCOTT: Quiet!
- 移動して、移動。
- スコット：静かに！
- GREER: Stay calm!
- Move. Excuse me.
- グリアー：冷静に！
- ちょっと、失礼！！
GREER: Keep it down!
グリアー：静かに！
Move. Move. Move. Move. Move.
ちょっと、移動する。通して。
Colonel? Colonel?
大佐？大佐？
Don't move.
動かすな。
Where are... Where are we?
われわれ…、われわれはどこに？
I don't know, sir. Are you...
大佐、わかりません…
You're in charge, okay?
君が指揮をとれ、いいか？
You're...
あなたは…
Sir?
大佐？
- T.J.!
- JOHANSEN: I'm coming!
- T.J.！
- ヨハンセン：いきます！
GREER: Move back, people!
Coming through!
グリアー：下がって！
通るよ！
JOHANSEN: Let's go! Move, move, move!
GREER: Get back, people.
ヨハンセン：いこう！
グリアー：みな、下がれ！
- Is he okay?
- I don't know.
彼は大丈夫か？
わからないわ。
WRAY: Get back!
レイ：下がれ！
Wallace! What is this place?
ウォレス！ここはどこだ？
- Look, I just did what Rush told me...
- Where is he?
- ちょうどラッシュに同じことを聞こうと…
- 彼はどこだ？
I don't know. He went through ahead of me.
わからない。僕の前にゲートを抜けたけど。
Rush! Rush! Eli, help me find him.
ラッシュ！ラッシュ！イーライ、探すのを手伝ってくれ。
What, I...
あぁ。
MAN 5: What's that?
男５：なんだ？
What in the hell was that?
なんだ？
I don't know. Look,
わからない。
Sergeant, I need you
to get these people settled.
軍曹、みなを落ち着かせるのにきみの助けが必要だ。
And you find out who and what we've got.
Nobody leaves this room.
それから、装備と人員を確認しろ。
だれも部屋から出すな。
Yes, sir.
イエス、サー。
Eli! Now!
イーライ！
ELI: The core of the planet
is the power source.
イーライ：動力源は星のコアだ。
You have to channel it into the weapon
to destroy the enemy ship.
敵を撃破するため、兵器にパワーを与える必要がある。
- MAN: Can't do it, dude.
- Uh, doing it.
- 男：できないよ。
- いや、やるんだ。
It's one of those programmer's jokes,
a problem that can't be solved.
イースターエッグのひとつさ、
解けないよ。
- Already solved it.
- No, you didn't.
- 既に解いた。
- いや、解けてない。
Just shut up! Watch this.
だまれ！みてろ。
- What the hell!
- What happened?
- いったいどうなってる！
- なにが起こった？
Nothing happened.
I'm back at the beginning of the level.
何も。
最初のレベルに戻った。
- You're so full of yourself.
- No. No, no, no. It worked.
- うぬぼれすぎ。
- いや、いやいや、やったのに。
- The firing code locked in.
- Whatever.
発射コードはロックされたんだ。
なんとでもいえるさ。
That was extremely unsatisfying.
納得いかないな。
Eli Wallace?
イーライ ウォレス？
Actually, Eli's not here right now.
実は、イーライは今ここにはいない。
Okay, okay. Whatever you guys think
that I did, I swear you got the wrong guy.
OK。OK。僕がそうだと思ってるんだろ。違うと誓うよ。
Do I look like someone
who'd be standing here
ここに突っ立てる私がどう見える？
if I didn't already know
everything there is to know about you?
君についてのすべてをしらないとでも？
- Yeah, not really.
- Right.
わかった。ちがうよ。
よし。
ELI: Who are you?
イーライ：だれ？
Dr. Nicholas Rush. May we come in?
ニコラス ラッシュ博士だ。入っても？
Why?
なんで？
You just spent a great deal of time recently
かなり時間かかるからさ。
playing an online fantasy game
called Prometheus.
プロメテウスというオンライン
ファンタジーゲームをやってるね？
Big Brother's got nothing better to do?
やってるけどなにか問題でも？
Last night you solved
the Dakara weapons puzzle.
昨夜、君はダカラ兵器のパズルを解いたね。
Yeah, a month of my life went into that.
あぁ、人生の一ヶ月をかけた
You know what happens
when you solve that thing? Nothing.
なにがおこったか知ってるかい？なにもさ。
We're here. That happened.
われわれがここにいる。おこったじゃないか。
To complete that particular puzzle,
君は、あの特殊なパズルを
you had to solve
a millennia-old mathematical proof,
完成させるためにエイリアンの言語で書かれた
written in another language.
一万年前の数学的証明を解いたんだ。
For that, you've won something of a prize.
それで、君はちょっとした賞を獲得した。
Well, whatever it is,
I'll take the cash equivalent.
そう、賞金か何かならうけとるけど。
There isn't one.
賞金ではない。
It's a non-disclosure agreement.
機密保持契約書だ。
Non-disclosure?
機密保持だって？
So, you guys really embedded
a top-secret problem into a game,
それで、あんたたちは、誰かが解くことを期待して
hoping someone like me would solve it?
最高機密をゲームに埋め込んだの？
Yup.
あぁ。
So, what do you need me for now?
それで、俺が必要？
I assure you,
it'll be worth your while to sign it.
保証するよ。
サインして間違いはない。
And if I don't?
それで、サインしなかったら？
We'll beam you up to our spaceship.
宇宙船に君を転送する。
Right. I think I want my lawyer
to look it over first.
わかった、まず俺の弁護士に
確認してもらうよ。
And by "lawyer,"
I assume you mean "mother."
弁護士でなく、母親だろう。
So, we'll just agree then
that I will call you.
それじゃ、サインするときは電話するよ。
What the...
なんだ…
Welcome aboard the Hammond, Eli.
ハモンドへようこそ。
Yes, that is planet Earth,
and yes, you are on a spaceship.
あぁ、あれは地球だよ。
宇宙船内にいるんだ。
We need your help, Eli.
君の助けが必要だ、イーライ。
To be honest,
I don't know how long it's going to take.
正直にいって、どのくらい時間がかかるかわからないんだ。
I should call my mom
to tell her where I am.
ママにどこにいるのか電話しなきゃ。
That's probably not going to work up here.
たぶん、ここでは使えない。
Right.
そうか。
You can speak to her on the way.
途中で電話できるよ。
There's a cover story you'll have to follow.
カバーストーリを用意してる。
I'm sorry. On the way to?
ちょっと待って、途中でって？
To another planet,
21 light years from here.
別の惑星へ行く。
21光年先だ。
I can't go.
I have things that...
いけないよ。
いろいろあるし…
We know about your mother's condition.
君のお母さんの状態は知ってる。
You just know everything, don't you?
すべてを知ってるの？
We also know that
you are currently unemployed,
今無職だということも、
and that your mother's
medical coverage is
君の母親に健康上の問題が
an ongoing issue.
あるということもね。
We'll see she gets the best available care
while you're gone.
われわれなら君の母親に過去最高のケアができるよ。
And if I don't sign, what?
You going to erase my memory?
それで、もしサインしなかったら何？
記憶を消すのかい？
Something like that.
それもありえる。
Can I get some pants?
替えのパンツある？
Hello, I'm Dr. Daniel Jackson,
and behind me is a stargate.
やぁ、僕はダニエル・ジャクソン博士。
そして後ろにあるのがスターゲイトだ。
It was originally built millennia ago by
an alien race who we call the Ancients.
元は、エンシェントと呼ばれる1万年前の種族によって作られた。
Over the next few hours,
we'll be touching on some of the things...
数時間かけて、いろいろなものについて説明する。
There are 39 symbols representing
star constellations as seen from Earth...
これらは地球から見える星座を表した39のシンボルだ。
When a connection is made
between two stargates,
スターゲイト間がつながったとき
an unstable energy vortex
emerges from the gate...
不安定なエネルギーの渦がゲイトから出てくる。
Whoa!
わお。
...and settles into the event horizon,
or "puddle, " as we like to call it.
そしてイベントホライズンに落ち着く。
Later, it was discovered
that using an eighth symbol
後に、数十万光年先の別の銀河にダイアルできる
would actually dial another galaxy
in hundreds of thousands of light years
8番目のシンボルを発見した。
via an interstellar wormhole.
銀河間のワームホールをとおして
It is believed an unprecedented amount
of power is required
9番目のシンボルに到達するには前例にない
to reach the near-mythical ninth chevron.
The first six symbols...
ほどのパワーが必要だと考えている。
最初の6つのシンボルだが、
to reach the near-mythical ninth chevron.
The first six symbols...
ほどのパワーが必要だと考えている。
最初の6つのシンボルだが、
Icarus Base was established
on a planet discovered two years ago
2年前に発見したイカルス基地には
to have a uniquely powerful core.
ほかにはない強力なコアがある。
The entire purpose of the project
is to hopefully one day
プロジェクトの目的は
dial the nine chevron address
found in the Ancient database.
エンシェントのデータベースから見つかった
9つのアドレスをダイアルすることだ。
Hi! I'm Dr. Daniel Jackson.
やぁ、僕はダニエル・ジャクソン博士。
Now, you've heard the term
"hyperspace " for years...
いま、君が聞いたハイパースペースとは
- Where are you?
- ELI: It's top secret.
- どこにいるの？
- イーライ:機密なんだ。
- Eli!
- I'm serious, Ma.
- イーライ！
- ほんとだよ、ママ。
I can't say anything more than that.
言えないんだ。
But I don't understand. Why could you not
at least tell me you were leaving?
けどわからないわ。どうして、何もいわずに
家をでたの？
I'm sorry, but did you get the letter from...
ごめんよ、けど、手紙が届いたろ…
Yeah, the Air Force. I got it.
あぁ、空軍からのね。
Are you in a plane now?
You sound like you're in an airplane.
飛行機に乗ってるの？
飛行機に乗ってるような音がするわ。
Uh, no. It's nothing like that.
うん。いや、まぁそんなとこ。
I want you to know that
they're going to look after you.
後の面倒は彼らが見てくれるから。
Well, you didn't have to do this.
そぅ、わかったわ。
This is good.
よかった。
Really. It's the kind of thing
I always dreamed of.
本当に、常に夢見てきたようなことなんだ。
- Hi.
- You mind?
やぁ。
ここいい？
- No, go ahead.
- Thank you.
えぇ、どうぞ。
サンキュー。
First time on a spaceship, too?
あなたも宇宙船は初めて？
Me? I've been on lots of various...
俺？いや、何度目かな。
- Eli Wallace.
- I know.
- イーライ・ウォレスだ。
- 知ってるわ。
- You've heard of me?
- I have.
- 聞いたことあるの？
- ええ。
Wow, that almost never happens.
わお。まじか。
And you are?
それで君は？
Chloe. I work for Alan Armstrong.
クロエ。アラン・アームストロングの秘書よ。
Senator of California?
カリフォルニアの上院議員？
Oh, yeah, yeah. I have heard of California.
あぁそう。カリフォルニアってのは聞いたことある。
My last job was in the burger and fries
field. How'd you line that up?
僕の最後の仕事はバーガーショップでの揚げ物。
きみは？
I was a political science major
at Harvard, so...
わたしはハーバードで政治学を専攻してたわ。
Mmm. I hear it's a good school.
For a while there I was at...
へぇ。いい学校だね。
少しの間、僕は…
MIT. I know.
MITにいた。
Really? What else have
they told you about me?
本当？他に僕についてなにを聞いたの？
- What?
- I've seen this writing before.
- なんだ？
- この文字前にみたよ。
- In the game?
- Yeah.
- ゲームで？
- そう。
Sheesh. We're on a ship?
わお。僕らは船に？
RUSH: The design is clearly Ancient,
in the truest sense of the word.
ラッシュ：これは明らかにエンシェントのデザインだ。
Launched hundreds of thousands
of years ago.
数十万年前のね。
Dr. Rush?
ラッシュ博士？
Faster than light,
yet not through hyperspace.
ハイパースペースの前の超光速航行だ。
- What are you doing?
- Who knows how far it's traveled.
- なにしてる？
- だれがどのくらい旅したかがわかるか。
Dr. Rush, I've got a lot of wounded.
We need to get home.
- ラッシュ博士、大勢の負傷者がいる。
- われわれは家に帰りたいんだ。
JOHANSEN ON RADIO:
Lieutenant Scott, come in.
ヨハンセン(無線)：
スコット中尉、応答を。
Go ahead.
どうぞ！
We've got a problem.
One of the air vents just shut down in here.
問題があります。
ここのひとつの通気坑がいまこわれました。
Copy that.
了解。
Yeah, the air's getting pretty thin
in here, too.
あぁ、ここも空気が薄くなってきている。
- What does that mean?
- That the life support system is failing.
- どういう意味だ？
- 生命維持システムが機能していないんだ。
And we should probably do
something about that.
どうにかしなければならない。
EMILY: Well, it's always just one more year.
エミリー：それで、一年間ずっとそれよ。
It's a command.
命令なんだ。
- Where?
- It's a lot safer than other places I've been.
- どこ？
- 前いたとこよりは安全なところさ。
- You've put your time in, Everett.
- When this tour is over, I promise...
- 時間がかかったわ、エヴァレット。
- この任務が終わったときには、約束する。
You know what?
Never mind. Don't bother.
例のあれ？
心配するないで。邪魔しないで。
You always end up choosing
somewhere other than here.
あなたは結局ここ以外のどこかで選択するのよ。
I am not choosing
my job over you.
俺は、きみより仕事を優先してないよ。
How you can even say...
How you can even say that to me?
それをいうのか…
おれに？
I love you, but I can't wait anymore.
I can't wait anymore.
愛している。けどもう待てない。
もう待てないわ。
Everett? Are you okay?
Sweetheart, baby, look at me.
エヴァレット？大丈夫？
あなた、私をみて。
Colonel? Colonel?
大佐？大佐？
Oh, my God.
オーマイガッ
Can't you do something?
He's having a seizure.
There's nothing I can do.
ON RADIO: Scott, this is Colonel Young.
Come in, please.
Our guests have arrived a few minutes
early, Lieutenant. What's your position?
Come on. Not yet. Not yet.
Lieutenant, drop whatever you're doing
and get your ass up here.
I'm on my way, sir.
Bye.
Holy...
Senator, it is my honor
to welcome you to Icarus Base.
Colonel. This is
my executive assistant, Chloe.
- It's a pleasure to meet you, sir.
- The pleasure's mine.
She's also my daughter.
- You must be the...
- Contest winner, yeah. That is a big gun.
Rail gun. 500 rounds per minute.
This is Lieutenant Scott.
He's been assigned to you, Mr. Wallace.
Shall we go inside?
ELI: Unbelievable.
SCOTT: Yeah, it is.
It's weird how fast you can start
to take something like this for granted.
So, if a stargate can instantly
transport you to another planet,
why did we fly here on a spaceship?
Something to do with how this one's
tied into the planet for power.
Apparently, it's been modified
to only dial out
because incoming wormholes
are too dangerous.
You're the genius.
You can probably tell me better.
All I did was solve a puzzle
in a video game.
Hey, you figured out something Dr. Rush
has been trying to figure out for months,
which, by the way,
a lot of people were glad to see.
RUSH: And, of course,
you know Colonel Telford.
- Ready for this, Colonel?
- You just give the word, sir.
Oh, I gave it quite a while ago, Colonel.
I'm just here to see
how my $1.6 billion is being spent.
Very good. Thank you, everyone.
Dismissed.
As you know, up until now,
we have been unable to channel
the precise amount of power necessary
to unlock the stargate's
ninth and final chevron.
However, thanks to some ingenuity
from young Mr. Wallace here,
that problem has finally been solved.
YOUNG: We've heard that before.
This time we're sure.
That's what I figured out?
I embedded the mathematical problem
we had to solve into the game.
I then engineered your solution
into a practical, workable application.
- What say we get on with it?
- Absolutely. Sergeant Riley.
- RILEY: Chevron one encoded.
- Sir.
We're dialing now?
- A test, to see if we can make a connection.
- RILEY: Chevron one locked.
If we do, we will send an automated
reconnaissance drone through.
We'll see what's on the other side.
RILEY: Chevron two locked.
And then they'll go?
No, first, we close down again,
assess the data we receive,
- and then perhaps send the away team.
- If it works.
RILEY: Chevron four locked.
Until then,
they're just interested observers, like us.
RILEY: Chevron five locked.
Chevron six encoded. Chevron six locked.
Chevron seven encoded.
Chevron seven locked.
Chevron eight encoded.
Chevron eight locked.
Chevron nine encoded.
- Whoa, what's going on?
- I don't know. We never got this far before.
Chevron nine... Chevron nine will not lock.
We matched the power requirements
down to the EMU. It must work.
Power levels in the gate capacitors
are going into the red.
- Shut it down.
- No, wait, wait, wait.
RILEY: We're reading fluctuations
in the output from the core...
Shut it down now.
- It should have worked.
- Well, it didn't.
And drawing power
from the planet's core...
Dangerous? Yes. We're all aware of that...
Regardless of what's been spent
or what's at stake,
my first priority is to ensure
the safety of the people on this base.
Of course. Of course.
Eli, we'd best run through
your equations again.
If you'll excuse me.
You are not seriously putting this on me!
Not my fault.
SCOTT: People, you have to calm down.
Seriously, you have to calm down.
MAN: We got power!
WOMAN: Thank God!
Everybody's attention, please.
All right, please listen.
Hey, listen up!
What is going on?
We are on an Ancient spaceship.
- MAN: What?
- That's all I've got.
Now, what that means is that...
That means you need to use the stargate
to get us all back home.
That is definitely
on the list of things to do, sir,
- but I think right now...
- You can consider that an order.
We are working on it, sir.
Now, I need to speak to the person
responsible for this. Where is Dr. Rush?
- Just shut up for a second, will you!
- How dare you talk to...
- Dad? Dad, please.
- WOMAN: Medic!
- Water? Water? Quickly. Over here.
- Get...
CHLOE: Sit down.
ARMSTRONG: The pills.
Look, I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to explain the situation.
We are on a ship, but we have no idea
where we are in relation to Earth.
Now, with respect, sir,
the reason you might be having
a hard time breathing right now
is because the ship's life-support system
is not functioning properly.
Dr. Rush is working on that right now.
Brody and Park?
- Here!
- Here.
Okay, good, you two are with me.
- But these consoles just came on.
- No, nobody touch anything yet!
Dr. Rush needs your help.
Everybody else, just stay calm,
stay put. Please.
MAN: "Stay put"? Wait, what do
you mean? You're just going like that?
There has to be
a mistake in here somewhere.
Seriously, who uses
a whiteboard anymore?
You have computers, like,
everywhere around here.
The power flow was in the target range.
Why wouldn't the address connect?
Wrong address?
There is only one found
in the Ancient database in Atlantis.
With no other instructions?
No, but that's not the issue.
It has to be your proof.
My proof works.
You know how I know that it does?
Because you said so.
Gentlemen. How's it coming?
- Whoa, whoa! What are you doing?
- Starting from the beginning.
Wait. Save! Save! Save! I can't...
Mr. Wallace, I would like you to join me
for dinner in the officers' mess.
- Thank you, I'm starving.
- We're quite close
to a breakthrough, actually.
I'd like Eli to keep working.
Well, we've been here for six months.
It can wait a few more hours.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
So, Colonel, you really have no idea
where this ninth chevron stargate address
is gonna send you?
No idea at all.
Hmm.
But the Ancients built the stargate
with nine chevrons.
It's got to go somewhere.
YOUNG: We've also known
for some time that the only way
to unlock the ninth chevron
was to solve the power issues.
Well, if anyone's going to solve it,
I think Eli will.
Yes, that's right. It's true. I am Math Boy.
Dr. Rush. Dr. Rush!
ARMSTRONG: I would like
to propose a toast.
Oh, no, that's really not necessary.
- Not to you.
- Oh.
When the proposal for this project
first crossed my desk,
I did not want to approve it.
- Oh, my God.
- It seemed clear to me at the time
that there were enough
terrestrial matters of importance
that needed that kind of money.
Now, being a proud father of
a beautiful young woman is one thing.
Having that young woman exceed every
possible expectation is quite another.
It was my daughter, Chloe, who reminded
me that there is no greater endeavor
than seeking an understanding
of who we are,
and the mysteries of the universe
in which we all exist.
- Not in those exact words.
- It was also her idea
to embed the Ancient proof
in a medium that would give us access
to brilliant young minds
that we would have otherwise overlooked.
And so to all the brave men and women
who have volunteered...
Okay, what was that?
This is Young.
YOUNG: The base is under attack.
All non-combatant personnel
report to your designated areas.
Everyone else to your battle stations.
This is not a drill.
Senator, I need you and your daughter
to go with Lieutenant Scott.
- Eli! You as well.
- Oh, yeah.
WOMAN: Hurry.
SCOTT: Yeah, we're on our way.
GREER: What's going on in here?
The life-support system is on,
but for some reason,
it's not working properly.
I'm attempting to reset it.
He has no idea what he's doing.
- Step away from that thing.
- ELI: That screen says
that what you're doing
is gonna overload it...
- Eli, please!
- Is that what it says or not?
You only think you know what it says
in this screen
because I embedded a rudimentary version
of the Ancient language into the game.
- This is not a game.
- Don't touch it, Rush.
When the oxygen aboard this ship
falls below critical level,
it will become increasingly
difficult to concentrate.
And what you're doing
could blow up the whole ship.
- Are you sure, Eli?
- Back off now or I will shoot!
Lower your weapon, Sergeant!
He already screwed us once.
I'm not going to let him do it again!
I need to get through, people. Stand aside.
Sergeant, we're under attack.
Don't know who, don't know why.
Consider the charges dropped.
Go take your anger out on them.
Yes, sir.
YOUNG ON RADIO: What do we got,
Colonel, Lucian Alliance?
That would be my guess.
They haven't introduced themselves.
They started shooting the minute
they came out of hyperspace.
Our shields are holding,
but we're not the target.
What's heading our way?
A full squadron of gliders
and a troop transport.
We cut them down some,
but the rest will be on your doorstep
in less than three minutes.
- Telford, did you copy?
- Roger that.
If we can get to the transport before they
land their troops, we stand a chance.
RUSH: I am going to press that button.
It's going to fix the life support,
and then you and I, and everyone else,
will be able to breathe and think
much better.
Don't do it.
Okay, look. Sergeant,
I know we are in a tough situation here,
but I am giving you an order.
Lower your weapon.
So?
Well, I suppose
that would have been too simple.
Apparently, that did nothing.
This may take a little more time, T.J.
Hang in there.
Copy.
Does Colonel Young know about this?
He knows.
Two weeks ago you told me that this
was the best experience of your life.
- Something must have happened.
- The scholarship came in.
I guess I've just been too afraid
to admit what I really want.
Wow, you didn't tell me
you had even applied.
There's nothing else going on.
You know I'd tell you.
- Unless you were protecting someone else.
- I'm not.
Like I said, I just hadn't made up my mind.
RILEY: Dr. Rush? I'm reading
a dangerous energy spike in the core.
Eli! Eli! I need your help.
- With what?
- The ninth chevron.
What? We need to get the hell out of here.
Look, it took us two years to find this site.
The properties are unique.
This may be our last chance.
If this bombardment continues,
the radioactive core is going to go critical.
You mean the planet...
It's going to explode?
- Yes.
- Ah! Okay, okay, okay, okay.
- If my math works...
- We can't assume that...
I said "if"! Then if it works,
then it's not a power supply issue,
it's the gate address.
We've known the first eight symbols
for years,
the ninth has to be the point of origin.
So, what if we're not on the planet
you're supposed to be dialing from?
This is where we are.
Okay, what if
we are not supposed to be here?
Icarus Base, Telford.
We can't hold them back.
Let's go! Go!
Sergeant Riley, dial the stargate to Earth!
- SOLDIER: Incoming!
- Come on, come on.
RILEY: Chevron one locked.
ELI: Okay, follow me.
The symbols on the stargate
are constellations as seen from Earth.
- That's what you said...
- Yes, yes.
Okay, so what if Earth is supposed to be
the point of origin?
- RILEY: Chevron two locked.
- The only viable power source was here,
- light years away.
- What if that doesn't matter?
What if it's the only combination
that will work, like a code?
- RILEY: Chevron three locked.
- A code?
- Yeah.
- RILEY: Chevron four encoded.
- Stop the dialing sequence.
- RILEY: I have my orders.
Get out of my way. Get out of the way!
We can't risk dialing Earth.
ARMSTRONG: Come on, let's go.
SCOTT: Go, go, keep moving.
- Dad? Dad? Dad!
- SCOTT: Chloe!
My father! There could still be
people trapped on the other side.
All right, let's go, people.
You need to move it to the Gate Room!
This is Scott. I got about a dozen
or so people cut off from the Gate Room,
southeast corridor.
- Oh, God! Okay. Damn it!
- YOUNG: Oh, my God!
- Is that Dr. Simms?
- Stay with me, okay?
He was helping pull people back
from the surface.
- Simms, can you hear me?
- T.J.
- No!
Hey, Tamara. Hey, Tamara.
Come on, we got to go.
That is impressive.
The power's fluctuating at critical levels.
Colonel, I'm detecting a massive buildup
of energy from the planet.
Recall our fighters. Radio Colonel Telford.
He's got two minutes to get his people
aboard before we jump to hyperspace.
What's everybody doing?
I ordered an evacuation.
He, uh... He didn't dial Earth.
It's the ninth chevron address.
What?
The attack started a chain reaction
in the planet's core.
There's no way of stopping that.
And any blast could easily translate
through an open wormhole.
It's too dangerous to dial Earth.
You could have dialed somewhere else.
Anywhere else.
- RUSH: This could be our only chance.
- Shut it down.
- You can't, it's too late.
- Riley!
- System's not responding, sir.
- I need to get these people out of here.
- We have a way out.
- We don't know what's on the other side!
- Damn it, Rush!
- Can't be worse than here, can it?
Nobody move. Await further instructions.
What's that?
Well, it doesn't look like life support.
RUSH: Yes, I realize that.
Whoa!
- What are we looking at?
- It's a star map.
PARK: That's the Milky Way.
RUSH: I believe it's a visual log
of the ship's journey.
So, this is where we are now?
No. That's where the ship
originally embarked from.
ELI: Earth.
- It's leaving the galaxy.
- RUSH: It did. Long ago.
That was Pegasus.
So, those points are more stars?
No, they're galaxies.
Rush, where the hell are we?
Several billion light years from home.
- Please.
- YOUNG: Scott.
Stand clear.
You could take down the rest of the roof
with that.
Look, we don't have time to argue.
I need you to lead the evacuees
through the gate. You need to go with him.
No! I'm staying here
until I know my father's okay.
Make sure everyone carries as much
of the expedition supplies as they can.
- Why?
- 'Cause you're not going to Earth.
Rush dialed the ninth chevron. Go.
Go!
Once I'm through,
follow one at a time on a three-count.
SOLDIER: Okay, people. Make way.
Come on, let's go. Keep it going.
You good? Okay, let's go.
If you can hear me, stand back!
Okay, get down.
Fire in the hole!
Dad?
GREER: Put your weight on me.
- Put your weight on me.
- YOUNG: Stay calm, everybody.
- I got you.
- CHLOE: Please.
Okay, everybody stay calm! Don't push.
Dad!
Careful, careful.
- YOUNG: You're okay, sir.
- Are you okay?
I'm the last one. I'm all right.
Greer, go. I'm right behind you.
Hammond, this is Young, come in.
Hammond, this is Young. Come in.
GREER: Let's go, let's go, let's go,
come on, people. Let's do it. Let's do it.
SOLDIER: Hurry up!
- Sir!
- Go!
Sir. We've got Colonel Carter. On screen.
General, we barely got away.
The planet was destroyed.
We managed to beam
most of our people off the surface
before jumping to hyperspace.
We also believe that
the enemy forces were destroyed.
Any word on how they gained intel
on our base?
No.
What about casualties?
Twelve. Eighty-plus MIA.
The bunker-shielding technology
prevented us
from beaming out anyone inside.
How many people made it
through the gate to Earth?
None.
None? Our sensors indicated
that the stargate was active
for a full six minutes
before the core went critical.
Well, they didn't come through here.
Then where'd they go?
Okay, listen up!
Everybody who is able, we are going
to search this ship top to bottom.
Teams of three.
- Weapons?
- Twenty-three, including handguns.
- One per group?
- Yeah.
Flashlights, radios, only when necessary.
Once those batteries are dead,
they are dead. Regular check-ins
with Dr. Rush in the control room
every 10 minutes, and keep in mind,
as far as we know,
this bucket is really freaking old,
and there may be areas of damage
where life support is unstable.
And, look, be smart, okay?
Don't touch anything that
looks like it might be dangerous.
How are we supposed to know
what's dangerous?
- Becker, right?
- Yes, sir. I work in the mess.
- I mean, I did.
- Well, don't touch, just look.
You're... You're James, right?
- Yes, Lieutenant.
- You and Riley are with me.
Subtle, man. Subtle.
SCOTT: If it's okay with you, sir, it might be
best, considering your obvious skills,
for you to hang back here and
help keep the rest of these people calm.
Don't patronize me, son.
No, sir.
- Are you all right?
- I'm solid, Lieutenant.
I'm trained for this.
- Look, I didn't mean to...
- Look, not now.
ON RADIO: Rush, this is Scott. Come in.
Rush, this is Scott. Come in.
Hello. This is Eli.
- Where's Rush?
- Bathroom, if he found it.
I'm at what looks like a bulkhead door.
It won't open.
I was hoping
Rush could open it from there.
Should I find him?
No.
- Here, give me a hand.
- What happened to being smart?
This could be the engine room
for all we know.
We got to at least open a few doors.
Do we? Do we really?
ELI: Hang on.
No, keep doing what you're doing.
I think I found where you are.
The door is flashing red.
SCOTT: Can you open it from there?
Red is usually bad, isn't it?
Maybe it means the door is stuck. Just try.
Okay. You should probably step back.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, not good! Not good.
More red...
Close it!
- Close it now!
- I'm trying!
Yeah. Okay. We established
why that hatch was closed.
Yeah. A lot of others are closed
for the same reason.
We're only occupying
a fraction of the ship right now.
It just goes on forever.
But if there are damaged areas of the ship
that aren't sealed,
that could be our problem.
Oh, hey, good timing.
We just found... Hey... Really?
This is Dr. Rush.
Meet me in the Gate Room immediately.
Everyone.
MAN 1: I don't know what's going on.
MAN 2: It's over there.
What's going on?
In this case are
five Ancient communication stones.
They work over vast distances in real time.
- We can talk to the people on Earth.
- Yes.
MAN 1: Great.
MAN 2: All right.
RUSH: You physically take control
of an individual at the other end.
I brought these with us in the event
we ended up somewhere out of range
of normal communication.
So let's use them.
MAN: Yeah.
WOMAN: Yeah.
I already have.
ALL: What? When?
- Are they sending help?
- No.
MAN: Why? Why are they not sending help?
The only means of dialing
this gate from our galaxy
was destroyed in the attack. We're cut off.
I want to use one of those stones now.
- I have spoken with General O'Neill...
- I am a United States senator!
I've explained our situation clearly.
In light of my knowledge and experience,
he has placed me in charge.
He did what?
MAN: How do we know?
I have faith in our ability to repair this ship
and to work together,
but if we're to survive this,
we need leadership
and a clear chain of command.
ELI: We only have a few hours of air left.
- Yeah.
- I want to speak to the General myself.
- Senator, please.
- Give it to him!
WOMAN: Yeah.
SCOTT: Give it to him.
- CHLOE: Dad? Dad!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. T.J.?
Excuse me, excuse me. Okay.
Okay, he's still breathing.
CHLOE: Oh, my God!
JOHANSEN: I saw him taking some pills?
CHLOE: Warfarin, for his heart.
Blood thinners are the last thing he needs
if he's bleeding internally.
- Please do something!
- Look, I told you, I'm just a medic.
Everyone, please, there's no need for us all
to congregate in the one place.
Ms. Johansen, please find
adequate accommodation for the injured,
- and everyone else...
- No, I don't recognize your authority,
- Dr. Rush. As an IOA representative...
- We have found quarters nearby
- much more comfortable. Please go there...
- I think you need to...
...and stay there until you're asked
to do something useful.
Something useful?
We do not want to settle in!
- We want to get back! Right?
- Yeah.
We should be working on getting home.
- WRAY: Exactly.
- I'm not sure if that's even possible.
What? You haven't even tried!
Maybe you should actually do something
instead of standing around,
- talking about being in charge.
- If that's even true.
Everybody! Everyone, calm down!
Now, the fact is
Colonel Young put me in charge,
and I expect all SG personnel
to follow my orders.
As for the rest of you, you get out of line,
we will lock you down.
Now, Dr. Rush is right
about a couple things.
First off, we all have to work together,
and second of all, we don't all have
to stay here, so let's move out.
- Go on, move. It's okay.
- SOLDIER 1: All right. You heard him.
SOLDIER 2: Do as he says, people.
I think we need you,
so I've got your back for now,
but if I were you, I would find some way
to dial that gate back to Earth.
I've got some testing equipment over here.
Looks broken.
- We'll get back to that.
- What about all these Ancient crates?
If it's not ours, don't touch it.
VOLKER: Did no one think
of labeling anything?
Every case has a bar code.
All right, anyone find a bar code reader?
I guess that got left behind
along with the food and water.
- Uh-uh. We got food.
- Yeah, protein bars and this powdered stuff.
Look, everybody.
Seeds? Volker, you've got to be kidding.
PALMER: I got a case of blank paper.
VOLKER: Maybe we should
start a suggestion box.
What are you staring at?
- You were in detention.
- Yeah.
- For good reason.
- GREER: What did you want him to do?
- Leave me there?
- Of course not.
I was just wondering
what to do about it now.
- That's not up to you.
- We'll see.
No, no, no. Don't do it, man.
SCOTT ON RADIO: Greer, I need you
to check for any open bulkhead doors
that lead to damaged parts of the ship.
Rush will direct you.
Copy.
RUSH ON RADIO: There should be
an elevator directly ahead.
Copy that.
- Are you there yet?
- This is Scott. Radio silence, please.
- Hey.
What's going on?
We almost lost you.
You were thrown clear across the room.
- Where are we?
- Sir...
- We're on a ship.
It's Ancient.
Rush says it's thousands of years old
and we're pretty far off into the universe.
- What's he doing to get us home?
- He says he's working on it,
but we have bigger problems.
The life-support system
isn't working properly.
If we can't get it fixed,
there's not much time.
You should also know that he used
the communication stones to contact Earth,
and he said General O'Neill
put him in charge.
I don't think so. I don't think... Oh...
Sir, you shouldn't be trying
to get up just yet, okay?
I don't think I have a choice, T.J.
I can't feel my legs.
- Whoa, jeez!
- ELI: Whoa!
What is that thing?
Come here, I'll show you.
It's a... It's a camera.
It's a flying camera. I'm calling it a Kino,
you know, after the Russian...
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Well, I figure maybe we can use it
to check out the damaged areas of the ship.
- That's good.
- Yeah.
- That's good. Where's it going now?
- Oh, I don't know. It's just doing its thing,
but there's lots more of them.
- Yeah, it's cool.
- Yeah!
- Do you want one?
- It's not a gumball machine, Eli.
Okay.
- Okay!
- Okay, so you figured out
where they keep the Kinos.
What else have you figured out?
Give me a break, man. This is my second
spaceship, and my first was yesterday.
I know. Icarus was my first SGC
assignment after training.
I haven't been at this
much longer than you have.
Did they beam you out of your house?
- No. You got me there.
- Got any food on you?
- No.
- Tylenol?
- Headache?
- Yeah.
Me, too.
Neuropraxia is temporary paralysis
that can follow a concussive injury.
You don't know?
You'd need an MRI and a qualified doctor
who knows how to read it
to know for sure if there's spinal damage.
We don't have either.
Hopefully, it's just the nerves in shock.
Best I can do is insist that you remain still.
Your tour was over two weeks ago.
You should be in some classroom
in San Diego.
Seattle. That's where my scholarship was.
- I'm sorry.
- That part's not your fault.
Tell Rush I want to see him.
Yes, sir.
- What's that?
- Flying camera ball.
- I'm calling it a Kino.
- Don't ask.
- That's marvelous.
- It comes with a remote.
I thought we could use it to look around.
- What do you have?
- Well, it's not so good, really.
These processing nodes are scrubbers,
responsible for cleaning CO2 from the air.
Here, here, and here, it's indicating
malfunction. Others are failing.
Greer, this is Scott. I'm heading
for the Gate Room. Meet me there.
Look, I'm just saying
that she better stay out of my face.
I'll remind her of your personal space issues
next chance I get.
Dr. Rush? Colonel Young wants
to see you right away.
There should be a kind of grate
covering the node.
RUSH: What do you see?
SCOTT: A problem.
We see a very big problem.
What happened?
You collapsed. We brought you here.
- What's going on?
- I'm not sure. I've been here with you.
I need to know what's happening, Chloe.
This is important.
Dad, I was worried about you.
- Okay.
- And I'm scared.
One step at a time, honey.
One step at a time.
- My pills...
- No, Dad, you can't take any more of those.
Your ribs are badly bruised.
You will bleed internally.
If I don't take those pills, a bruise
is going to be the least of my problems.
I know.
Don't worry about me. Go.
Find out what's going on out there.
No, I want to be here with you.
And I want you here, but right now,
I want to know what's going on
just a little bit more.
Okay.
I'll be here when you get back.
- Okay.
- What's going on?
- I don't know, man.
The air filter's full of crap. Come on.
They want us to keep looking.
- Let's go.
- All right, okay.
Alkaline.
Everyone's heart rates are elevated,
people are reporting headaches.
- It has to be.
- What?
The used-up residue
of whatever magic compound
the Ancients used
to scrub CO2 from the air.
So, now we have two big problems
relating to the life support.
Our first priority must be to
seal off any of the leaks.
If we can manage that, then we can
maybe buy ourselves a day or so
before the buildup of CO2 kills us.
- As it stands, how much time do we have?
- I don't know.
Couple of hours at most.
Huh. Awesome.
Brody, there was some medical-grade
soda lime in the supply manifest?
- It never made it.
- That's a pity.
Well, in a ship this old
there's bound to be systems
past their designed life.
Okay, let's say we find the leaks.
Can you fix this?
I doubt this stuff can be cooked off.
Perhaps if there were stores
of this substance in a clean form,
or something else capable of
CO2 sequestration, calcium carbonate,
lithium hydroxide, then yes, "if."
Okay, well, that's not going to matter
because you're going to get the gate
dialed back to Earth
before this becomes an issue,
- Rush, right?
- Lieutenant...
That's the kind of thing
you're taught to say in officer training,
presumably for the benefit of
those who don't know any better.
Please.
What makes you think I won't try?
Greer, I found what looks like a shuttle.
Looks like there are two shuttles,
attached to individual docking sleeves.
- We're all going to die.
- GREER: Shut up, Franklin.
I'm just saying
what everyone's got to be thinking.
I said shut up,
or else you're going to be the first.
This the door?
Yeah, yeah, that's it. Can you close it?
It won't close.
We can't close it from here, either.
There's something wrong
with the mechanism.
FRANKLIN: I think I found the leak.
There's another door
on the back of the shuttle,
but there's no control.
Then maybe we can close it off locally.
FRANKLIN: The shield keeping the air inside
is obviously not 100% effective.
RUSH: Probably wasn't
designed to compensate
for the amount of damage
the ship has sustained.
FRANKLIN: Is there a way of boosting it?
At least in the areas we need it?
RUSH: We haven't found a way yet.
It seems to be operating
at maximum capability.
ELI: Open the door!
Well, that's not good.
That's very good, sir. A very good sign.
I don't have time for this, do I?
Two problems. We're venting atmosphere
from a damaged shuttle,
and even if we could seal it off,
the life-support system in this ship
is past its expiration date.
We'll build up CO2
to lethal levels within a day.
Well, that explains the headache.
You already had one.
They'll find a way.
That's what these people do.
Well, most of these people
aren't even supposed to be here.
- How did the ship get damaged?
- We don't know.
It certainly looks like it's been through
a battle, at least the parts we can access.
We're still cut off from most of the ship.
It's huge.
They tried jamming something into
the shuttle doorway to keep it open
long enough to let
the person inside get out...
But it just opens again.
Some sort of safety mechanism,
like an elevator.
Rush says he can't override it.
How long do we have right now?
As it stands...
Rush says if we don't get it closed,
we've got...
...just over an hour.
Bad air's better than no air.
Guess a day's better than an hour.
Someone's got to go in there
and close this door.
My head is pounding.
Heartbeat has accelerated.
It's getting harder and harder to breathe,
as our very lives
are being vented out into space.
That is going to get old very fast.
- This needs to be documented.
- No one's going to see that.
How do you know?
We made it here. Someone else could, too.
If we die, maybe this can help them
to find out what happened to us.
Yeah, well, we're not dead yet.
I'm starting to have slightly blurred...
- Eli!
- What?
So how are we going to decide who?
RUSH: I assume we're not going
to get any volunteers.
What's another day going to buy us?
Time, to find a way to survive.
May I see the list?
JOHANSEN: I marked the names
of anyone injured.
Right. We have to find out people's
skills, background, experience...
Doesn't take any special skills
to die from asphyxiation!
Look. What I'm saying is,
it shouldn't be someone
with potentially valuable knowledge
or abilities we might need
to help us survive beyond this.
Are you really suggesting
- what I think...
- Half the people on this ship
- already want to kill you.
- I don't care.
You can't ask someone
to sacrifice themselves, period.
Politicians ask military personnel
to sacrifice themselves
for the good of others all the time.
If someone doesn't go in there
and close that door,
we're all going to die, period.
Franklin is still working at
the airlock controls locally,
but it doesn't look good, sir.
Camile's explaining the situation
to everyone onboard.
- I'll do it.
- Sir?
This isn't the kind of thing I can ask
somebody else to volunteer for.
If we're going to make it past this,
we're going to need you, sir.
I don't know about that. You're doing
a pretty good job without me, Lieutenant.
Yeah? Well, look at the mess we're in.
- If that's not proof that we need you, then...
- Look, I'm not sure anyone should do it.
I don't want someone sacrificing
themselves for me.
I say we figure this out together
while we still have time,
- or we all die trying.
- I want you to both listen to me.
It needs to be done, and I'm doing it.
- Look, sir, you can barely stand.
- Help me.
Look, the paralysis is temporary.
- You know that now. You will recover.
- Lieutenant, I need your help.
- No, sir.
- I gave you an order.
- I know.
You can have me court-martialed
when we get home,
but I am not going to help you kill yourself.
My father's not in his room.
We'll find him. He does not leave this room.
- SCOTT: He can't have gotten far.
- I told him what was going on.
Greer, this is Scott, come in. Greer?
Greer, do you read?
Senator Armstrong is missing.
He may be headed your way.
He's here.
He's got a gun.
I don't want to shoot you.
I don't think you want to shoot me.
- Get out of the way.
- FRANKLIN: Just give me a little more time.
- Let me try and fix this.
- I don't have much.
ELI: Guys, I'm not seeing any change.
Whatever you just tried,
it's not working!
The problem's obviously mechanical.
You can't fix it.
Tell me what to do.
Dad! No, wait!
Dad, no! No! No! No!
Open the door!
- Open the door, please!
- I can't!
Please open the door!
- He was dead on his feet.
- Dad, no!
I love you.
Please open the door. No!
Eli! Not him!
There's nothing I can do for him here.
Help him! Open the door, please!
Please! No. No! No!
No! No!
No!
He can't leave me.
Chloe. Chloe!
Well, at least he bought us a day.
You! You did this! You killed him!
You've killed all of us!
- Chloe, stop! Little help here.
- Hey, hey, relax.
- Hey, hey, Chloe.
- Just get away from me! All of you!
Miss Armstrong. You're in shock.
Believe me, I understand.
Everyone deals with tragedy
in different ways.
- You're looking for someone to blame.
- I'm not looking.
Hey, hey.
I'm sorry about your father. I truly am.
He was a good man, and he certainly
wouldn't have been my choice,
but you must realize,
none of this was my fault.
I didn't create the situation
that forced us here.
There was no other way.
Miss Armstrong, I know
you don't want to hear this just now,
but this ship...
This ship could be the most important
discovery mankind has made
since the stargate itself.
You know, the Icarus Project was
something your father truly believed in.
Enough to risk his career to support.
What difference does it make if we all die?
A number of people died
during the attack on the base.
Some of them I knew very well.
I'm sure some had more value than others.
As human beings,
all of them were invaluable.
Look, my point is, I promise you,
I will do everything I can to make sure
no one gave their life in vain.
No one.
Please give me a chance.
Colonel.
- We've lost Senator Armstrong.
- Oh, my God.
- He's bought us some time.
- To do what?
We're working on it. First up
is trying to dial the gate back home.
- Should you even be on your feet?
- No.
Well, I am on my feet,
and right now we're trying to get home.
Camile, I need your help.
You know these people.
I need you to spread the word.
Try to keep things as positive as you can.
- I can do that.
- Good.
CHLOE: I can't believe my dad is gone.
I watched him die,
and I still just can't accept it.
- Tell me about him.
- Why?
Man died so I could live.
I'd like to know a little more about him.
No matter how tired he was,
or how long he'd worked,
or what was going on in his life,
he always had time to listen to me.
I'd go on and on.
He never preached.
He never told me what to do,
even though sometimes I wished he would.
He would just listen.
And then he would tell me
that he loved me.
The best part was if I'd had a fight
with my mom, he never took sides.
Hmm.
Oh, God. My mom.
He was her whole life.
She probably thinks we're both dead.
All I know is that he wanted you to go on.
I know.
I got to get back to the search.
You going to be okay?
I don't know.
Fair enough.
- RUSH: Eli?
- What?
What are you doing?
I just watched a man die.
Okay?
Don't you even care?
Of course I do, and I'm also trying to learn
as much as I can, as quickly as I can.
That is, in addition to running
nine separate searches
in the database in the hope
of solving our life-support issues.
Right.
Found anything?
Destiny.
As in ours?
The name of the ship.
Translated from Ancient.
I've also discovered
that they were never here.
I thought this was an Ancient ship.
It is, but they sent it out unmanned,
planning to use the gate to get here
when it was far enough
out into the universe,
but they probably learned to Ascend
before that time.
Learned to what?
Ascension.
It's a process whereby
consciousness converts to energy
that no longer requires physical form.
That wasn't in the video.
Well, there's more than one video.
We should get back to work.
Sorry.
Sir, I think I got it.
It wasn't even that hard to find.
It's right here in the dialing program.
- You're sure?
- Yes, it's an eight-symbol address.
You mean you can dial this thing
back to Earth?
There's no point of origin indicated,
but still,
there's only 36 symbols on this gate.
I'm assuming the ninth symbol represents
some X-factor distance equation.
Well, I don't care. Start dialing.
Sir, don't we want to
bring Dr. Rush in on this?
YOUNG: Well, you said
this wasn't that hard to find?
- No.
- Well, then he probably already knows
and didn't tell us.
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
- What?
Someone's dialing the gate.
- Colonel Young. You're up.
- Nice to see you, too, Rush.
I did order you to report to me.
Yes, but what are you doing?
We're trying to dial Earth.
RUSH: That would be a mistake.
YOUNG: Riley thinks he's found
the address for home.
RUSH: His understanding of Ancient
is marginal at best.
RILEY: With respect, Doctor, I know enough
to recognize a reference to Earth.
He says the address wasn't
that hard to find, Rush.
No, no. This is a complete
waste of power we may need.
We have the address back.
All we need is the right point of origin.
And we've got 36 tries.
We barely have enough power
to operate the main systems.
This ship simply doesn't have
the capability to dial Earth.
You see, that's news to me.
- He didn't tell me that, either.
- Well, I've only just learned myself,
- and you know what I've been doing.
- Even if it doesn't work,
the people aboard this ship
need to see us at least try.
So, what, you're going to drain
what little power we have
for the sake of morale?
How ridiculous.
What was that?
YOUNG: Anyone near the observation deck?
Colonel, it looks like
we've dropped out of FTL.
- RILEY: Because we were draining power?
- No, no.
If I'm right, the gate should
begin to dial any moment.
How did you know that?
The ship detected a stargate on a planet
within range that may have what we need.
What? How the hell
are there even stargates out here?
The Ancients sent out a number
of unmanned ships ahead of this one.
They're programed
to gather data, resources,
to manufacture stargates
and deposit them in habitable worlds.
Any relevant information
is relayed back here to help plot the course.
You're telling me
that this ship knows we're in trouble?
Yes, because I told it we were.
Essentially, we're flying on autopilot.
This ship may have stopped
when it was within range of a stargate
regardless of our need.
But I have reason to believe...
YOUNG: So, what we need is
on the other side of that wormhole?
An educated guess, yes.
There's only one way to find out.
RILEY: Sir, you can't do that.
We have no idea what's on the other side.
We can use the Kino to find out.
I expect that's the purpose of this device.
- I'm getting readings over here.
- What have we got?
Temperature, gravity,
atmosphere composition,
barometric pressure.
Oxygen, nitrogen, very little CO2,
extremely low humidity.
- Habitable, but just barely.
- Good enough.
BRODY: Looks like four other addresses
came up here, too.
They could be other planets within range.
Maybe we should think about
dialing them up and seeing...
No, no, no, they're locked out.
The ship chose this one.
The stargate is open,
all we have to do is step through.
What we have to do is put a team together.
Dr. Rush.
RUSH: Looks like our time might be limited.
YOUNG: What is it?
It's a countdown. Just over 12 hours left.
What happens then?
I suspect we jump back into FTL.
Palmer is a geologist.
Obviously she should go.
Franklin and Brody are
the best of the rest of what we have.
Thanks for the ringing endorsement.
He didn't even mention me.
YOUNG: Franklin goes. The others stay.
We're still going to need good people
working on the problem from this end.
ELI: I'd like to go.
Really?
If I can help, then...
- Colonel Young, please.
- What? You don't think I can handle it?
He's going.
I've been off-world before.
You have made a habit out of
pulling our asses out of the fire.
Eli, you want to go, you're going.
The only one I'm questioning right now
is you, Dr. Rush.
Well, besides Palmer, I'm the only one
who knows what we're looking for.
We have 12 hours to find what we need
and then get back on the ship.
You're sure you can't stop it?
No, we're just along for the ride for now.
Then we may all be better off on the planet.
Well, that's another reason
why I should go.
Someone to assess whether
long-term survival there is even an option.
Right. Okay.
I want everyone clear
that Scott is in charge of this mission.
Let's gear up, let's find whatever
supplies we have, and move out.
- Sir, about Eli...
- He volunteered.
He's not trained for this.
Just like a lot of people we got on the ship.
I'm going to need to know
what they're made of.
He'll slow us down.
Well, if he does,
you send him back to the gate.
Listen, if we're going to make it,
and I'm not just talking the next few hours,
we're going to need
everyone on board to step up.
Lieutenant.
Keep an eye on Rush.
We'll be back, sir.
Good luck.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org