Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
RUSH: Destiny.
The design is clearly Ancient.
Launched hundreds of thousands
of years ago.
SCOTT: Where the hell are we?
Several billion light years from home.
We are on a ship, but we have no idea
where we are in relation to Earth.
RUSH: This ship could be the most
important discovery mankind has made
since the stargate itself.
YOUNG: These are the wrong people
in the wrong place.
SCOTT: I've got a lot of wounded.
We need to get home.
RUSH: We barely have enough power
to operate the main systems.
This ship simply doesn't have
the capability to dial Earth.
In this case are
five Ancient communication stones.
RUSH: You physically take control
of an individual at the other end.
- Where are you?
- ELI: It's top secret.
- But did you get the letter from...
- Yeah, the Air Force, I got it.
You sound like you're in an airplane.
It's the kind of thing I always dreamed of.
Dad! No, wait!
CHLOE: The ship is old and damaged.
We were losing air and somebody had to...
He's dead, isn't he?
I didn't choose my job over you.
It wasn't just about the job.
I want nothing more than
to get back here to be with you.
You made your choice, Everett.
You are so beautiful.
Don't.
I'm sorry. I never meant to hurt you.
SCOTT: Colonel...
Sorry, sir. They're waiting.
YOUNG: Sorry.
We're late.
- TELFORD: You're late.
- It's my fault.
Thanks for joining us, Colonel.
Sorry, sir, I wasn't expecting a party.
We may have figured out
a way to get you home.
Surprise.
WILLIAMS: Now, the power flow issues
are obviously the biggest variable,
but our simulations are encouraging.
It's time to take it to the next level.
Any questions?
It sounds dangerous.
The IOA fully supports
the implementation of this plan.
I've seen it for myself.
The situation on board is dire
and justifies the risk.
Look, I'm not going
to pretend to understand
everything you guys are talking about,
but it sounds like there's a chance
that this plan could end badly.
You want to get those people home.
So do we.
I'm just saying maybe these guys
could do a little more calculating.
The fact is, we are at the stage
where a practical attempt is the only
way to get any more hard data.
The goal is to save lives.
And we don't want to put the ship at risk.
All we're asking is that you try.
Well, this is something I would have
to take up with everyone on board.
Colonel, my office.
Look, if it makes you feel any better,
Colonel Carter saved my ass
dozens of times,
using all kinds of wacky science
I didn't understand.
Well, I can't force people
to do something they don't want to do.
You're in command of that ship.
It's not a democracy.
I'm sorry, sir, it's just...
It's not that simple.
Yes. Yes, it is.
A United States Senator is dead.
His daughter and dozens of other people
are trapped a billion light years
away from home.
The President wants it done.
Sir, with all due respect...
You are being given a direct order, Colonel.
And I'm telling you that,
regardless of the consequences
to my standing, I'm going
to take the situation under advisement.
I will let you know my decision tomorrow.
- Are you sure you don't want anything?
- I'm fine.
Thank you.
- Must be nice to get out, I imagine.
- It is.
Everyone's very impressed
with how you're holding up
under the circumstances.
I'm doing my best.
You're our eyes and ears now.
Your life, certainly the lives
of everyone aboard, is the first priority.
But you have to understand,
there's a lot at stake here.
You passed me up for promotion
four times.
I never really got
a straight answer as to why.
You are a highly trusted, well-respected
member of this organization.
You would not have been on Icarus
in the first place if you weren't.
The point is,
I know there's no way in hell
you'd be talking to me right now
if you had a choice.
So, please, can we just cut to the chase?
Make this happen.
I'm not a scientist.
- How can I do that?
- You have influence.
The people onboard need to
believe it'll get them home.
Even if, in reality, it can get us all killed.
- Not what I've been told.
- Why are you pushing so hard?
If this works,
we think we might be able to use the data
to re-engineer the process
in one of our ships here, in this galaxy.
Dial a gate to Destiny
without an Icarus-type planet.
Yes, and get the team that was supposed
to go in the first place back onboard.
Now that we know
where the ninth chevron leads,
this mission has taken on
even more importance.
Why isn't Rush here?
Ah.
We're not convinced
Rush wants to come home.
And do I have to remind you how much
you have to gain personally in all of this?
Assuming I live.
The ship doesn't have enough power
to dial back to Earth,
and as we've seen recently,
when the ship runs out of juice,
it finds a star and refills its tanks.
Now, theoretically, at that time, the full
power of the star should be available to us.
Star power. Ultimate wattage, baby.
Yeah, it's brilliant.
If we can somehow use the ship as
a conduit and channel the star's energy
into the gate as we dial...
That would do it?
The problem is
the whole ship is a conduit part.
Well, does anyone know when the ship
will run out of power again?
It's tough to tell.
Based on current usage,
probably going to be several months.
Not if we can drain the power faster.
Right, that's part of the plan
that sounded a little vague.
- It's possible.
- So, you guys are saying
you're all for this?
Let's see what Rush says.
Given how little we know about this ship...
Can't we at least try it,
and abort if something goes wrong?
Well, unfortunately,
the "something goes wrong" part
would most likely mean
the ship exploding.
Not according to the people
who came up with the idea.
Well, if only all science
was that definitive, Colonel.
You're just going to have to choose
who you want to believe.
Nothing to worry about.
It doesn't hurt at all.
- Do I look worried?
- A little.
Just trying to figure out
what I'm going to say to my mom.
My family thinks
I'm on sabbatical in Africa.
So, when it's time to come back,
what do I do, click my heels three times?
RILEY: There's no way for you
to disconnect the transmission yourself.
The base needs to be manually shut down.
There's a device on the other side as well,
and turning either off
will sever the connection.
- Pretty cool.
- RILEY: Easiest way to swap consciousness
with someone across the universe
I've ever seen.
- What's with the Kino?
- First time using the stones.
Very exciting.
Any chance I could get something else
to wear?
Wow, check me out.
Okay, this is weird.
The people we're in can't hear us,
can they?
No.
Wonder what they're doing
with our bodies.
- Colonel Telford.
- I'll just get right to it.
I've been ordered to enact the rescue plan
put forward by the IOA.
- Rescue plan?
- I don't understand.
I've brought Doctors McCormack
and Williams with me.
- I believe you know them.
- Yes.
- I've already set them to work.
- What about Colonel Young?
Effective immediately,
I'm assuming command of the Destiny.
YOUNG: You replaced me.
O'NEILL: For now.
- Without waiting to hear my answer?
- You were going to say...
Give us more time.
Then you were going to be
disobeying a direct order.
- Sir...
- Look,
I offered you command of the expedition.
You were my first choice,
but you turned it down.
Your exact words, as I recall, were,
"I don't think it's still in me, sir."
Well, I'm there now, sir,
whether I like it or not,
whether anyone likes it.
This is wrong, and you know it.
I've spent most of my career
looking up to you,
because you always did the right thing,
even if it meant disregarding
the chain of command.
Colonel, don't think I like this.
- They can't do this to us, can they?
- YOUNG: For now, they have.
Look, I think it comes down to
the fact that they don't trust Rush,
and the truth is, I can't blame them.
What are we supposed to do?
Well, they've given you permission
to see your families
as long as you guys follow the rules.
Look, I hate to go there,
but what happens if they screw up
and the ship explodes?
Most likely, we will die here, too.
Look, apparently they're just doing
some preliminary testing,
information gathering, nothing too crazy.
So, what you're saying is,
live it up while we can.
- Colonel Telford, I presume.
- Sergeant.
He can use the facilities. That's it.
And what if the power flow
can't be controlled?
Well, if there are any dangerous
fluctuations, we just shut it down
and allow the ship
to continue powering up.
Early tests show it should work.
We are not going to be putting you
in any more danger
than you're already in just being here.
McCORMACK: From what I gather,
supplies are desperately short.
And given the condition of the ship,
it could experience a fatal breakdown
at any time.
No one is trying to alarm you unduly,
but we can't continue to scrape by,
barely surviving.
Obviously, we can't say for sure
that this is going to get you home,
but the best minds that we have
are working on this,
and I'm sure you'll agree
it's well worth pursuing.
Dr. Rush.
Colonel.
- It is spectacular, isn't it?
- Yes.
If this plan has any chance at succeeding...
Which it doesn't.
Control over most of the ship's
operational systems is limited, at best.
Navigation, propulsion, and many
others have been locked out entirely
by a master code,
which we have had no luck in breaking.
I thought you might want to know we've
come up with a way of draining the power.
Yes, so I heard.
Many of the power conduits
have been badly damaged,
and firing the ship's weapons system
without either repairing them
or isolating the damaged areas
would be prohibitively dangerous.
That's what we're working on right now.
Just wanted to keep you informed.
She's not going to understand.
She can barely follow
an episode of Star Trek.
You don't have to tell her.
- Yes?
- Hi.
- I...
- Can I help you?
My name is Phillip.
Phillip Fry. I work with your son.
You know Eli?
We've recently become very close.
It doesn't feel real.
It's like a bad dream.
You're here.
If this is the only way, I can live with that.
I can't stay this way forever, Mom.
I know.
Everyone's working very hard
to get you home.
I'm trying to get through this.
I am.
- Your father always used to say...
- One step at a time.
I miss him so much.
Me, too.
Awesome, thanks.
Eli drinks four or five of those a day.
- Actually, he quit.
- Really?
- I find that hard to believe.
- He's on a bit of a crash diet.
You may not recognize him
next time you see him.
- When will that be? Do you know?
- I'm sorry, I'm not sure.
- Really getting into shape, though.
- Can I get you something to eat?
Eli said you make the most
amazing chocolate chip cookies.
- He told you that?
- Oh, yeah.
It's crazy how close you get
in such a short time.
Sometimes it's like
he's just right up there, in my brain.
Why don't I make some?
You can take them back with you.
He also said you make a mean schnitzel,
but I don't want to put you out.
No, I'm happy to do it.
You know,
I thought he'd be calling more often.
Here, let me help you.
Tell me, this work you're doing...
- I know you can't tell me much about it.
- I can tell you that it's important.
In fact, it could change the world
as we know it.
Really? My Eli?
Not that I'm surprised,
don't get me wrong.
He's my son. Of course I think he's special.
He was always so bright, so different,
but he just...
He never seemed to apply himself.
Some of it was my fault.
No. He doesn't blame you at all,
for anything.
I'm sorry if this is personal,
but he told me you're not well.
Did he?
Lucky guess.
Eggs are in the fridge, right?
I didn't think
he ever talked to anyone about it.
He asked me to make sure the Air Force
was making good on their promise
to help you.
To be honest, the whole thing
makes me a little anxious.
I really just want to know Eli's okay.
He is.
You make sure you tell him
I'm proud of him.
I will.
I'm sorry.
It's just... It all happened so suddenly,
and I miss him.
He misses you, too.
RILEY: That's it for me.
BRODY: I'm almost done over here.
You're stalling.
I'm doing things
the way they need to be done.
Now, we've isolated power to 40%
of the operational weapons system,
and it should be good enough to get us
a read on our power reduction capability.
- The next time we drop out of FTL...
- Look, look, this ship is old and damaged.
The computers aren't registering
half the things they're supposed to.
I want manual confirmation before
activating any system
that comprehensive.
Over 80% of this ship is inaccessible
without spacesuits right now.
With only two suits,
doing it your way could take months.
If that's what it takes.
- Dr. Rush, we're ready here.
- RUSH: Okay, sending power through.
Riley?
RUSH: Looks like a coolant leak.
BRODY: I thought you got it.
Yeah, so did I.
There's a problem.
Power's backing up in the relay.
- Shut it down.
- I'm trying. It's not working.
The problem is contained.
It's restricted to that corridor.
That's not the point.
How big an explosion
are we talking about?
RILEY: I'm going in. I can seal it.
Are you crazy? You can't go in there!
We're on the hull!
- Rush!
- We are in FTL!
If it punctures the hull,
disrupts the shield at all,
even for a microsecond,
then the entire ship could be in jeopardy.
Riley!
It's... It's going to be touch and go.
We're proceeding with the test
next time we drop out of FTL.
Colonel, the man nearly died.
You're the one who put him in jeopardy.
I was trying to make sure
you didn't kill us all.
I'm not going to.
Look, I accept responsibility
for what happened,
but you forced the situation,
and activating the weapons system
the way you're proposing
is completely reckless.
Come on, Rush,
these people are in danger just being here,
evidenced by what just happened.
This ship is falling apart.
They're the wrong people for this.
We need to get them home.
Yeah, well, there's a right way
of doing that.
We are doing it the right way.
That's a matter of opinion.
Look, I know that we've had
our differences in the past.
Yeah, you wanted me
off the expedition team. I remember.
It was my duty to express concern
for how everyone else felt about you.
So are you suggesting that my judgment
is now somehow clouded,
or is it that I'm just plain lying?
Admit it, Rush,
after everything that's happened,
you're afraid
they're not going to let you come back.
- Hello?
- CHLOE: Hey, it's me.
- How's it going?
- Okay.
How'd your mom take it?
Couldn't do it. I told her I was a co-worker.
I told my friends
I'm Cousin Liz from out west.
I may have oversold the job.
I said I was going to change
everything for mankind as we know it.
What the hell, right?
Might as well make her feel
like I left for a good reason.
You did.
Right. I guess so.
So, some of my old friends
are taking Cousin Liz out on the town
to see Janelle Monáe.
- You want to come hang out with us?
- Hell yes.
Emily, it's me.
Emily. Hey, no. Emily!
Emily, please just open the door.
- Go away!
- I'm not leaving, Emily.
- I'm not going to leave you.
- I will call the police, Everett.
Emily, please.
It doesn't end like this, Emily!
Open the door! I just want to talk to you!
Hey, just...
I need you to just listen to me, okay?
Because I know this is crazy.
I'm barely keeping it together,
and the only thing that's keeping me
from going out of my mind is you.
That's making me crazy, too,
because I know how much I hurt you
and I know that you hate me for leaving.
Emily, I really tried.
I didn't want to come here.
I tried not to come here,
but I can't stand it!
Baby, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry, and I love you so much.
Please, just... I had to try, all right?
Just in case there was a chance.
A chance that you could forgive me.
Maybe you're just afraid,
thinking that I would die out there,
so it's easier for you to just push me
away now than have to face me like this.
I just want to come home to you,
and that's all I want.
We're dancing free
but we're stuck here underground
And everybody trying
to figure they way out
Hey, hey, hey, all we ever wanted to say
Hi.
Me?
- What's your name?
- Phil.
- Can I buy you a drink?
- I have one.
Yes, you do.
- Want to dance?
- Sure.
Oh, my God, this is awesome!
Oh, make it rain, ain't a thang
and the sky to fall
The silver bullet's in your hand
and the war's heating up
And when the truth goes bang
The shouts splatter out
Revolutionize your lives and find a way out
And when you're growing down
instead of growing up
You gotta ooh, ah, like a panther
Tell me, are you bold enough
to reach for love?
Hey, we're going to go dance.
You guys want to come?
No.
So, how long have Celina and Josh
been together?
I don't know.
- Too bad about Chloe's dad, huh?
- Yeah.
- What's she going to do?
- What do you mean?
Well, her job.
She was working for him, right?
I don't really think
that's on her mind right now.
Sure.
- Well, tell her we're sorry.
- I will.
You know, it sucks for me,
because Senator Armstrong was hooking
me up with his Wall Street connections,
and now that's not going to happen.
I think I have to go throw up.
Hey.
- So, is Chloe really okay?
- She'll be fine.
- I wish she'd call me back.
- I'm sure she misses you.
I think she's just having a hard time
dealing right now.
It's just... I really need to talk to her.
You know?
You mean about the fact
that you're sleeping with her boyfriend?
- What?
- It's pretty obvious
you guys are together.
Look, Josh and Chloe broke up.
Yeah, I don't think
she ever would have suspected
that you're the real reason why.
- I don't know who you...
- How could you do this to me?
- To you?
- You're supposed to be her best friend!
Get your hands off of me.
Excuse me, Colonel? Can I have a word?
One moment.
About Sergeant Greer...
Colonel Telford?
EMILY: Oh, baby...
Scott, it's Young.
- What just happened?
- We just dropped out of FTL, sir.
What's going on?
It must have disrupted communication
between the stones.
Scott, listen to me, we don't have
a lot of time. You've got to...
Colonel Young? Colonel Young!
Oh, baby...
- What just happened?
- We just dropped out of FTL.
Looks like it might have temporarily
disrupted the communication device.
We have to fix that.
Sir, I think Colonel Young wanted me
to shut down the stones.
This is no longer his command,
is that clear?
The device stays on.
A glitch?
That's one hell of a glitch, General.
That's what I'm being told, Colonel.
They're working on it.
Yes, sir. Just let me know.
They said it was some sort of glitch.
Apparently. It won't happen again.
- How do they know?
- I don't know.
Right now, I don't care.
Did you see that girl I was dancing with?
She wrote her e-mail address on my hand.
I hate this. I hate everybody.
Hey, Captain Buzzkill.
Whoa! Okay, no more drinks for Cousin Liz.
You see those two over there?
That's my best friend, Celina,
and my ex-boyfriend.
You can do better.
Do you want to dance?
I think I want to go over there
and punch him in the face.
Hey, hey! I have an idea.
How about we get out of here?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Easy.
- This is awful.
I'm not even drunk at all.
Really? Because you seem drunk.
- My head's just all foggy.
- Almost there.
Usually it makes me feel better,
at least for a little while.
It usually makes me dizzy,
and then I fall asleep.
Just once I'd like to go out with a girl
and not have it end with her crying.
My life was so shallow and pointless,
and then I started working with my dad.
I really thought that I could do something,
make a difference.
You can.
These aren't even my tears!
I'm sorry.
If it makes you feel better,
I had a really great time tonight.
I'm glad.
Do you know the last time
a girl that hot told me I was cute?
Never.
Doesn't it bother you that
she wasn't really talking about you?
Well, when you put it like that...
Oh.
I didn't mean that. Come on.
You're cute. The real you.
- What?
- Nothing.
Go on. You were saying...
And you're funny, too.
And you're a genius. And...
- Don't say it.
- ...you're a good friend.
Yes.
That's me. I am a good friend.
I don't want to be trapped on that ship,
and I don't want to be stuck here like this.
I can't feel anything. Can you?
- Well...
- You know what's the worst part
about having a father like mine?
- Whoa, how did we get onto that?
- You can't live up to it.
He was so great.
I'll never be like he was.
My dad definitely would have
punched Josh in the face!
Wow. I think I'm going to take you home.
Could you take me home?
A lot of people are behind this.
Well, a lot of people play the lottery.
What's surprising is
they'd do it with their lives.
I know you're opposed.
I have serious concerns myself.
I'm just wondering how much safer
it might be if you were involved.
They can't keep me
locked up in here forever.
You know he will, as long as he can.
- What you did...
- He had it coming to him.
Look, just shut down
the damn stones, man.
I'm not you, Ron.
- He's our commanding officer.
- Colonel Young
- is our commanding officer.
- Telford's got guards posted 24/7.
- What am I supposed to do?
- This better work.
What are you doing?
I'm making sure
we still have enough power
to control these consoles
when approaching the star.
Dr. Williams says you've come up with
a way of improving the odds of success.
- Well, I don't want to die, Colonel.
- Good.
Hopefully, we've proven
that's not our goal.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't deal with it, the thought of you
being trapped on that ship, with her.
Emily, what do I have to do?
And I shouldn't have brought it up again.
I know it's over,
but you got to understand...
Everett?
No...
- Rush, what's happening?
- We just jumped to FTL.
Rush?
- Colonel Telford?
- Yes.
Everything okay?
It will be soon enough.
All right, this is ridiculous.
Jumping back and forth without any
warning is completely unacceptable!
Seriously.
Routing power flow to the stargate.
Ready to attempt dial in.
Do it.
SCOTT: All right, stand back!
Everyone, back up!
BRODY: You're going to overload
the capacitors.
Bringing power flow down.
BRODY: The limitations are not holding.
Because the system wasn't meant
to handle this much power.
- Stay calm!
- The shield is failing.
Colonel, we need to abort.
Shut it down!
It's not working.
- I thought you said you could stop it!
- I know! It won't shut down.
Where the hell are you going?
SCOTT: Do something.
BRODY: They're gone.
Thank you.
If I can have everyone's attention, please.
I'm sorry to have to tell you that
we will not be going home.
Not yet, anyway, but you can all relax
and return to your quarters.
The ship will not be exploding,
at least not today.
Normal power levels
will be restored soon, right?
Yes.
Thank you.
You staged the whole thing.
So all of this was just to get rid of Telford?
Had to be done.
So you're saying that the ship
was never going to explode?
Oh, no, we would most definitely all be
dead had I not put certain limits in place.
I also arranged for the alarms
and warnings to go off regardless.
Bit of theater, always nice.
- Their plan was never going to work.
- You could have warned us.
You scared the crap out of everybody.
Well, I didn't know
who was on my side, did I?
YOUNG: Colonel Telford removed not only
any sense of command,
but the two scientists that designed
and implemented the program
that was causing the crisis.
The situation appeared to be irreversible.
Fortunately, Dr. Rush was able
to avoid catastrophic disaster.
Yes, and we'd like to see how he did that,
along with the rest of the data
collected during the experiment.
Those were people's lives
you were experimenting with.
- We were trying to get them home.
- You cut and ran.
There's no point in three more lives
being lost if it could be avoided.
Colonel Telford was following orders.
YOUNG: Sir, after much consideration,
we have decided
to stay in communication with Earth.
I hope personal visits for everyone onboard
will still be permitted.
That depends, Colonel.
- Consider it done.
- YOUNG: Thank you, sir.
I'm afraid the time that I've allotted
for this briefing is now up.
General.
We are going to have to
be tough. Disciplined.
The road may be longer
than many of us hoped.
We will have to sacrifice, compromise,
work together without exceptions.
I thought you did a good job.
People need to know the truth,
but they also need hope.
- I need you to do something for me.
- Sure thing.
Go over the data collected
as they tried to dial the gate.
I have already.
There's a lot I don't understand...
Well, then you need to learn, as fast as you
can, and you talk to whoever you have to.
You think Rush is hiding something?
That's what I want you to tell me.
YOUNG: We are going to survive.
We are going to make it home.
Make no mistake.
My first priority is to make sure
that we all return to those we love.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org