This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
That ship is the best chance
we have of getting home.
Are we done?
We'll never be done.
You shouldn't have left him
on the planet.
You think I don't know that?
Everyone thinks we're safe.
They think that they'll
never find us again.
Why did you take
one of our people prisoner?
We're not safe, are we?
They're coming!
Who's coming?
Lucian Alliance.
They're coming to take Destiny.
There's only one way
this is going to end if we wait.
I'm not
surrendering this ship.
Chloe,
what are you doing in here?
I don't know how I got here.
There may be something happening
to Chloe on a cellular level.
Some kind of genetic manipulation
gradually changing her.
What were you doing?
He wanted me to look at some
equations, see if I understood them.
- Did you?
- I don't know.
So, the chair kills off
any potential alien matter inside her
while leaving her human
side unaffected.
She's breathing and her pulse is steady.
- Did it work?
- We'll soon find out, won't we?
I think it's, uh, right over there.
Yeah, can you see it?
We're comin' into town.
How can you tell?
Hey, it beats the hell out of our digs
in Kandahar, don't it?
I wouldn't miss it for the world, brother.
Well, I appreciate it. I do.
Cloverdale!
Me first!
Damn, I thought my dad might be here.
There they are. Hey, guys!
He's coming to again!
T. J!
Just cut it off me, please!
Try something else!
I've tried everything in my bag.
Nothing is working.
The best thing for him
is to keep moving.
Matthew...
Matthew!
What the hell's the matter with you?
Sorry!
I'm sorry, he just ran out in front of me!
- No, I'm fine. I'm fine, I'm fine...
Thank God.
Lucky for you.
- No, no, no, I was just being stupid.
Look, Mr. Brody, don't worry about it.
They bounce at this age.
Okay. Hey, are we still on for the, uh...
Yeah, yeah. Yeah. Go, go.
We're takin' up the whole road here, guys.
If you wind up with any insurance issues,
Matt, I got it all on video.
I kind of wish you didn't, Eli.
Oh, you, uh, you must be Ronald.
Oh, Dad, sorry, this is Ron, my best man.
Pleasure to meet you, sir.
Oh, you call me Everett. You're family now.
- Yes, sir.
- And this is Chloe's brother, Eli.
Brother Elijah.
Eli, actually, and I took myself
out of the running for best man,
because I'm creating a video
for my wedding gift.
- Lucky for me.
- Yeah.
- Where's Chloe?
- Uh... Something about a dress.
She's going to meet you at the house.
I guess I'm anxious to see her.
I'll say, nearly got yourself killed
the day before your wedding.
Yeah, probably would've ruined
the whole weekend, huh?
Yeah, probably,
but I guess since it looks like
you're gonna live for another day,
welcome home, Son.
Okay, he's out again.
Guys, we can move him.
You'll be able to help him
once we're back on the ship, right?
We can't risk taking him aboard.
It's too dangerous.
What?
Rush is right.
You saw how quickly the organism
spreads on contact.
It could take over the whole ship.
He can't stay here either.
Chloe. Now, ready? One, two, three.
I got you, buddy.
Come on, come on, move your feet, Eli.
Come on.
Okay!
I'll run ahead, contact Destiny,
try to get them to send back
medical supplies.
If I'm fast, I'll get back
before you reach the gate, okay?
Yeah, yeah, good. Go.
- Eli...
- Yeah. Whoa. Stop.
Remote. Yeah. Okay.
Wow. Aw, this hasn't changed one bit.
Matt is clearly moved
seeing the old homestead again.
- What's that?
- A temp track for the voice-over.
All good documentaries have one.
I'm thinking Kiefer Sutherland,
but I'm the fallback.
Ronald, uh, make yourself at home.
Let me grab that.
You're going to be up in Matthew's room.
You're in my room.
I'll be fine on the couch in the den.
You're the one with the fiancée.
That's gonna be weird.
Like that'll stop you.
Okay, so, uh... So, what's the plan?
I say... You get married,
you start a family,
you grow old, and die happy.
Okay, well, I thought you guys might, uh...
What?
I don't know, throw a party maybe?
Was I supposed to do that?
No, no. Yeah. No, uh, Chloe said she wanted
you all to herself tonight.
Yeah, yeah, she said something
about wanting to catch
the early show at the Clova.
- Really?
- Yeah, that's what I said.
Well, we could see a movie any night.
What are you doing right there?
What, you don't want to see a movie
with your fiancée?
He'd better!
Mmm.
Video boy.
Kiefer Sutherland might have somethin'
to say over here.
Oh, I'm so sorry
I couldn't be there to meet you.
The train was too long
after I changed my shoes.
Uh... Okay.
Matt, what did you do to your arm?
Oh, I got hit by a car.
- What?
- I'm fine.
Hit... Are you sure?
Baby, you don't look so good.
Matt?
Time's an issue, I get it.
What do you need?
Lieutenant Johansen's medicinals.
One of everything
you can get your hands on,
but especially the alien venom.
Nothing she's tried so far has had any effect.
Okay.
What else?
I want to try hydrochloric acid.
We need some alcohol
from the still, clean bandages...
And whatever's appropriate
for cutting through bone.
It's as bad as that?
Yeah. Put it on Eli's Kino sled and
get it through as quickly as you can.
- What happened?
- You fainted.
I got it on video if you want to...
No thanks, Eli.
Why the heck would I faint?
You did just get hit by a car.
Ronald said you haven't eaten
all day.
Here.
No, I don't think that's it, honey.
Now, you listen to me.
You're one day away from being out of here.
You're fine, all right?
Go to a movie with your girlfriend.
You enjoy yourself.
We'll leave the lights on.
Okay?
Oh, you're going to hate the cake.
Would you stop worrying so much
about one day?
Think about all the days after that.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Okay!
Thank you.
You remember the first time we came here?
Yeah.
That's why we came here, isn't it?
Yup.
It's so beautiful.
- Whoa, this is...
- What?
It's like an
ocean of flowers.
This doesn't look familiar to you?
It goes on forever, doesn't it?
Did you see that?
Yeah.
Watch this.
Get out of there.
Don't you just want to
run through it barefoot?
Yeah.
It would be so beautiful.
Would you relax?
Maybe not.
I'm sorry.
Matthew, what is wrong with you?
You don't remember any of that
actually happening?
No. It's a movie.
No, I'm... I'm sorry, I...
I don't know what's wrong with me.
Can we just get out of here?
Hang on, I left my purse.
And what was that about?
I have no idea.
Look, I can stall for a while,
but you'll have to let them know
we're going to be early.
- Okay.
- Okay, thanks.
Wake up!
You've got to wake up! Wake up.
You've got to wake up!
Okay, let's unpack the supplies
and get him on the sled.
- What did you ask for?
- Everything I could think of.
- The venom was top of the list.
- All right, I'll try it first.
Has it spread beyond the arm?
- No, not yet.
Good.
I know.
Did something happen to you over there
that you want to talk about?
No, no, that was just some
kind of weird déjà vu.
I'm over it now.
Hey, you want to go to Mr. Brody's
for a bite?
Now?
- Matthew Scott!
- Hey, Mr. Volker!
Dale, please.
I'm your pharmacist, for God's sakes.
So you're back home.
No one... No one tells me these things.
Well, we're getting married this weekend.
Right! Yes, I... I did hear
something about that.
Wow! That must be...
- It is.
- Yeah, I bet it is.
I bet it is. Good... Good, so, uh...
What are you up to?
Uh, on our way to Brody's, but, uh,
I don't think they're open yet, do you?
Uh, why don't we find out?
No, it's no problem. No problem.
Adam! Hey, guess who I just bumped into?
Matthew Scott and...
That's right.
Yeah, hey, listen,
they were wondering if you were...
Just opened. Perfect.
Well, we'll see you in a few minutes.
They will... Them.
They... They'll see you. Good.
Well, they're all there.
The staff's all there.
The, uh, waiters and...
So...
Well, you're good to go.
Slow night, huh?
Oh, no, place is packed. Everyone's hiding.
What?
Surprise! Surprise!
You are a lot of work. Oh!
Oh, you couldn't sit through
one damn movie, huh?
I almost blew it, didn't I?
Mr. Volker was stalling.
Oh, I'm such an idiot!
Yes, you are, but my work is done.
I have delivered you to your bachelor party.
Better early than never.
Well done.
If he is hung-over in the morning...
No, no, no, we're good.
We got it. Everything's...
Nothing to worry about.
Listen, if you're not hung-over,
I will be very disappointed.
Here's a toast to my son,
to my boy, who is getting hitched!
What's that supposed to do?
Hopefully dull the pain.
It's still spreading towards us.
Probably following the vibrations
of our movement. Anything?
- The venom had no effect.
- That's disappointing.
It didn't even react to the acid.
I tried everything you brought back.
It's like this thing is indestructible.
Well, you know what you have to do.
No. No...
- I know it looks extreme...
- No, he wouldn't want that.
Any rational person would give up
a limb if it meant saving their life.
Hey, if we wait too long,
and it spreads to the rest of his body?
Those things are still comin' this way.
The leading edge is on the other side
of those trees.
Okay, that gives us roughly 15 minutes.
Ten.
Is that enough time?
No. We're almost to the gate.
We'll do it there.
Hurry.
Whoo!
- Whoo, whoo!
- Hey.
Brody! Brody, Brody, what...
What is this? What's with this music?
What's wrong with it?
- What's wrong with it?
- It sounds like an animal dying.
Best man chooses the music.
- I am the best man.
Oh, really?
Oh, is this the man here?
This is your fault?
Sir, I've been called a good man,
a strong man...
An angry man...
- Hey.
But I ain't never been called a
"best man" until now, huh?
Now, groom. "Groom" what is that?
Oh, God, that's me...
Last call, guys!
Oh, come on, Vaness.
Come on, night's young.
Come on, that's
it, keep 'em comin'.
Uh, I think you are cut off.
That is not the first time you've
told me that, if you catch my drift.
Let's not forget who
dumped who, Matt...
An awkward moment
with Matt's ex...
Are you flirting with me
the night before your wedding?
Hey, I still got a whole 19 hours
of freedom left.
Okay. Well, then, let's go.
Right now.
We'll drive somewhere,
and we'll never come back.
Whoa... Okay, come on, Vanessa.
I was... I was just kidding.
Yeah. That's what I thought.
Erase that.
Okay, all right.
You honestly weren't planning
on driving, were you?
Well, not now.
For God's sakes, Everett,
tomorrow's an important day.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah. No, it's true.
It's true. You got him?
Yeah, I got him.
Oh! Are we being arrested?
Just a friendly ride home.
Call it a wedding present.
- So how was it over there?
- Boring.
- He just means we didn't see any action.
- So, what's wrong with that?
What's wrong with that?
It's a waste of ability.
You're that good, huh?
Well, don't take this the wrong way,
Sergeant,
but guys like you
usually get themselves killed.
- Guys like me?
David, why?
Why do you always got to start a fight?
It's a conversation...
Hey, you guys ever wonder what's real?
Because ever since I got home,
I keep thinking I'm someone else.
Like, I'm... I'm not myself.
Alcohol can have that effect...
- No, I don't really drink.
I can see that.
- Oh, Chloe's gonna kill me.
- She'll... She'll get over it.
- Go to sleep, all right?
- Yeah, go ahead, close your eyes.
But I'm sorry to tell you that
when you wake up,
you're gonna feel guilty for things
you've done or said.
Some of it you won't even remember.
It'll just be a blur,
and you're going to wonder
if you're ever going to feel
like the person you used to be again.
Matthew?
I think he's out.
I hope so. I don't want him
waking up in the middle of this.
I need you to hold him still.
- Oh, God, I can't watch.
You don't have to.
Take his feet. Hold tight.
Hold his arm?
Have you done this before?
No.
Ready?
Wait, wait. Stop, stop.
What?
Look at the color.
- It's in his bloodstream.
- No point in dismembering him.
- Not if it's spreading internally.
Damn it!
So, what do we do now?
We've got three hours
before the ship goes into...
- No, Sergeant, there's no...
- Let's keep at it.
- We can still win this!
- This is an enemy you can't fight.
Watch me. Three hours. That's the clock...
Not really.
He means we're gonna be overrun by the
organism in less than an hour, Greer.
Are there any planets in range?
One, but it's locked out. I guess
it's more dangerous than this place.
- Dial the ship.
- We can't take him back to Destiny.
- We've already been through this...
- I know that! I need some things.
Matt?
Why did you drink so much?
Isn't that what
you're supposed to do at a bachelor party?
That's why you do things,
because you're supposed to?
Sometimes.
Is that why you're getting married?
What? No! Why would you say that?
So you're not just coming back from war
to marry your high school sweetheart
because you're supposed to?
Because you think it's
the right thing to do?
Uh...
Wow. You really should know the answer
faster than that, Matt...
Chloe, this isn't fair.
My brain isn't working.
Well, it had better start working.
This is your wedding day.
You have to talk to the Justice of
the Peace at 10:00 about our vows.
I know.
You have to pick up your tuxedos.
I know. Chloe...
I really, really have to pee.
Oh!
So we're ruling out quarantine?
Well, it's not up to me
to rule out anything,
but we have to consider the possibility
that Lieutenant Scott's infection
is how this organism reproduces.
It's already spread to his blood.
- Well, still, there must be precautions.
- Against what?
We have no idea what the next stage
of infection entails.
Even if we were to manage to move him
from the Gate Room into quarantine,
it's just a matter of time
before the infected area would burst open
and release microscopic spores
into the ship's air.
All we would have to do is breathe it in
and the same thing that's happening
to Scott
could happen to all of us
from the inside out.
Yeah, but you can't say that for sure.
But we have to assume that this thing
has infected Scott in order to spread.
One way or another.
It's what virulent, aggressive organisms do.
- We can't invite it aboard.
- Okay.
Look, um...
Please don't put this all on me.
I'm not.
Because he's one of the nicest people
on the ship,
and I just would hate
to be the one that's...
Lisa, it's my decision.
As deep a ditch as you can dig.
Then the barricade.
Doesn't have to be pretty, just quick!
Anything outside of that...
is the kill zone.
We gotta hold the gate for three hours.
Sergeant, we're sending a Kino, see
if we can get you some intel on this thing.
Hello.
Hi. I'm Matt Scott.
You're marrying me tonight?
I... I mean, me and my girlfriend.
I wasn't confused. Come in.
So, uh, I guess we just want to go
with the usual.
The usual?
Wedding vows.
You know, "Dearly beloved..."
I know what wedding vows are.
I'm sorry, I'm... I'm not all here today.
So...
To what do we owe this, uh,
partial presence?
Are you having doubts
about what you're entering into?
What, you...
You mean about marrying Chloe?
No, no, I love her.
I'm just a little hung-over.
Like father, like son.
My dad is a great man.
Anyway, we talked about it, me and Chloe,
and we decided to go with the regular vows.
They're all good.
Traditional vows it is.
Um... Is there anything else
we need to talk about?
I don't know. Is there?
I've been having this feeling.
I don't know how to describe it.
Something's not quite right.
Yes, yeah. Something is definitely
wrong here, and I...
To tell you the truth,
I think I'm... I think I'm losing it.
Have you spoken to your father?
Every time I try to say something,
he tells me everything's great,
- and I should just be happy.
- Ah...
- The sage advice of great men.
- But I can see it in his eyes.
Oh, I am scared.
Well, you know,
I'm not a great man, Matthew,
but I can tell you that fear...
Well, it's just one of those things
in this world,
that proves beyond a shadow of a doubt
that you're truly alive.
And I can tell you that you're alive
until you're dead.
You are going to die, Matthew.
We all will, eventually.
Well, yeah.
So, 7:00, then?
- The "Dearly Beloved" business.
- I'll be there.
Your whole self, please.
What we can see above ground must only
be a fraction of the whole organism.
The bulk of it has to be
like an enormous root system
that extends outward from the flora,
dormant until its prey gets close enough
to get stung
and survive just long enough
to spread spores.
I don't even want to think
of what it could do aboard ship.
What do you think it is, plant, animal?
Maybe properties of both, like coral,
except its growth rate
smacks right up against the laws
of thermodynamics.
It spreads upon contact,
and it resisted every chemical
T.J.'s exposed to it.
Hmm. Let's hope it burns.
Short bursts, gentlemen. Short bursts.
T.J., go to Two.
Yes, sir.
Are you sure Lieutenant Scott
is the only one who's been infected?
- Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
- Well, I need you to be damn sure.
I'm going to need you to send
non-combatants back to the ship.
The last thing we need is a mad dash
at the last minute.
Understood, sir.
T.J., that means you, too.
Sir, I'd like to keep trying.
Don't make me come down there
and get you.
I'm not willing to lose both of you.
Young out.
He's dying, isn't he?
How long?
I don't know.
He's strong,
so probably longer than we can stay.
No, I'm not leaving him.
Chloe, I just got orders to send everybody
but Greer's team back to the ship,
and that includes you.
- Tamara, I have a right to stay.
- No, you don't!
I'm not leaving!
Chloe...
Oh, my God.
- It doesn't look like it touched your skin.
- How did it get there?
Maybe when Matt first cut the thing.
It could have been a microscopic droplet
for all we know.
It grew right through the material.
It's a miracle you weren't infected.
Greer!
Over here.
You've got to be kidding me.
Okay, listen up!
Everyone not on Sergeant Greer's fire team
is going back through the stargate.
Each of you needs to be checked
for traces of the organism
on your person before you go! Eyes only.
Use the buddy system, okay?
Eli, that means you.
I've been checking myself every 30 seconds.
Just... Just give me a minute, okay?
Damn, we look good.
Is that you or Kiefer talking?
Oh, I think Mr. Sutherland would agree.
All right, they fit?
It's like the enthusiasm
just explodes out of your face.
Yeah, well, you did this to me. Go change.
Listen, Matt. I can't help but notice
that something's bothering you.
- Beyond the blood alcohol level.
- I'm fine.
I... I'm just saying that we've...
We've known each other a long time,
and I can pretty much tell
when something is...
What, you think you know me?
You're not that deep.
Look, nobody who knows you at all
thinks of you as a one-girl guy.
It's not a criticism, okay?
It's just... It's who you are.
If you're having cold feet, I think that...
No, listen, listen, I'm going to marry Chloe,
and we're going to have a half-dozen kids,
buy a house on my dad's street.
We're going to renovate it together,
play catch with the kids in the front yard,
and go to Brody's every Friday night.
You can videotape the whole dang thing.
Well..."A," that's a lot of tape.
And "B," I don't think
you believe that yourself.
Are we done?
Lf... If you can hear me,
I just want you to know
that nobody's giving up on you.
Sweep! Sweep!
I mean, you should see Greer's face.
He's taking no prisoners.
You'd better keep fighting, too.
Eli!
- Okay?
- Eli...
- I asked for one lousy minute.
Where's Chloe?
- Chloe!
Chloe!
What happened?
Now I have to stay.
- No, you didn't, did you?
It wasn't that hard.
- It doesn't even hurt that much.
- Chloe, why would you do that?
They weren't going to let me stay.
Now they have no choice.
- But now you can't come back!
- She's already made up her mind.
Look, I'm sorry, Eli, but I had to do this.
Go have someone check you out.
Hi. I'm Tamara, I'm a paramedic.
Your friends called 911.
- Why?
- You were on the floor, man.
Why?
A lot of things can cause a syncope
episode, but you don't have a fever.
He was hit by a car yesterday.
No, don't listen to him.
That was nothing.
I just had a little too much
to drink last night.
- You could be low on electrolytes.
- Awesome, let's go with that.
Okay, well, just to be safe,
I'm going to take him to the hospital...
No, no, no, I'm getting married tonight,
and I'm gonna be there
if they have to prop me up with a stick.
Lucky girl.
- I just mean I'll be fine.
- Up to you.
Just do me a favor and have some
chicken soup or something, okay?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Okay.
Whoa.
They don't like that. Come on!
How about this, huh?
You want some of this, huh?
How about some of this!
Bye.
Chloe...
Before I go, please tell me you didn't
do this to keep a dying boy company.
The organism got on my clothes.
I know it touched my skin, it had to.
I should have been infected, but I wasn't.
So you decided to test if you were immune.
- And?
- It doesn't hurt.
Matt was in agony by now.
Lieutenant Johansen...
- David.
- Hey.
- Thank you for coming.
- Wouldn't have missed it.
- How's your boy doing?
- Oh, he's fantastic.
You know, white as the plastic man
on the cake, but that's just nerves.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
It's true, I nearly killed him yesterday.
Ran right over him.
Oh, come on, I told you to keep
that thing out of my face.
Before the ceremony,
Matt enjoys a hot bowl of soup and
the camaraderie of his closest friends.
Has my dad showed up yet?
- He's mingling.
- Good.
Just make sure you get a shot
of Chloe comin' in.
Right.
Hey...
We can do this another day.
There he is. How's my boy? You ready?
No.
What... What do you mean, no?
I mean, I don't know if I can do this.
What if it doesn't work out?
What if it's wrong? What...
- What if I hurt her?
- Well, you would never do that.
- Oh, we're so different from each other.
- Can you give us a second?
Hey.
What do you want from me?
Just tell me the right thing to do.
What, you think I know?
- I'm asking you, please, Dad.
- Wake up.
Wake up.
Your blood looks normal to me.
No, but it's not normal. They changed me.
You said the chair undid all that.
Well, obviously she relapsed.
The point is whatever they did to her,
it's given her immunity to this organism.
Look. Look, I'm already healing.
A transfusion of Chloe's blood
could help save his life.
And pass whatever the Aliens
did to her on to him.
Well, I think that's a bargain
he'd be willing to make, don't you?
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered here in the face of
this company to join this man
and this woman in matrimony.
It is not to be entered into unadvisedly
or lightly,
but reverently, discreetly, advisedly,
and solemnly.
Marriage is the union of husband
and wife in heart, body, and mind.
It is intended for their mutual joy,
and for the help and comfort given one
another in prosperity and adversity.
Through this union,
Matthew and Chloe make a commitment
to embrace their dreams,
realize their hopes,
and to accept each other's failings.
We are here today to witness this occasion,
that marks the celebration
of love and commitment
with which this man and this woman
begin their life together.
If any person can show just cause
why they may not be joined together,
then let them speak now
or forever hold their peace.
Damn things don't want to burn.
I'm running out of fuel.
His pulse is getting stronger.
I just need a little more time.
I can't give it to you!
Please! I know it's working!
Sergeant, last time we dialed the gate,
did you see how it reacted?
We just got to keep dialing over and over.
- It may buy us the time we need.
- Not we. Just me.
This ramp is about to get crowded.
I need you two to get out of here.
- Sergeant...
- Go, go! Get out! Go!
Do you, Matthew, take Chloe
to be your wife?
Will you love her, comfort her,
honor and keep her in sickness
and in health,
for richer, for poorer,
for better, for worse,
in sadness and in joy
and forsaking all others,
keep yourself only unto her
for as long as you both shall live?
He's conscious.
- What the hell's going on?
- Stay down!
Oh, my God, his arm!
Are you okay?
- Well, yeah, but...
Come on.
Let's go!
Whoa! We're okay, we're okay.
Welcome home, son.
Thank you, sir.
I, uh, I don't know how they did it, but...
Unfortunately, I do know.
The three of you will undergo
decontamination right away.
Yes, sir.
As for the two of you,
you'll be placed in quarantine indefinitely,
until I decide what to do with you.
Sir?
I'll let Miss Armstrong explain.
English - US - SDH