This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
That ship is the best chance
we have of getting home.
- Are we done?
- We'll never be done.
You shouldn't have left him
on the planet.
You think I don't know that?
Everyone thinks we're safe.
They think that they'll never find us again.
Why did you take one
of our people prisoner?
We're not safe, are we?
They're coming.
Who's coming?
The Lucian Alliance,
they're coming to take Destiny.
There's only one way
this is gonna end if we wait.
I'm not
surrendering this ship.
I don't know
if you've met Ginn.
Homeworld Security wants
to talk to her now.
About the planned attack on Earth?
I want you to walk with me,
side by side, for the benefit of everyone.
Okay, so, what are we talking about,
some kind of code, a... a message?
We're all sitting here, ready.
- Ready for what?
Nothing that concerns you.
- We need to talk.
- I'm sorry?
I'm Dr. Amanda Perry. I...
I've thought a lot
about seeing you again.
This time is different.
Sometimes with the stones it's easy
to forget you're in another person's body.
How can you
just forgive him?
No, who says I did?
He's done nothing but lie to us.
I don't believe he
intended for Riley to die.
Yeah, but he was responsible.
And he's going to have to live with that.
I'm not saying he was right.
What are you saying?
That I'm trying to understand
why he did what he did.
- Something wrong?
- On the contrary.
So far, it seems like
everything you said is true.
About the Ancients finding evidence
of a signal once being broadcast
across the universe.
It is amazing.
A distinct structure
in the background radiation.
That sounds like static to me.
You were expecting
Stairway to Heaven?
This is huge.
It suggests more than a random order
to the universe.
Possibly constructed by intelligent life.
We're assuming you had no luck
deciphering any of it.
Is this the reason you brought me up here?
Well, you have planted false information
in the database before.
- I'm just saying...
- Actually, I'm consulting.
Part of a new spirit of cooperation.
As you may have noticed,
we dropped ourselves out of FTL.
There are three planets in range.
Conditions?
One's a wasteland, but two show promise.
Okay, I'll have a look.
No, no, you go on. You go get some rest.
- No, no, I'm fine. I'm okay.
- No, seriously.
I will tell you when there is
something worth writing home about.
Sorry to have bothered you. Go ahead.
Okay.
Thanks.
- Hey, listen...
- Don't worry, Eli.
Nothing's going to happen.
We can start gathering some Kino data.
Let me go to the Gate Room.
I'll put together some teams.
Yeah.
You don't have any idea
how much longer Homeworld Command
is going to want to talk to Ginn, do you?
I mean, it just seems like
they've been questioning her for...
I'm going to go to work.
Mandy?
Mandy, it's Nick.
This is Rush.
I need help, Ginn's quarters, now.
Eli...
Colonel, this is Scott.
All Lucian Alliance members
are accounted for
and locked down except Simeon.
Michaels was assigned to him,
and he is not responding on radio.
We don't know for sure.
It's never been confirmed
- that that's what happened.
...until further notice.
Teams of two, room by room.
I want him found.
Airman Dunning, come in.
This is Young. Please respond.
Sir, this is James.
Amanda Perry is dead.
Rush! Hey, Rush.
Sir, there's more.
Ginn told Homeworld Command
some things you'll want to hear.
Colonel, give me a gun.
Wait here.
- Oh!
- Close and lock the doors. Now!
Dial.
Two men are down.
He's locked himself in the Gate Room
with at least one hostage.
Nobody's getting in here.
Just, please, let her go.
Don't move.
Come here.
Colonel, this is Greer.
I found Michaels. He's dead, sir.
- Look, take me instead.
- No.
Shut up! Both of you.
Move.
Wait...
Mr. Brody, I need the door opened now!
I'm working on it.
- Where'd he go?
- He went through.
Wait. Wait!
Where is he?
He took Park. Rush went through after him.
Re-dial.
There's something on my back.
He put something on my back.
Let's move.
He's bleeding badly.
I need help here. Get him on the table.
Bag him.
I've got a chest wound over here!
- Is the airway clear?
- Yes.
Use the plastic to apply pressure.
You want to avoid air in the wound.
Hold it steady!
- He's bleeding pretty bad.
I can't get away.
All right, let's get this clamped.
He stopped breathing.
Do what you can.
I need a tube.
Talk to me.
Simeon went through with Park hostage.
Rush went after him.
Well, we need Simeon alive.
- Sir?
- Ginn told Homeworld Command
that he knows the details
of the Alliance attack
being planned against Earth.
The location of the base, who's involved.
He may be the only way to stop them.
Assuming he'll tell us.
It's a bomb, isn't it? One of theirs.
Yes.
We studied them, didn't we?
Ginn, she told us how they work.
This is Rush. Do not come through.
Repeat, do not come through.
I am attempting to disarm an explosive
at the base of the gate.
- Do you copy?
- This is Young. Copy that.
Keep the gate open.
I'll let you
know when it's clear.
Hold still. I'm going to try
and remove the cover.
Rush, this is Volker. Can you hear me?
You can't disarm it,
but you can remove the proximity sensor.
Yeah. Please shut up.
There... There's a fuse.
I know. I just...
These pinholes are too small. I just...
I don't have anything
that's going to do this.
I'm sorry, I... I can't.
Oh, God. Okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Get out of here. It's okay.
It's okay.
Wait, wait, wait.
Yeah.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- You all right?
Go.
Rush!
I've got him.
What happened?
Simeon killed the man guarding him,
then he killed Ginn.
Where is he?
He took a hostage through the gate.
Colonel, I swear, I had no idea...
Before he got to her,
Ginn told Homeworld Command
that Simeon had intelligence
about an attack
that was being planned against Earth.
Are you kidding me?
Ginn and Simeon were from the same clan.
Are you saying you know nothing
about this?
You know the Lucian Alliance are made up
of different factions.
There are many secrets between them.
If I did know,
I would have told you before now.
Is there anyone else on board
from that clan?
No.
Colonel, about Simeon,
don't underestimate him.
If I'm guilty of anything,
it's not warning you about him sooner.
He's not going to get away.
- Let me help.
- I think you've done enough.
I think it might be better
if you just let him go.
He killed three people, injured four more.
You'll lose more people trying
to bring him in alive.
He's dangerous. Trust me.
Stay, stay, stay, stay!
This is Scott. I'm okay.
Hold your positions.
- Are you hurt?
- No. No, no. I'm fine, I'm fine.
Ah, wait. Wait, wait. Stop!
What the hell? Rush, we need Simeon alive.
He may have intel
on a Lucian Alliance attack on Earth.
And you think he's going to tell you?
That's not my problem, right now.
I've got orders.
I don't care.
Listen, Rush, I get it, okay?
I can see how angry you are,
but you're going to get yourself killed.
You have no idea where he could be hiding.
Just give me a second.
- Lieutenant James, do you read?
Yes, sir.
We will call our position due west
of the gate.
I want two men left behind to
guard the gate in case he circles back.
The rest will split up
into two teams of three.
One will head southwest,
the other northwest.
Radio contact every 15 minutes.
Roger that. James out.
Do we send you back to Destiny,
or are you here to help?
Listen. Listen! We have orders.
Right now, we need him alive.
As far as I'm concerned,
as soon as the Colonel is done with him,
you can do whatever the hell you want
to the son of a bitch. I don't care.
If you don't kill him, I will.
Right now, there could be lives at stake,
people back on Earth.
They may be a billion light years away,
but we still may be able
to do something about it.
Are you hearing me?
Okay. We've got nine hours
till Destiny jumps back into FTL.
If we have not found him
in four-and-a-half, we are turning back.
Let's move.
Hey.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
I still... I don't understand
why he let me live.
Well, he's a soldier.
I mean, to him, this is a war
and you were unarmed.
What, you think he was being honorable?
That, or he knew
how much it would torture you.
Colonel Young wants us to stall the clock.
That's what I'm going to do.
Going to figure out how to stall the clock.
Hey. What can I do?
Hey. Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Look, I'm... I'm so sorry...
Yeah, I know. You did everything you could.
- You sure you're all right?
- Yeah.
- Where are we at?
- We're trying to stall the clock.
Hey. T. J?
Dunning, Graham, and Lougheed
are all probably going to make it.
Infection is always a risk.
What about Henderson?
This message you found
in the ship's database...
More of a signal, a repeating pattern.
- You have any idea what it means?
- No.
Obviously you think it's important.
Yes. It's important.
Its existence defies
the very laws of physics.
Is it a message from God,
the almighty creator of the universe,
as I'm sure you would like to believe?
Well, I don't know.
We'll just have to wait and see, won't we?
Let's go.
I don't care if the Colonel forgives him.
I never will.
Well, I'm not sure if anyone's
forgiven him, but maybe he's right,
that fulfilling Destiny's mission
is our best chance of getting home one day.
All I'm saying is, from now on,
he'd better watch his own back.
We have no control over the clock yet.
We're definitely not going to solve this
before Destiny jumps back
into FTL this time.
This time.
Well, we have to stay
in FTL a minimum of four hours,
at which point we can drop back out again.
Good news is we'll still be in range.
That'll be our last chance, though.
Not much time left.
They'll still be able to drop out in range.
Check it out.
What is it?
Some kind of animal.
Is it something we can barbecue?
I can see why you would blame yourself.
For what it's worth,
you didn't mean for this to happen.
I brought her onboard.
I understand why you kept the secret...
Why you felt you couldn't trust
Colonel Young.
But we're going to
have to work these things out.
All of us together, from now on,
learn to trust each other.
What happened to following orders?
Yeah, well, some things
are more complicated than that.
Congratulations.
I'm saying we have to try
and figure out what's right.
Not me.
Revenge isn't going to bring her back.
I know.
You think it's going to make it
easier to live with?
I don't even know
if we're going to find him anyway.
He could be hiding anywhere.
I guess the good news is he'll probably die
a miserable death out here.
He's got a Kino remote.
He'll probably wait for us to leave,
and then...
Try and use the gate to find his way back
to the Lucian Alliance we left behind.
Lieutenant.
That looks like a track.
You see him?
I think he's up there.
James, this is Scott. Do you read?
Go
ahead, Lieutenant.
Yeah, he's got us pinned down.
We heard the shots.
All right, good. That means you're close.
We are at the bottom of a canyon,
and he is dug in somewhere on a ridge
northwest of our position.
I see the canyon. We're topside.
Moving to flank him now.
- E. T.A. is five minutes.
- Copy that.
Eli? Eli, it's Chloe.
Can you hear me?
I can hear you.
T.J. told me what happened.
I'm really sorry.
Look, I can't talk right now.
What are you doing?
Are you in the navigation interface?
- Yeah.
- I told you to stay out of that.
Sorry, I just...
You know, this is complicated enough
without you messing up
everything I'm trying to do.
Eli?
Sorry. I don't have time right now. I'll...
Come and see you later.
- We need to drop out.
- So drop out!
- Just warning you.
- Great.
- Eight hours.
- Colonel Young, this is Brody.
- Go ahead.
We've got eight hours on the clock.
I'll notify the team on the planet.
One last time, to be clear, sir,
this will be our last window.
Understood. Young out.
Eli...
Just leave me alone.
Okay?
Lieutenant, we're approaching
his position. Stand by.
Roger that.
Rush get down!
Tell them to get back.
Tell them to get back!
Get back. It is a trap!
I repeat, it is a trap!
Take cover!
James! James! Come in!
Sir, we got wounded up here.
How bad?
Torres is unconscious.
Looks like Weber's arm is broken.
Corporal Lee, do you read?
Read you, Lieutenant.
Moving to cover
Lieutenant James'position.
Assist with getting the wounded
back to the Stargate.
Yes, sir.
How did you know?
I had a feeling.
When I stood up and presented a target,
he didn't shoot.
What about you, sir?
We can't leave you here without backup.
Stand by.
I saw you doing something
with that Kino remote.
Yeah, I was checking the time.
Damn it, Rush! Stop lying to me!
Okay, I thought there might be a way
for one remote to pinpoint
the location of another.
You knew he wasn't on that ridge anymore.
Well, I've only figured it out now!
Do you know his position?
Yes, I think so.
James, we think we've found a way
of tracking Simeon using the Kino remote.
Get the wounded safely back
to the gate and check back in.
By my calculations, we've got a little less
than an hour before we've got to turn back.
We are going after him.
Roger that.
Let's move.
Hey, Eli. What you doing?
Going to help on the planet,
and I don't care what you say.
I'm not going to be able to figure out
how to stall the clock in the time we have.
What exactly do you think
you're going to do on the planet?
I don't know. Something.
He's already injured two more Marines.
These are highly trained combat...
Do you even know how complicated
Ancient programming algorithms are?
'Cause Rush didn't solve it,
and he's had a couple of months.
I need you to get back to the bridge.
Even if I could find a way
to quickly bypass all the protocols
and add time to the clock,
I have no idea what the consequences
might be down the line.
For all I know, we may end up
burning out all our power
before we reach the next star.
Are you ordering me to do that?
I am considering the fact that we may
be able to save lives on Earth.
Only if we catch Simeon alive
and if he just tells you
what you want to know.
'Cause, really, what are
the chances of that?
Now, are you going to let me
have one of these weapons or not?
You're angry. Is that it, Eli?
I get that.
I also know that this is not
something that is in you,
and that's not something
that you should be ashamed of.
Now, listen to me.
Killing someone, no matter how much
you think they deserve it,
is going to change you. All right?
Don't you act like you are the only person
aboard this ship,
that has lost someone
that they care about.
- I know.
- Good.
I need you to get back to the bridge.
Here.
Got him.
Shoot him!
What are you doing? Shoot him!
- I did.
- Again!
What the hell's the matter with you?
You had him in your sight!
- Get off!
- What's the matter with you?
Rush! He did the right thing!
What is the point of being able to
track him if we can't catch up to him!
He is wounded now!
Killing him could kill countless people
back on Earth.
We are running out of time,
and you're dreaming if you think he's ever
going to tell you what you want to know!
Hey! Let me see, let me see.
Buddy, you're going to be okay.
It doesn't look that bad.
Rush? Rush!
Ooh, I've got to get you back to the ship.
Go! Go get him. I'm... I'm fine.
No, you're not.
You are bleeding pretty bad.
- I thought you said it didn't look bad.
- Ah, I lied.
Rush, you've got to listen to me.
Greer has been hit.
I've got to get him
back to the gate.
You were right. We are out of time.
You have to turn back. Do you hear me?
This is not worth it.
We need you, Rush.
Don't throw everything
away for this.
Rush?
She says she can help.
Really? How?
Well, you know Rush has been
giving me problems to solve.
Equations.
I... I didn't understand
any of it at first,
but I would stare at it for hours,
and then suddenly something
would pop into my head and...
And I would write it down.
Yeah, I know. Look, I get it.
You want to help.
The point is, I think I'm starting
to understand it, Eli.
It's like I'm slowly getting control
of whatever is in my head.
Or it's getting control of you.
You really want us to give her access
to the ship's systems?
Eli, this is me talking.
Please. I really think if I could just see
what the problems are.
Can't hurt to let her look, can it?
Actually, yes, it could.
We're assuming that any solutions
she may provide us
are what we really need.
Yeah, and not some subroutine
that could sabotage the ship.
The last thing we need right now
are those aliens attacking us again.
And that's what I'm counting on
all of you for.
Rush...
I know you didn't care enough about Ginn
to risk your life coming after me.
I'm sure it was that other woman
she was connected to.
You must have
really cared for her.
I understand revenge.
Your people have killed
enough of mine.
People I cared about.
I let you live. You know why?
I wanted you to live
with it, the way I have.
I wanted the pain to eat you alive.
I know it's a fate worse than death.
I let you live, but next time I won't.
You want your revenge?
You come and get it, Rush.
I'm going to put you out of your misery.
Come and get me.
Hey, what are you doing? Chloe!
Stop her!
It's okay.
What do you mean, "it's okay"?
What did you just do?
I... I don't know, but it's okay.
You said you were in control.
Yeah, I am.
Do you even know what you just did?
No.
- I'm sorry. I...
- You should go back to your quarters.
Come on. Come on.
Eli! You should look at this.
They stall the clock yet?
No, sir. Less than two hours now
until Destiny jumps again.
- And they say that's it.
- Dial the gate.
What about Rush?
I have information.
Oh, God.
- You're late.
- I know.
Nine hours late.
- How's Greer?
- He's going to be okay.
You?
You didn't answer your radio.
The battery died a long time ago.
You didn't come after me.
Eli figured out how to track
the Kino remotes the same way you did.
We saw two signals heading back
this way together,
figured one of you had them both
and the other was dead.
True.
You couldn't have known
you had so much extra time.
What in the hell were you thinking?
I knew Eli would figure out
how to stall the clock.
Really? Because he didn't.
What?
Chloe calculated a new FTL course.
She turned the ship around to come back
and get you.
Good for her.
You gave her those equations
knowing she might be able to figure it out.
I did.
Dial the gate.
Eli said there may still be
unforeseeable consequences as a result.
Well, there always are, aren't there?
I hope you were right about Simeon
not telling us about the attack on Earth.
I'd hate to think we
could have prevented it.
You feel any better?
English - US - SDH