I may be on the verge of discovering
the true nature ofDestiny's mission.
You've had control of this ship
the whole time!
Why wouldn't you tell anyone?
The Lucian Alliance is planning
an attack on Earth.
I killed Riley.
I suffocated him with my own hands.
You are a good commander.
There is no mission other
than getting these people home.
It was never about going home, it's
about getting us to where we're going.
That is the mission.
Ginn was strangled by Simeon.
And we received confirmation
that Dr. Perry died on Earth.
I think we
have a connection.
You're aboard the Destiny.
I'm Colonel Young. Who are you?
I'm Ginn.
If Ginn is in Chloe's body,
whose body is Chloe connected to?
- Chloe?
- No, Amanda Perry.
I do have another idea.
The neural interface chair.
We can isolate each consciousness
and upload them into Destiny's
memory bank.
It worked.
Thank you.
I know it's only temporary.
But for now, it's
the best we can do.
Mr. Ambassador,
when we first spoke of using
your planet's core as the power source
to dial the nine chevron address,
it was a scientific mystery.
Now it has become a necessity.
It was always your intention
to send people.
Not these people.
Not so unprepared.
If we could open a supply line
of equipment and relief personnel...
- Mr. Woolsey...
- The planets with the required properties
to do this are exceedingly rare.
What's more,
99% of the work is already done.
Your facility draws power from the core,
the Stargate is in place...
Twice this has been attempted,
and twice the planets were destroyed
by a catastrophic chain reaction.
The overload at Icarus was a direct result
of the enemy bombardment.
- In the second case...
- We acknowledge
there were mitigating factors
in both cases.
Nevertheless, our scientists believe Dr.
Rush's solution is inherently dangerous.
Which is why we asked you
to come here, sir. We have a new solution.
Ambassador Ovirda, Dr. Rodney McKay.
Ambassador, gentlemen.
This will just take a second to boot up.
There isn't anywhere I
can plug in, is there?
Ah, it'll be fine.
Knight to queen's bishop five.
Move it yourself.
Very funny.
You're not concentrating.
Well, I couldn't beat you
when you were a flesh and blood person.
What chance do I have now?
I'm a person, Nick.
Of course you are.
I mean... What I meant to say,
what I should have said,
is that you're more than that.
I'm still me.
What are you doing right now?
I'm here with you.
And?
And analyzing the structure
you found in the database,
and accessing the ship's sensors
so I can study the nearest...
Wow.
Okay. You have a point.
So much more
than a flesh and blood person.
Then why is that the only thing
I dream about?
I have the same dream, and you're in it.
There is a way.
Okay, good to go.
Sorry. Now, I'm sure we're all familiar
with the old adage,
- "It's all in the algorithm," so...
- Doctor.
- I'm going to stop you there.
- All I said was "so."
I'm not a scientist.
No, that's not a problem.
I dumbed it down.
There's no point in wasting our time.
No, I can talk very, very fast.
Let me ask you this.
If our roles were reversed,
would you be so blithe
as to put Earth's population at risk?
There's no risk. That's the point.
Hopefully once our own scientists have
had a chance to go over your work,
they'll reach the same conclusion.
There's no time for that.
- Colonel...
- The Lucian Alliance wants Destiny.
They know that your facility
can get them there
and you know damn well
that they will not take no for an answer.
There's an excellent argument
to dismantle the facility altogether.
Don't think that that will stop them.
They will move in faster.
They will do anything to
get to the Destiny,
and won't give a damn if they blow up
your planet in the process.
Then don't let them.
If we were allowed to show you that
Dr. McKay's dialing solution is safe.
That is the price of your protection
from the Lucian Alliance?
As a life-long practitioner of diplomacy,
you must understand that sovereign states
act in their own interest.
The defense of a supply line, for example.
For example.
If and when our scientists
reach the same conclusion as Dr. McKay...
No, no, no, it could take months for them
to understand the science.
Then that is how long
you will have to wait.
The Alliance won't be as patient.
I have no choice
but to hope that you're wrong.
Good day, gentlemen.
The Lucian Alliance got to them.
He just proved that to me.
We have to move.
He didn't even look at my work.
Because he wouldn't have understood it
in the first place.
You saw my presentation.
A cat could understand it.
And he knows
their government will only listen
to the assurances of their own experts.
We would do the same.
They've already made a deal
with the Lucian Alliance.
I seriously doubt that.
I can prove it.
- David, how'd it go?
- Pretty much like I expected.
Dr. McKay,
your reputation precedes you.
Some of it even good.
- And you are?
Sorry, communication stones.
This is actually Colonel Young,
commander of the Destiny.
You know Woolsey.
You said something about proof?
Not exactly, but close enough.
We've parked a dozen or so
listening satellites around Langara.
The communications are encrypted
in a Lucian Alliance cipher
we haven't broken,
but there's enough back and forth
to suggest
that some sort of negotiation
has been going on for some time.
Does the IOA know this?
General O'Neill briefed the chairman
and the president this morning
in an emergency meeting.
We are in an undeclared war
with the Alliance.
Now, if the Langarans have already sided
with them, they can launch
another attack on Destiny
at almost any point.
Without the benefit of my solution.
Which would make
dialing the ninth chevron
a hell of a lot more dangerous
for the Langarans.
So we're protecting them from themselves,
is that it?
If that's how you want to put it, sure.
The General's authorized
a mission to Langara.
What sort of mission?
We're calling it a "proof of concept,"
but before we get into that,
we'll need McKay
to run through his presentation.
- Oh, okay.
- Not here.
Who's this?
That's a good question. Where's Rush?
He sent Mr. Brody in his place.
He said you wouldn't care.
Well, I don't. Doesn't mean
he can do whatever he wants.
What's wrong?
Rush was supposed to switch with you
and go over your data on Earth.
- I thought I was here to talk to Rush.
- No, no, no,
you're here to talk to Eli.
You convince him, you've convinced me.
- Lieutenant, would you mind?
- Yes, sir.
I'll take care of it.
Rush, this is Young. Where are you?
- I'm up here.
- Right, of course.
We met at Stargate Command.
It's Vanessa, right?
- Yeah.
- Hmm.
- After you.
- No, ladies first.
I'll go.
Hey.
He ran into me, literally, a while ago
in a hurry somewhere.
He didn't say anything?
He said to tell you
he was taking the day off.
- What does that mean?
- That's what I said.
- We just found him.
- His vitals are stable.
There's some kind of program running
that I've never seen before.
Don't ask 'cause I don't got a clue.
Haven't you heard? He's taking the day off.
Looks more like he's taking a nap!
I'm reading delta waves.
Stage four sleep. Very deep.
So now I say, "Wake the bastard up,"
and you tell me it's dangerous.
Well, it is.
All right, well, let's find out what the
hell he's doing, and report back to me.
You are in an immersive
simulation program.
It's already in the
Destiny's database.
In fact, some of you have
already experienced it.
- Colonel Young's no-win scenario.
- Hmm.
It was already so capable
of hyper-realistic sensory input,
all I had to do was find a way
that we could experience it together.
And that's where the chair comes in.
In a way, you're outside
of your physical body right now.
This would've been no fun at all
if it was only in your head.
This way we can feel each other's touch.
You must have had to put in
some kind of conditions
in order for the scenario to play out.
That was the easy part.
The parameters are so simple that you
should be able to come and go as you wish.
So it's just the two of us, then,
in our own little world.
We have the whole matrix of the ship
to ourselves.
I think we could even take a shuttle
somewhere if we really wanted to.
Oh, really?
Well, maybe we'll try that sometime.
- Not now.
- Definitely not now.
Greer, are you nuts?
You just donated a damn kidney.
I just needed some exercise.
There you are!
Sorry, Colonel, he snuck out.
Listen to me, Ronald,
you're no good to me dead.
I need you to get back to the infirmary.
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
Yes, sir.
No, no, no. See, this is where
you are completely wrong.
It is impossible to make that deduction
because it falls outside
of the boundary conditions.
This changes the boundary conditions!
It doesn't work that way!
If you make the change, yes, it does!
Read the writing on the wall, man.
Listen, kid, one semester at MIT
does not make you...
Gentlemen! I take it there are problems
with this?
What?
He thinks we're talking about your
nine chevron dialing solution.
No, no, no, no, no, we've moved on.
Very, very bright, this kid.
I mean, in many ways
he reminds me of me at that age.
Of course, I was carrying
around a lot less...
- Hair?
So, it'll work?
- Yeah, yeah. I wish I'd thought of it.
- Thank you.
Great. Just to be clear,
without blowing up the planet?
- I'd say the odds of that are...
- Statistically zero.
Good.
Now, Rush's original calculations
were sound, don't get me wrong.
It's just that he was using a trinary
instead of a quad base,
- which threw off...
- I don't really care,
just as long as Eli says we're good to go.
Yeah. Yeah, we're good.
- Let's go.
- I just got here!
Well, you can come back anytime.
In fact, we pull this off,
you can come back in person.
- This is not over, mister.
- Bring it!
Brody bought McKay's solution.
- Of course he did.
Look, he didn't eat any citrus
when he was in my body, did he?
'Cause I am not feeling well.
I assume this means you're going ahead
with your mission.
I don't see that there's a choice.
Of course there is!
Clearly the Alliance is putting
something substantial on the table.
If we go to them with some sort
of a peace offering of our own...
General O'Neill believes the Alliance
will move in a matter of days,
whether they're invited or not
by the Langaran Government.
He also believes the Langarans
would prefer siding with us
- if given the choice.
- I agree wholeheartedly.
Well, the goal of our mission
is to make that choice easier by proving
that Dr. McKay's solution is safe.
Oh, it's safe!
Our secondary goal would be to determine
whether or not they've already made a deal
- with the other side.
- And if we find that out?
Well, then we will act accordingly.
The Lucian Alliance is not going to be
allowed to attack Destiny again.
I think I can speak for
both of us when I say
that if your intention is
to take their facility by force,
we'll have no part of it.
No, of course not, Mr. Woolsey.
We're going to give them a peace offering.
T.J., any change?
I don't think he's asleep.
He's in something closer to a coma.
- What's wrong with this guy?
You know what, T. J?
This timing sucks, but Scott and I,
we've got to do this thing.
You're in charge. Keep a defense
team in the Gate Room at all times.
- Yes, sir.
- I also need you to check in on Greer.
- I ran into him in the corridor this morning.
- What?
- Yeah, he didn't look good.
- No, he shouldn't be walking around.
Right.
Aside from "taking the day off,"
did Rush say anything that
might give us a clue as to why he did this?
- Not to me.
Maybe he couldn't bring
himself to see how McKay
improved on his work.
Look, I'm not saying he doesn't have an ego
the size of a bus,
but Rush would kill
to bring people and supplies from Earth.
So, what was so important?
I'm sure he planned to tell me
at our next heart-to-heart.
Just do me a favor, get him on his feet
so I can knock him on his ass
when I'm back.
Sorry, I didn't mean to wake you.
Does it have to be so hot in here?
It's not. You have a fever, which means
you're fighting another infection.
Good to know. I'll fight harder.
I wish it worked that way.
It does.
Here.
See, I feel better already.
How's Volker?
Great, for a guy who's sporting
someone else's kidney.
I really didn't expect you
to be the one who got sick.
Better me than him.
- Why's that?
- 'Cause I'm strong.
Yeah, you are.
But no more walking around, okay?
You need to sleep.
That's an order.
Yes, ma'am.
I got nothing. You?
There's hardly any brain activity at all,
it's like he's not even...
Go back in the logs as far as you can.
His present physical state
has nothing to do with this.
Holy crap.
Yeah. That is one hell of an upload.
Over 900 terabytes were transferred
into Destiny's memory.
Eli, what am I looking at?
The complete and unabridged
consciousness of one Nicholas Rush.
Feels strange with
no one else around.
Thanks a lot.
You know what I mean.
It must be different for you, too.
Yeah, it's hard to explain.
I mean, there are hours
when I feel oblivious to the fact
- that there are even other people aboard.
- Yeah?
Like when I'm looking outside of the ship,
taking in the galaxy around us,
and then at other times I can pore
through data in fractions of a second
that would take me hours
to read if I was...
If you were a...
What, a person, you mean?
I much prefer being here with you.
I mean, physically here.
Existing as consciousness is lonely.
Now, you needn't be lonely ever again.
You have no idea how happy it makes me
to hear you say that.
In fact,
if there was a way for me to interact
with Destiny's real systems,
we could spend even more time together.
But we can't.
The system is isolated.
It wouldn't be much of a simulation if it
had real-world repercussions, would it?
We'd best let Eli and Ginn know
for their sake.
For now is it okay if
we keep it our secret?
Yeah, of course.
I really need to go now.
Do you have to?
Well, for one, I've been away long enough
for Colonel Young
to start getting hysterical.
And another is, I have to work.
So, is there a door somewhere,
or do I just click my heels together?
It's even easier than that.
All you need to do is sit, close your eyes,
and when you open them, you'll be back.
Yeah!
And the shouting and the pointing
and the demanding of answers shall begin.
I cannot wait.
But you'll be back soon, won't you?
Well, you can always come visit me
in the real world.
I know it's not the same thing, but...
Hey, at least you know I love you
for your mind as well as your body.
Yes.
Go, sit.
- I'll come say good night to you later.
- I'll see you then.
Amanda, it didn't work.
Defensive positions!
- I am unarmed.
Mr. Woolsey!
You are not expected.
I am here at the request of my government,
bearing gifts for both the ambassador
and your chief administrator.
Should I call him for you, sir?
Not yet. What sort of gifts?
Symbols of our friendship.
Artifacts carved by the Ancients
themselves over a million years ago.
I would prefer it if you didn't.
You don't think I would allow you
to give something like this
to Administrator Halpurn
without looking it over first.
All right.
- Well, Captain? Is it acceptable?
- Looks fine to me.
Then may I present it to the administrator?
- Absolutely.
- Excellent. I know the way.
Ahhh!
- What is this?
- You're on board the Destiny.
I promise you, you won't be harmed,
and you will be returned
to your own body shortly.
Woolsey! What are you doing here?
He's brought a gift, sir.
For you and the ambassador.
I've already inspected it,
I'm sure it's harmless.
Captain, what you should have done is
instruct Mr. Woolsey
to return home immediately.
At least read the inscription
on the bottom of the stone. Please.
How is this possible?
That I can't tell you, sir.
Just stay calm.
This shouldn't take too long.
We pulling this off?
- So far so good, sir.
What the hell am I wearing...
SG-1 teams four and five
should be arriving in five minutes.
Well, let's go welcome
them to our facility.
It should have worked.
Well, there's no point
in panicking just yet.
Maybe you should try it again.
I have tried.
Maybe I can shut the simulation down
another way.
No, no, Amanda,
that's a really good thought,
but you can't do that from in here.
This system's isolated.
You told me so yourself.
In fact, nothing you're doing at the moment
is having any effect whatsoever.
I don't know
how I could have been so stupid.
Well, now, that's one thing you're not.
It's probably just a glitch.
Probably, but I can't leave,
and you can't fix it from here, so...
Right.
You'll be all right?
I'll be fine. You go.
Ginn! Ginn!
Eli! She's in the ship's memory.
It's not like she can hear you
any better or worse out there.
Then why isn't she answering me?
Why are you so sure she can help us?
I think I know what Rush is doing.
Because Ginn and I had the same idea,
and I think they talk.
- What?
- In their Ascension research,
the Ancients experimented
with the transfer of human consciousness
all the time.
- I mean, it's how the stones work, right?
- We have no clue.
Why would he do that?
Okay, so this is a little...
Night before last,
Ginn was visiting me in my quarters.
We were talking, and I said something like,
"Wouldn't it be great
if we could do more than talk?"
- You mean actual physical contact.
- Yeah.
- Oh, you mean...
- Yes, yes, that's what I meant.
Honestly, I was just thinking out loud,
but the suggestion did not go over well.
Well, Eli, she just died
and had her consciousness uploaded
to the ship's memory,
and you're just thinking
about getting your...
What? No! No, no, no, no.
That part she was all for.
Then why?
- Because she said it would be dangerous.
- Why?
You don't think uploading a human
consciousness and back again
is a little dangerous?
When I tried to talk her into it anyway,
she got mad, or depressed,
or some combination of the two,
and I haven't seen her since.
I'm sure the discoveries we make will be
of great benefit to both of our worlds.
Well, the ambassador and I
couldn't agree more.
We're happy to help in any way we can.
Our people will be dialing in momentarily.
Of course.
We have agreed
to attempt dialing the Stargate's
nine chevron address immediately.
This will be done to prove the viability
and the safety of such a connection
so that we will be able
to provide ongoing support to their people
on the other side.
Now, I am confident that
there is no danger. Captain?
A team from Earth will be arriving shortly.
We will give them
our complete support and cooperation.
Stow your weapons.
These people are allies.
- Dismissed!
- Captain, what's going on?
Well, I overheard them.
They've offered to share in everything.
Information, technology...
The administrator said drawing
that much power could overload the core,
- rip open the planet's crust.
- Yeah, he's good.
What?
He was bargaining.
I'm sorry I was gone so long.
I've been having quite
the existential time of it, actually.
Trying to perceive the difference
between this place and the real world,
and if there is one, well,
I haven't found it.
So you'll still come back, then?
Well, I have to go away first
in order to come back.
Well, that shouldn't be a problem anymore.
Never a doubt.
What was the problem?
Actually, it was Ginn.
Ginn? What has she got
to do with this, then?
I don't think she approves of this.
- None of her bloody business.
- I know.
But somehow her disapproval
manifested itself in keeping you here.
- Colonel Telford, gentlemen, welcome.
- McKay.
Dr. Rodney McKay.
Right.
With your permission, Administrator,
we'll get started.
The facility is at your disposal.
McKay, put us to work.
Right, you and your team check
to make sure the power relays
are still connected to the Stargate
while I hook up
their woefully antiquated excuse
for a mainframe.
I want somebody
on every entrance of this building.
It's a big building, sir.
Well, use their own people if you have to.
Should we have another go, then?
Bye.
We'll see.
He's back, he's back!
There's no need to shout. They can see me.
What the hell were you thinking?
I thinking I'm rather hungry.
How long have I been away?
Almost 12 hours.
That seems about right.
If you're going to do something
like this, you should tell someone.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Young is pretty pissed!
Yeah, well, he can shout at me later.
How could you be so blasé about this?
You could have died in there.
You can shout at me
on the way to the mess if you like.
I don't believe it.
Amanda said it was some kind of
subconscious act of disapproval.
Ginn would never hurt anyone.
It doesn't matter anyway. I'm back.
What was it like?
Entirely personal.
We're not going to be able
to keep up this charade forever.
How long is this gonna take?
I gave you my best guess in the briefing.
You also said you'd reassess
once we got here.
Well, the facility is already drawing
power from the naquadria core,
which speeds things up considerably.
On the other hand,
this is more or less 1940s technology,
which can slow things down.
Then again, there's the "They don't
build things like they used to" factor.
One hour or two, McKay. Which is it?
If we end this conversation right now,
I can still manage the former.
- Sheppard's right.
- About what?
Perhaps now would be a good time
to undertake our secondary objective.
By all means.
I'll show you to my office.
How can you possibly control
the power flow from so small a device?
Because, technically speaking,
as far as you're concerned,
I'm from the future.
Dr. McKay appreciates your help.
- What is it with genius and social skills?
- Hmm?
Never mind. We're good to go
as far as the Stargate is concerned.
Good, good. Just loading the program,
so 10 minutes, tops.
I'll just come right out and ask.
Once we've proven we can do this,
would you be interested
in joining Destiny's crew?
Well, I never actually...
I know that you can pretty much
write your own ticket
as far as assignments are concerned,
but there isn't a more exciting mission
out there.
Well, there is the niggling issue
of not being able to get home.
Not yet,
but we get the right people aboard,
return Destiny
to its former glory...
If that's even possible.
That why I need you.
I thought Colonel Young was in command.
Let me rephrase. That's why we need you.
Mandy!
I just wanted to make sure
you got back all right.
- Home again.
- I'm glad.
- I was worried.
- I know you were.
The last thing I would ever want is...
What the hell was that?
An emergency shutdown
of the FTL drive.
- Ginn!
- I don't think there will be any damage,
but I needed the distraction.
Dr. Rush is in danger.
I know, we've been trying to get him out,
and I've been looking for you.
It was a mistake.
She didn't do it intentionally,
but there's no way out of the simulation.
Who are we talking about?
Dr. Perry.
I tried to reach out to you sooner,
but she keeps stopping me,
or suppressing me.
It's hard to explain. It's taking all
of my concentration just to be here.
Why would she do that?
She's trying to buy time
to solve the problem
in her initial programming
of the simulation, but she can't.
The only way to end this
is from the outside.
You have to do it, Eli.
- How?
- You have to...
Ginn! Ginn...
Hey, what happened?
I sensed a potential overload
in one of the FTL drive modules.
I was able to stop it
with an emergency shutdown.
Very good.
So, should I leave you to your work
or can we sit and talk a while?
Well, I should work, really.
- I'll see you soon.
- Sure.
We have a problem.
- You couldn't find proof?
- Oh, I found proof, all right.
That for the past several months,
the Langarans have steadfastly refused
to have anything
to do with the Lucian Alliance.
It doesn't take that long to say "no."
In each exchange they've been
offered more, much more,
and each time they refused,
apparently out of concern
for jeopardizing their alliance with us.
I told you...
Woolsey, we had damn good reason
to suspect...
Yes, because of our spy satellites.
This changes nothing.
I believe it's for you, Administrator.
This is Administrator Halpurn.
Sir, I don't know who you've spoken to,
but there is nothing to be concerned about.
Everything...
Ambassador?
They're on their way.
Shouldn't you be trying to get me
out of the neural interface chair?
I might, if you were still
in the neural interface chair,
but seeing as how...
- What are you doing?
- Nothing to be concerned about.
You're dialing the shield strength back
all over the ship.
Yeah, not to worry.
No, you... Stop! Stop!
Listen! If the shield strength drops
below 4%, the ship will rip itself apart!
You'll be fine.
No! No, I won't!
Why are you doing this?
Because I haven't left the simulation yet,
have I?
It's time for me to find a way out myself.
This isn't the way...
Look, all simulations require parameters,
conditions beyond which the programmed
scenario can no longer continue.
If this doesn't stop it,
I don't know what will.
No, Nick, this is really happening.
You're going to kill everyone on this ship.
I don't think so.
David, we need to reconsider
what we're doing.
"Better to beg forgiveness
than ask for permission."
That's what my dad used to always say.
That only made sense when we could
achieve the dial-out before we got caught.
We still can.
McKay, what are you waiting for?
The program is running.
Listen to me, Everett, I need
to get back there, and you need supplies.
Sir, there's a sizable force
gathering outside the building.
Chevron one is encoded.
If I could have your attention, please!
For safety reasons,
I need all Langaran personnel
to leave this room immediately. Thank you.
There's no time.
We should stop now and dial Earth.
No! We can't quit now,
not when we're this close.
This will be a diplomatic disaster.
I give a damn about those people
on that ship, I make no apologies for that.
If we stop now,
we give up any chance of helping them!
And if we don't stop,
people will get hurt, David.
We've got two trained SG units,
plus you and me.
All we need to do is hold them off
until we can make a connection.
Chevron two encoded!
- Then what?
We stand down.
We explain what happened,
the whole thing,
but at least we will have proven to them
that it works.
Chevron three encoded!
Sir?
Do not fire!
I repeat, do not fire unless fired upon!
Everett, I do not want to hurt anyone
any more than you do,
but we've only got one shot at this.
- You want to get back that bad?
Not just for my sake.
This place can be
Destiny's lifeline.
Chevron four encoded.
We know what you're attempting to do,
and it will not be tolerated!
Ambassador, the Earth's delegation
has convinced me that there is no danger.
I don't know who you are,
but Administrator Halpurn
would never agree to this.
Chevron five encoded!
Our forces have been instructed
to open fire
if the dialing process
reaches the eighth chevron.
We just want to prove to you
that it can be done, that's all!
The choice is yours.
- Power levels?
- Well within my predictions.
- So it would have worked?
- Absolutely.
Chevron six is locked, by the way,
and I would not be standing there.
They won't shoot.
Colonel, look, I may just be
the brilliant scientist
relegated to shouting out the obvious
in terms of chevrons here,
but while I'm stating the obvious,
this mission is already a failure.
It's only going to get worse.
Thank you.
Shut it down.
There's no way
to shut down the simulation.
Why not?
- Because Perry's the one
who programmed the parameters.
Unconsciously or not,
she's keeping him there.
- So what are we doing?
- Ginn told me
the only way to do it's from the outside.
Dr. Perry pulled her away from me
before she got the words out,
but I'm pretty sure I know
what she was gonna say.
Why did you do that, Nick?
To prove that it wasn't real.
Why did you lie to me?
I thought it was some kind of glitch.
I thought it was something
that I could repair.
They could just keep your body alive
while I found a way.
You wouldn't have to worry.
So what do we do?
It's out of my hands now.
Ginn finally got through to Eli.
It was never her fault, was it?
No.
It was an innocent mistake in programming
the parameters of the simulation.
It was so simple
that nothing could go wrong.
What were the parameters?
I don't blame you.
For what?
Amanda, what were they?
That we love each other.
That's all.
That was the only thing
that needed to happen,
and then you could have come and gone
as you wished.
I love you, Nick.
- But you don't...
- No!
No, no, of course I do.
That can't be the problem.
It's not something you can will to be true.
But it is true.
I love you.
This wasn't fair to you to begin with.
I've felt this way about you
for most of my life.
No, no. Amanda, please listen to me,
here, now.
I mean, not the verdict
of some bloody program.
You don't have much time.
Eli has
already started deleting the memory
where our consciousness is stored.
You and Ginn?
It's the strangest feeling...
- Well, stop him!
- I can't.
No, try! Protect yourself!
I know you blame yourself for my death,
but don't. Okay?
Because if that hadn't happened,
then I never would have felt this.
I do love you. I swear it.
Goodbye.
Is that you?
- Yeah, it's us.
Yeah.
How'd the mission go?
They've agreed to release our people
in exchange for the defense of their planet
from the Lucian Alliance,
also the removal of the Stargate
from their power facility.
So, mission not accomplished.
- Speaking of letting prisoners free...
Oh.
They seemed decent enough.
I didn't think there'd be harm
in showing them the ship and crew
that they were trying to help.
I hope that was all right.
Lieutenant, in the grand scheme of things,
I think that was the best decision
any of us has made all day.
What happened? How did I get here?
You've actually been back
for a couple of days.
It just took you that long
to come out of the coma.
Eli, what the hell did you do?
What the hell did I do?
I transferred the memory
where they were stored into quarantine.
They're cut off
from the rest of the ship now, and us.
- They?
- There was no other way.
That's what Ginn said,
so that's what I did.
To save you.
No, Eli!
Forget it.
You need to rest.
In fact, you're lucky to be alive.
Listen to her, Doc.
She knows what she's talking about.
English - US - SDH