Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
RUSH: This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
YOUNG: We are going to survive.
We are going to make it home.
I'm telling you,
the ship came here for a reason!
RUSH: Destiny is powered
by the stars themselves.
WRAY: He and Young
are bumping heads, yes.
Not sure which camp is the better choice.
YOUNG: We just pretend
nothing happened?
We need to be ready
for the next encounter.
For the sake of the crew.
YOUNG ON RADIO: What do we got,
Colonel, Lucian Alliance?
CARTER: That would be my guess.
They haven't introduced themselves.
Any word on how they gained intel
on our base?
No. What about casualties?
CARTER: Twelve. Eighty-plus MIA.
I'm pregnant.
It's yours.
Ours.
Look, I know that we've had
our differences in the past.
- Yeah.
- It was my duty
to express concern for how
everyone else felt about you.
I've never even met your wife.
Telford, you connected with him.
This is a residual memory of his that
somehow transferred to my subconscious?
I would think you'd be doing everything
possible to get these people home,
to get yourself home, back to your wife.
And I know you're still sleeping with her.
Everett!
- You're up late.
- Yeah.
I just had a very interesting dream.
Everyone thinks
their dreams are interesting.
Nobody else cares.
Yeah, well, you're going to care
about this one.
I'm outside a warehouse, on Earth.
And there's birds.
At least I can hear them. Seagulls, I think.
I'm at some kind of meeting.
There's four or five people there.
- Who?
- I don't know.
I don't know,
but I'm giving them information.
Reports, files.
I'm talking about Icarus.
In detail.
Well, who were they?
I don't know, I...
They had a Goa'uld cargo ship.
- The Lucian Alliance on Earth?
- I can only guess.
You dreamt you were the spy
who leaked everything about Icarus
to the Lucian Alliance?
No, no, no, not me. It wasn't me.
Rush, what the hell are you talking about?
On the way back to the car,
I see my reflection.
It's Colonel Telford.
I was Colonel Telford.
YOUNG: Rush switched with him
two days ago.
The only reason I am telling you is
because you are the only person
who's ever experienced
this kind of bleed-through memory
after using the stones.
It was just that once, sir.
Certainly nothing like that.
Thanks, Lieutenant.
All right. Look, sir,
I understand that you have your issues
with Colonel Telford,
- but you cannot seriously...
- Sit down, Lieutenant.
Before he was assigned to Icarus,
Telford spent the better part of a year
undercover, infiltrating the Alliance.
You really think he would turn?
Eight months into his assignment,
there was an attack on a planet
that we had a large team working on,
P2S 569.
Thirty-seven people were killed.
Now, we later found out
that Telford knew about the attack
and decided to do nothing.
In order to protect his cover.
That's what he said.
Stargate Command let him off the hook,
and everything was
swept under the carpet.
- But now...
- Sir, there's got to be more to it than that.
We know that the Goa'uld
had brainwashing technology,
could make a man turn against his mother
and be proud of it.
It is possible that the Alliance
now has that capability.
Well, if they do, sir,
then we can't trust anyone.
ELI: Colonel, hey. We were just going over
some of the data we found...
Take a break, Eli.
- Secrets, you two...
- Now, please, go.
Okay.
So I talked to Scott.
He doesn't remember
anything like your dream.
Well, we have to do something.
Agreed.
Telford's still on active rotation
with the stones, yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
He's due to make a connection
in a couple of days with Dr. Morrison.
What if I take Morrison's place?
And do what?
Try to make contact with the Alliance.
It's risky.
It's a pretty good disguise, actually
being inside someone else's body.
- I'll go.
- No, that would be a mistake.
- Why's that?
- Because I had the dream.
Look, there's still elements
I'm trying to piece together.
For example, there's a number, 3-1-4.
Now, I know that's significant,
but I don't know why.
If I'm there,
in Telford's environment, then...
You're not trained for this.
Well, who is?
I'll just have to do my best.
If Stargate Command
is this badly compromised,
I can't tell anyone what you're up to,
do you understand that?
- Yup.
- Once you are on Earth,
- you are on your own.
- I understand.
- No back-up...
- I get it, I get it.
But someone has to stop this guy.
He can't be allowed to continue.
The Alliance probably already know
more about this ship than we do.
- Which isn't much.
- Well, I wouldn't underestimate them.
I'm not.
WRAY: Colonel, I need a minute.
That's about all I got right now.
Did you bump Dr. Morrison from his spot
on the communication stones?
- Yes.
- Without consulting me?
- Any particular reason?
Yes.
- You care to enlighten me?
- No.
With everything
that we have been through,
you really want to do this?
Look, Camile, I've got good reason
not to tell you, or I would.
You're going to have to trust me.
GRAHAM: Dr. Morrison?
Yes.
Welcome back.
I'm Staff Sergeant Graham.
I'll be your escort.
Right.
I want to talk to Colonel Young, now.
He is busy at the moment, sir,
but he said he'd come and see you shortly.
Why was I connected with Dr. Rush?
That wasn't part of the schedule.
Yes, sorry about that, sir.
It was unavoidable.
Why?
Dr. Rush had to consult
with some people back on Earth
regarding some technical problems.
You're a terrible liar, Lieutenant.
I'd like some fatigues.
No problem. This way, sir.
I need to speak to General O'Neill
immediately.
- And you are?
- Colonel Everett Young,
authentication 1-6-1-9-4-1-4.
Tell him it's urgent.
Everett, I'll have you know I'm missing
a national security briefing for this.
Sorry about that, sir.
Well, if you'd ever been
to a national security briefing,
you wouldn't say that.
- What's up?
- It's Dr. Rush, sir.
He's on Earth right now
in the body of Colonel Telford.
Probably hasn't even left the building.
- So?
- We need to put a tail on him.
Well, he's got an escort.
He'll ditch the escort first chance he gets.
I think we should let him do it,
then follow him discreetly.
- Why?
- He's about to try and make contact
with the Lucian Alliance.
Oh, Chloe...
- Oh, my God.
- MAN: What is it?
Chloe, I didn't know you could sew.
Oh, no, I can't.
Not really.
I hope it doesn't fall apart.
No, it's beautiful.
- Thank you.
- CHLOE: You're welcome.
Here, open this one.
Hey, can we talk to you for a second?
Oh, my gosh.
You made this yourself?
If it's a girl, I can make something else.
- No, it's perfect. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- What's going on?
- We're hoping you could tell us.
About Rush.
Going back to Earth
on the stones unscheduled.
Well, I'm sure there's a good reason.
Right, yeah, that's what we're afraid of.
They didn't say anything to you?
Young came in to talk to him
the other day...
They did kick me out.
Yeah, we heard Young went, too.
- He did?
- After Rush. He's there right now.
Something's definitely going on here.
TELFORD: Congratulations, T.J.
Camile, if I could have a moment
of your time, please?
Mmm-hmm.
TELFORD: Were you aware of the change...
Yeah, we could check those...
...control interface room
probably has something...
Yeah, I could meet you guys at the...
- That'd be great.
- Sure.
JOHANSEN: And the wrapping paper.
Where'd you get this?
If I'm not mistaken, sir,
I believe you've witnessed
the effects of this brainwashing technology
first hand.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's true.
I recommend
we keep the number of people
we bring in on this to a minimum.
Well, thank you, Colonel,
for stating the obvious.
Truth is, you took a bit of a chance
by telling me, didn't you?
Well, I had to, sir.
Rush was asking for a free pass,
an unscheduled,
unauthorized visit to Earth,
exactly the sort of thing he might do
if he was the mole himself.
Well, if he's the mole,
why would he be trying to frame Telford
at this point?
I can't answer that, sir.
And if he's telling the truth?
Hopefully, he'll still be able to lead us
to the Alliance.
And not lose his life.
Yes, sir.
RUSH: I've quite a few personal things
to attend to.
- I'll be a few minutes.
- Not to worry, sir.
I came prepared.
TELFORD: So, do you know
what they're going to do to Rush?
WRAY: They didn't let me know
until after the fact.
They're trying to keep me
out of the loop. It's not...
Where the hell have you been?
It's nice to see you, too.
Come with me.
We have some things to discuss.
Do we?
Privately.
We haven't seen you in a while, Colonel.
I hope everything is well.
- I've been on assignment.
- Of course.
I'll give you some privacy.
MAN: Yes?
Yeah, this is Telford.
I have some new information.
We have to meet.
MAN: Stand by for instructions.
Get in.
You're allowing alcohol onboard now?
I doubt I could stop it if I wanted to.
So I can report your command
of this ship is solid as ever, then?
I am doing my best to make it work.
Why did I connect with Rush?
Oh, we'll get to that.
I think we need to clear the air a little bit.
Have another.
I'm on duty. You're on duty.
Yes, and we're both
a billion light years away
from the nearest disciplinary hearing.
So, what, you're afraid of
what you might say?
I don't have anything to hide,
from you or anyone else.
Is that so?
I could've brought you up on charges
for assaulting a fellow officer.
You should just thank me and let it go.
Well, I think we both know that
you don't want the details
of that little incident
getting out any more than I do.
You cheated on your wife,
and she moved on. End of story.
You took advantage
to get back at me on a personal level.
You were sleeping with an officer
under your command!
I mean, look at you, Everett.
You're a disgrace.
But I'm here, right?
And that's what's killing you, isn't it?
Because this
was supposed to be your prize.
Your reward for all that hard work.
An entire year living with those criminals,
thieves, murderers,
pretending to be one of them,
I mean, that's got to take its toll.
I'm not doing this again.
The man I used to know would not let
37 people die to cover his own ass.
So,
what changed?
What happened to you, David?
Thanks for the drink.
Scott...
What are we doing?
We're waiting, what else?
O'NEILL: Daniel, come in. Do you read?
Jack, what is it?
Carter says they're using
some kind of jamming device.
We can't get a lock on anyone in the area.
What's your status?
They've stopped.
Looks like we're waiting on someone.
Well, ground assault is standing by.
They'll move when you call it.
Hang on.
Who are you?
I'm sorry, I don't know what you mean.
All right, who am I?
Whoever you are, you must be using
the Ancient communication stones.
I don't know what you're talking about.
You failed to use the proper code
when you called in.
Colonel Telford would never make
such a mistake.
His cover's blown. Move in. Move in now.
They have a ship.
BLACK OPS LEADER: Go! Go!
Yeah. We're too late.
CHLOE: You okay?
Yeah,
I'm fine.
What chance does this baby have
of ever living a normal life?
What's normal anyway?
I don't know, but I don't think it's this.
Look, I know right now
it seems impossible
that we will ever make it back.
But I also know that
since we've been here,
it seems like we're averaging about
five impossible things a week, right?
So why assume the worst?
Look, at the very least,
there are a lot of people here
who are going to care about that baby.
That's something.
Yeah.
We are all going to help you.
Thanks, Chloe.
Come here.
According to our intelligence,
her name is Kiva.
She's the daughter of
a Lucian Alliance warlord named Massin,
one of the higher-ups. Powerful and brutal.
That intel come from Telford?
Yeah, well, at least
we know who the mole is, eh?
There's an easy way to end this.
We cut the connection on the stones.
They get Telford back,
we're no closer to figuring out
what they're up to.
Dr. Rush's life is in danger.
He volunteered. He knew the risks.
That cargo ship
slipped past all of our sensors.
We have no idea where it's going.
Telford might, and he may know more.
I'm just asking for the chance
to get it out of him.
He still has rights, doesn't he?
He didn't say how he was going to do it.
With all due respect, sir,
you and I both know
the people who made the rules
were not prepared for anything like this.
KIVA: I'm sorry.
I know that really hurts.
RUSH: Well, I suppose it was worth it.
I had to make it look good.
Of course, I didn't give them the code
on purpose.
I'm not a complete idiot.
KIVA: On purpose?
What are you talking about?
They were getting suspicious.
Yes, I was beginning to have
concerns about that myself.
Well, that's why I had to come in.
I wasn't sure
whether I was being followed.
I figured if they thought
I was being taken by force,
it might help us salvage something
from this operation.
Nice try.
You almost managed
to make that sound convincing.
Well, it sounds convincing
because it's true.
If you really are Colonel Telford,
you'll know my name.
It's Kiva.
Good.
Next question.
What's yours?
A spy?
A Lucian Alliance spy?
You are so desperate to get back at me
that you would say or do anything,
wouldn't you?
We have proof.
Oh, come on, Everett,
this is all about me and Emily.
Well, how do you think
I found out about that?
You switched bodies with Scott,
do you remember that?
Yeah.
He's the one who told me.
He saw it, in his mind, a vision.
Call it residual memory,
whatever you want.
It seems that every time
you use the stones,
you leave a little something behind.
Maybe... Maybe that's guilt.
Maybe, deep down inside,
you want the truth to come out.
You're insane.
You've already confessed.
You just won't admit it.
We'll let him sweat a while.
GREER: Give me a shot, sir.
Won't take long.
Appreciate the enthusiasm, Sergeant.
Not yet.
I'd really prefer not to have to do this.
I wish I had time to convince you
that I'm not what you think I am.
Oh, yeah, and what's that?
I'm a reasonable person just trying to do
what's right for my people.
You make a terrible first impression.
We have brainwashing technologies.
I could try those, but I'm not sure what
they'd do to you under the circumstances,
with your consciousness
in somebody else's body.
Unfortunately, I've learned one thing
about torture over the years.
It's effective.
Barbaric, I know,
and I hate lowering myself to this level,
but I need to know who you are,
and beyond that,
whether or not you're any use to me.
Has he been given any food or water?
YOUNG: Open it.
Sir, maybe I should go in there with you...
No, no,
that will not be necessary, Lieutenant.
This is on me, only me. Open it.
You can't keep me in here forever.
No one's pulling the plug
on the stones, so...
Why don't you just admit what you did,
and we can move on?
I want to talk to Scott.
I have a right to face my accuser.
Oh, this didn't come from Scott.
You switched with Rush, remember?
Rush?
This is coming from Rush?
At first, I didn't believe him, either.
I figured I'd give him enough rope
to hang himself, but guess what?
That didn't happen.
- What's that?
- Airman Dunning brought it along
with his personal effects.
Do you recognize them?
They were all stationed on Icarus.
The fire suppression team.
They got trapped during the attack
when a corridor collapsed.
They all burned alive,
every last one of them.
No, no, no, no. No, no.
You take a good look.
Take a look.
I want you to look at their faces,
because you killed them.
You killed them as if you'd doused them
with gasoline and lit the match yourself,
and they weren't the only ones.
So we know that you are
a traitor and a murderer.
Now we know you're a coward, too.
SCOTT: All right, that's enough!
Stand down, Sergeant! I said stand down!
YOUNG: Get out, both of you!
SCOTT: Sir...
Get out!
Okay.
So,
where were we?
This will eventually kill you.
You'll be killing Telford, too.
That might just work out for the best
given that he's been compromised.
I have a full rundown
of the personnel aboard Destiny
and I doubt very much that civilians
or the scientists would have endured this,
so the question is
whether or not Colonel Young would
have put himself in this situation,
or sent his first lieutenant, Scott?
How do you know
I'm someone aboard Destiny?
That's a fair question.
You can make this stop.
If I answer your question,
you're going to kill me.
Either way I'm dead.
KIVA: I won't.
You have my word.
You have nothing to lose.
Rush!
I'm Dr. Nicholas Rush.
I want this connection cut.
I want to go back to my own body.
No, you don't. You're damaged goods.
You go back now,
your friends at the Alliance
aren't going to be too happy with you.
I don't have any friends in the Alliance.
Not anymore you don't.
Your only hope is with us.
You come clean now,
I will do my best to help you.
I am not a spy, Everett!
How many times do I have to tell you?
Recognize it?
Should I?
It's your work.
To do with dialing the ninth chevron
that leads to Destiny.
These readings...
Similar naquadria deposits.
We had some issues
adapting the equations,
but there should be enough power
to get us there.
You've found another Icarus planet.
Let's talk about the outpost. P2S 569.
We've been through this.
I was cleared of any wrongdoing.
Because they didn't have all the facts.
I couldn't blow my cover.
I didn't have a choice!
Remember that little combat engineer,
Sanchez?
Remember her? She used to follow you
around like a puppy.
She was hit in the first blast.
Right arm severed at the shoulder.
She's screaming, yelling,
begging me to help her.
All I can do is watch her
bleed to death in the dirt.
It wasn't my fault.
Now, we already know you did it,
but it's possible you're not responsible.
- What are you talking about?
- Think about it.
I want you to think about it.
Why is it that the memory transfer
happens only with you and only you
and no one else when they use the stones?
They messed with your head, David.
They made you think
that you were one of them, and you're not.
That's not you.
Now, we can help you,
we can bring you back,
but I need you to take the first step.
You tell us where they're taking Rush.
David?
Tell me.
KIVA: We've replicated it as best we could.
Olan!
Meet Dr. Rush.
Doctor.
Olan is one of our lead scientists
working on the project.
OLAN: Your work is impressive.
It was nothing, really.
When I found out
that you were on your way...
Yes, we're all very excited to have
Dr. Rush's full cooperation.
Maybe now
we'll actually make a connection.
As you can see, we've procured
some familiar technology.
It was necessary
to implement your methods.
I trust it will suffice?
I'll leave you to your work.
The figures for these naquadria deposits
are correct, yes?
- Of course.
- Because if they're out even by a fraction...
We spent months
doing a detailed orbital survey.
We mapped every deposit
down to the last vein.
All right, then, I'm done.
Really?
It's not that difficult
when you know what you're doing.
- But...
- I'm kidding.
This is probably going to take some time.
Oh.
Of course.
Quite possibly the rest of my life.
Huh.
Lieutenant, there's a lot of talk
around the ship
about what's going on in that room.
This is a military matter, ma'am.
It doesn't concern you.
That's exactly the kind of talk
that forced us
to try and take control
of this ship once before, Sergeant.
Camile...
Do you want the rumors to spread,
or do you want to do something about it?
It'll be over soon enough,
that is all you need to know.
See, that's the wrong answer.
Come on, Lieutenant.
Something tells me that you do not want
this on your conscience.
Better be careful.
Whatever it is, we all have to live with it.
I need to communicate
with Stargate Command.
- Do we let him out...
- Nobody in or out.
That is an order.
I want to talk to him. Colonel!
Progress?
- None yet.
- You must be joking.
You're stalling.
Well, if you want to blow yourselves up,
you go right ahead.
You along with us.
This is going to take time,
and I don't just mean a few hours.
But Olan said we've been close
for months now.
I assumed that with your help,
we'd be able to...
Look, with all due respect to Olan here,
his work is shoddy at best.
I'm sorry, you're just going to have to
trust me on this one.
The whole thing's a bloody mess.
I may have to start from scratch.
You call yourself reasonable?
I am.
You said he was incompetent.
I was stalling.
You were right.
I shouldn't have to demonstrate
how important this is to me,
to all of us, Dr. Rush.
No more chances.
VOLKER: Now what's happening?
We're not sure.
Young's been back and forth
on the stones all day.
ELI: Looks like this time
he brought someone back with him.
Who is it?
Welcome to the Destiny, General.
- Hello.
- Sir.
- Corporal?
- Sorry about that, sir.
This way.
Sir.
Who's this?
General O'Neill.
It's really him.
Okay. Let's say it's true.
General, I'm being held without charge.
I've been denied counsel,
and one of his men attacked me.
YOUNG: David, he knows.
He authorized it.
Well, maybe not that last part there.
This is what I've been trying to tell you.
O'NEILL: Time to come clean, son.
YOUNG: We need to know
where they've taken Rush.
TELFORD: You checked out
that gate address I gave you?
Oh, yeah. Dead end.
You didn't think
I'd give you anything real, did you?
You should see your face.
You look so surprised.
Actually, I'm disappointed.
You may not believe this,
but I was actually holding out hope
that it might not be true,
that there was some other explanation.
It doesn't matter.
You can't stop it.
Stop what?
Here you go.
I wouldn't say it was good.
What's it like?
I mean, we've heard descriptions,
but what's it like being there?
On Destiny?
You've flown around in spaceships before.
VARRO: Not an Ancient ship.
Not that far out
into the unknown universe.
Well, it's a rust bucket, what can I tell you?
I can't wait to see it for myself.
What if I can't do it?
What if we just fail to make a connection?
Kiva promised she wouldn't kill you.
Her word is good.
I'll have to kill you myself.
You think I was brainwashed?
I came to my senses.
We freed billions of people
from thousands of years of slavery
all over our galaxy,
and then we patted ourselves on the back
and left them with little
or no means for survival.
What the hell did we think
was going to happen?
YOUNG: This isn't you, David.
Wake up, Everett!
You think the Lucian Alliance
are just a bunch of criminals?
Who made us judge and jury?
People will do what they have to do
to survive.
You should know that by now.
We take whatever we want.
We do whatever is good for us
regardless of the impact on other planets!
What makes us so special?
I know what makes me special.
This is not our ship.
It wasn't intended for us.
Where are they taking Rush?
It was supposed to be
for the benefit of all mankind.
Wow. He's more far gone
than I thought, General.
Yeah, I've heard enough.
Should probably take it
to the next level, sir.
Go ahead and do what you need to do.
Communications Room, this is Young.
- Please cut the General's connection.
- Yes, sir.
- Sir.
- Dismissed, Corporal.
WRAY: Okay, this has gone on long enough.
- You have to cut the connection.
- I can't do that.
Dr. Rush's life is in danger.
That's more important than getting
any intel on the Lucian Alliance!
I just thought maybe we'd be better off
if she knew, sir.
Control Room, this is Young.
This is Brody.
YOUNG: Can you bring up the life
support controls for this section?
BRODY: I got it.
Begin venting the atmosphere
in Colonel Telford's quarters now.
- What?
- SCOTT: Sir?
Say again?
Begin venting
Colonel Telford's quarters now.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Camile, stay out of this.
He can't do this!
- Lieutenant!
- I...
David!
David, can you hear me?
It's got to be a bluff.
To scare him.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
ELI: Look, you can't...
David, I'm venting the atmosphere
in your room!
You've got five minutes
before you die of suffocation.
Your only hope is
to tell me the location of the Alliance base.
TELFORD: You're bluffing!
Kill me, and you kill Rush!
I know, but right now,
I'm thinking of the greater good.
So what's it going to be?
Young!
Open this damn door!
We both know you're not going to kill me.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org