I may be on the verge of discovering
the true nature ofDestiny's mission.
You've had control of this ship
the whole time!
Why wouldn't you tell anyone?
The Lucian Alliance is planning
an attack on Earth.
I killed Riley.
I suffocated him with my own hands.
You are a good commander.
There is no mission other
than getting these people home.
It was never about going home, it's
about getting us to where we're going.
That is the mission.
And if ever you were gonna have
a chance with anyone, this is probably it.
I've thought a lot about you.
We need to talk.
I'm sorry?
- Where's Ginn?
- She's on Earth.
Ginn told Homeworld Command
that Simeon had intelligence
about an attack
that was being planned against Earth.
Then he killed Ginn.
Amanda Perry is dead.
There's been an attack.
We think there might be a bomb onboard,
as yet unexploded.
I think I can help.
I can tell you how to defuse that bomb.
Have you heard anything?
Not yet.
Day six. Shifts running continuously
around the clock,
just like you ordered,
but still no connection.
I'm up next.
You okay?
Yeah. Just... Leg fell asleep.
Okay.
Checkmate.
Again.
You might want to put
a bit of effort into it this time.
Doesn't it bother you?
We don't know
if that bomb was defused in time.
You're worried about your mom.
I'm worried about everyone.
So, again?
Come on, take your mind off it
for half an hour or so.
Couple of minutes, the way you're playing.
Also Sprach Zarathustra.
It's the theme from 2001:A
Space Odyssey.
- So why didn't you just say that?
- Because that's not what it's called.
It's called Also Sprach Zarathustra,
Thus Spoke Zarathustra. It's by Strauss.
But nobody knows it by that name,
so why not just say the name
people know about?
Look, you asked me what my favorite
piece of music was,
- and I'm telling you. That's what it is.
- Yeah, I'm just saying...
It's the one piece that reminds me
of the very moment
- I wanted to be an astrophysicist.
- Right, when you saw 2001?
Yes.
That's my point.
That people know that song
- only because of the movie.
- Song? It's not a song, Brody.
Oh, it's not a song now?
You all right?
Yes. It's you.
You get me wound up with your stupid...
Hey, hey...
Colonel Young, this is Brody. Come in.
Go ahead.
I think we have a connection.
You're aboard the Destiny.
I'm Colonel Young. Who are you?
I'm Ginn.
What happened?
I had some trouble
breathing, at first.
Dr. Perry's condition
was difficult to adjust to.
- Eli.
Ginn?
It's you? Really?
- What happened, then?
- Your people from Homeworld Security
asked me questions
about the Lucian Alliance.
I answered as best I could, and then...
Nothing.
Nothing?
It's strange.
One moment I was answering questions,
and the next thing I knew,
I was sitting here.
What happened?
Why didn't I return to my own body?
Ginn, while you were
connected to Dr. Perry,
one of your people, Simeon, he killed you.
And we received confirmation
that Dr. Perry died on Earth as well.
That can't be true.
Then, how am I still here?
Heya, T.J. You burning the midnight oil?
Well, since Rush broke
Destiny's master code,
all these Ancient medical devices
are now accessible to us,
so I'm kind of taking
a crash course on them,
although it would help if I were fluent
in Ancient...
You okay?
Oh, yeah, I'm feeling a little
under the weather, trouble sleeping.
I was wondering if you could
give me something.
A good night's sleep would do me wonders.
Yeah, yeah, sure, hang on.
I got just the thing. Let's see.
Here. Just gonna take this,
mix it with water,
give it about a half hour or so
and it'll calm you down,
help you relax, and maybe...
It doesn't make any sense.
Well, obviously we don't know
as much about the stones as we thought.
Look, Ginn was... Ginn was murdered.
So, therefore, the connection
wasn't properly severed
with the communication device.
Now perhaps her consciousness
became displaced.
Displaced?
Floating around, like a radio signal?
Chloe just happened to be the one
to tune into it.
But why her?
We've had people on stone duty
around the clock for days now.
Why didn't any of them connect with Ginn?
Well, perhaps because Chloe
was the only one to fall asleep.
Her consciousness relaxed just enough
to allow an opening for a connection.
Well, I don't know, Colonel.
It's just conjecture at this point.
I'm sorry, but the bigger question here is,
if Ginn is in Chloe's body,
whose body is Chloe connected to?
How long have you been feeling like this?
A few days now.
"Few" meaning...
A week, maybe two.
Maybe a month.
Your blood pressure's high. 176 over 110.
I used to take blood pressure pills.
Hypertension.
I ran out shortly after
we got to Destiny.
Why didn't you tell me?
Well, there's nothing
you could do about it.
It's not like you could
write me another prescription.
No, I have medicinals that could help.
Tea leaves have been effective
in improving circulation...
T.J., I was feeling fine.
I didn't think it was a problem.
Hypertension is often symptomless
but dangerous.
Didn't your doctor tell you this?
Okay. Look, one of these Ancient machines
is used for diagnostics,
including blood work,
so I'm going to run a few tests.
I just think a good night's sleep
is all I'm going to need.
Probably. Let's just be sure, okay?
Nothing.
So, whoever Chloe is connected to,
they're definitely not on Earth.
Wow, look at that face.
That can only mean good news, right?
May I come in?
Yeah.
Your kidneys are failing.
End-stage renal disease.
All of them?
Kidney disease tends to attack
both kidneys at the same time.
Okay.
Okay, can we do anything?
Any of your medicinals...
No.
The problem with kidney disease is,
by the time you have symptoms,
it's already too far advanced.
On Earth, the next step would be dialysis.
Um...
The machines in the infirmary,
do any of them...
No. I already checked.
It's mostly testing equipment,
some devices for use during surgery,
but nothing for dialysis.
The only other option for treatment
would be a transplant.
Rush killed him?
Chased him halfway across a desert planet.
I wanted to go, too, but...
No, I'm glad you didn't.
I'd hate to see you get hurt.
Hey, I wasn't going to get hurt.
I was just so...
I had to do something.
You know, after what he did, I wasn't...
Whoa, no... It's just...
I'm sorry. I...
No. No, no, no, no, no, no. It's okay.
Believe me, there's nothing more
I want to do right now than kiss you.
What's going to happen to me?
Is there any way that I
can get back into my own body?
After you...
The next planet we stopped at,
it was beautiful.
We buried your body there.
Had a memorial service. It was...
Then, where will I return to?
I don't know.
I mean, we don't even know who
Chloe is connected to on the other end,
if she's safe.
I've been trying to remember more,
but I just can't...
What? What's wrong?
Ginn? Ginn!
Help! Somebody help!
Hey, hey...
You all right?
What just happened?
I don't know.
I'll be right back.
As far as I can tell,
there's nothing physically wrong with her.
So, do you have any idea what caused it?
I have no idea.
It was weird. We were just talking
and then suddenly, she was choking.
No reason.
Ginn was strangled by Simeon.
Now, brain function is really just
a series of electrical signals.
Energy which is no doubt the foundation
of how the stones work.
Now, she was murdered
before she was disconnected.
So, what, the energy was disrupted,
resulting in some kind of glitch
that made her replay the event?
Do you think
we should disconnect the stone?
If we disconnect,
who knows what'll happen to Ginn?
We may not be able to get her back.
Eli, if she has another attack,
Chloe could be harmed.
But T.J. just said there's nothing
physically wrong with her.
I just think that we should study this,
see if there's some way that we can
save Ginn without harming either of them.
I agree.
It warrants further study.
All right, well, let's go ahead.
We'll keep an eye on her.
Hopefully, this is a one-time event.
Sir, there's something else
I need to talk to you about.
Transplant? How soon?
As soon as possible.
Well, we can't connect to Earth,
so using the stones to bring a doctor
onboard is out of the question.
Yes, sir.
Given the obvious limitations of this ship,
is that type of surgery even possible here?
We have access to more Ancient devices
as well as a pretty extensive medical
database since Rush cracked the code.
Anything in there
about organ transplants?
Probably, I don't know.
I've just begun to search through it all.
All right, well, sounds like
you've got to get back at it.
Sir, listen, in order to do this procedure,
we're going to need a compatible donor.
Well, you have the records
of everybody's blood type.
We're also going to need to tissue-type
to get a thorough match.
- Okay.
- It's going to be extremely difficult.
There's not that many people
on board this ship.
To get an adequate match,
it's a long shot at best.
T.J., let's just... First things first.
Start testing.
Let's see if this is even possible.
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
T. J?
Oh, hey, thanks for coming.
I cross-checked blood types.
There's 18 people on board the ship
who are compatible with Dr. Volker.
Among them are you two.
It's not too complicated. I just need to
draw some blood if that's okay.
Let's do it.
You first?
I'm a Marine. We're always first.
So, what are the chances
of getting a good match here?
Well, it's a matter of degrees.
We're looking for certain genetic markers
on white blood cells.
No one on board the ship is related to him,
so that rules out the best possible match,
but hopefully we can find one close enough
that warrants doing the transplant.
T.J., you're gonna be okay.
You can do this.
Yeah, piece of cake.
How's it going?
Well, Rush has some ideas,
but we're still working on it.
How are you doing?
I feel different.
It's not like the last time
I used the communication stones.
Well, what's different?
I mean, aside from the choking part.
Something just doesn't feel right.
We're gonna figure out
what's going on here. I promise.
I'm not gonna lose you again.
- I heard about Dr. Volker.
- Yeah, tough break.
You know,
this surgery is fraught with danger,
- even in the best of circumstances...
- Are you compatible?
- Sorry?
- Your blood type. Are you compatible?
No.
I'm just checking. Go on.
Look, I don't want to lose
anyone on this ship, Colonel,
but the fact is, a transplant risks
not just one life, but two.
I'm not just gonna sit back
and let the man die
without at least trying
to figure out something.
T.J., we need you
in Ginn's quarters, now!
I'm on my way.
- Hurry!
Eli, what's happening to me?
Ginn...
No. Help me.
Chloe?
- No, Ginn.
- What happened?
- You had another choking attack.
You switched with Chloe
for a minute there.
Look, when you switched with her,
where did you go?
- Was there anyone else there with you?
No.
I don't...
I remember not being able to breathe,
and then I woke up here just now.
- Colonel?
- Yeah.
I checked with Corporal Barnes.
The connection wasn't cut at any time.
Really?
Then how was Chloe
able to switch back with her?
See, I don't believe that Chloe
is connected with anyone at the other end.
I believe her consciousness
has been in her own body the entire time.
Suppressed by Ginn's?
How is that possible?
I don't know. I'll have to further study
the communication device.
- We should pull the stone.
No, no, no.
We have to find out why
this is happening first.
- Not at the risk of Chloe's life, Rush...
- This is crucial for understanding
- how these communication stones work.
- Figure it out, okay?
Because the next time she has an attack,
I'm going to pull the stone.
- No, no, you can't...
- No hesitation.
- I don't want to hurt Chloe.
- Yeah, I know. I know you don't.
I agree with Colonel Young.
If I start choking again, disconnect me.
Hopefully we find a solution before then.
Solution?
- To the situation.
- Chloe?
- What's going on here?
Is it you?
Yes. Matt, what happened?
Ginn connected with you when you used
the communication stones.
Ginn? Well, I thought...
I thought she was dead.
- Are you okay?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Corporal Barnes,
did you just disconnect the stones?
No, sir. Still active.
What do you mean?
She's still connected to me?
Do you feel any different?
Can you sense someone else,
you know, inside your brain?
What?
- Ginn?
- Yes.
Oh, man, this is nuts.
What happened?
You switched with Chloe
for a moment there.
Wait a minute,
you don't remember it?
No. It's all so strange.
I feel weaker.
Here, sit down.
I'm sorry, can you just
excuse us a second here?
Okay? Eli?
Hey. What?
I don't know.
I mean, we can't be sure of anything until...
Eli...
Her energy might be decaying.
The radio signal getting weaker,
harder to keep tuned in.
Matt, even without disconnecting
the communication stone,
we might not have much time before
we lose Ginn completely.
How's that translation program
working for you?
Good. A lot of information here.
Some good stuff about organ transplants.
Hey, you see this?
According to the database,
it's a kind of a ligature device.
Cuts and cauterizes at the same time?
I thought it did something like that,
but I could never get it to work.
Hey, T.J., there's a whole section here
on stem cell-like procedure
for post-op anti-rejection.
It's only 176 pages.
A little light afternoon reading.
Still a lot of other
potential post-operative drawbacks.
Infection, high blood pressure,
erectile dysfunction...
Why is that funny?
After everything that's happened recently,
we can't be sure this thing's
even working properly anymore.
What is it you're trying to do?
We're trying to see if there's a way
we can intercept Ginn's signal
and download it
into the ship's memory banks.
Okay, then what?
What is she? She's just another
program in the ship's computer?
Well, she'd be preserved,
for the time being,
until we can determine the viability
of downloading her consciousness
into another body.
Colonel?
T. J?
We have a match.
Two, actually.
Tissue-typing takes a look
at six specific antigens
in the blood of the
recipient and the donor.
The best compatibility, obviously,
is a six-antigen match.
It happens most often in families.
The two of you, you both have
a four-antigen match with Dr. Volker,
which is surprisingly good, considering.
The equipment that you used,
how accurate is it?
- Because I want to make sure...
- I'll do it.
Sergeant, listen to me.
There are a lot of risks involved
in this procedure,
and you don't have to decide
right this instant.
- Think it over.
No need, sir.
I'm good to go, Lieutenant.
The Ancients wrote about a procedure
to eliminate post-operative rejection
of transplanted organs.
It involves removing bone marrow
stem cells from the donor prior to surgery,
and then implanting them into the recipient
at the time of the transplant.
It produces a state called mixed chimerism,
which is basically an immune system
that blends elements of both
the recipient and the donor.
You need some bone marrow.
So, go ahead and take it.
Okay.
I can give you something
to put you to sleep during the procedure.
Don't worry about it.
We're short on meds.
You don't need to waste any.
It's really painful, Ron. It requires sticking
a large-bore needle into your hip bone.
The pressure...
The sooner you do it,
the sooner it gets done.
All right. I'm going to need you
to lay on your stomach.
Thank you.
- No big deal.
Well, yes, it is. It's a very big deal.
You'd do the same thing for me.
Okay.
I'm going to need you to hold really still.
Ready?
That was a joke.
Just kidding...
Okay, well, knock it off.
Okay, okay.
The Colonel said you and Dr. Rush
were working on something
with the communication device?
Yeah, no luck.
Okay, so what's next?
We're kind of running out of time here.
- Matt?
- Chloe?
She's switching back and forth
more frequently now.
How you feeling?
Weird.
Tired.
This whole thing's affecting both of them.
Am I still connected to Ginn?
- Yeah.
But Rush is working on it.
We're gonna figure this out.
Is she all right?
Yeah.
Well, she's fading.
We're trying to figure out a way
to preserve her consciousness
without harming you.
I'm fine. Don't worry about me.
Do what you need to do to help her.
No, not at the risk of hurting you.
I won't let that happen.
No one will let that happen.
Did we switch again?
Ginn.
I'm sorry,
will you excuse us a second?
Look, how long is this gonna go on?
- She hasn't had another choking episode.
- Yet. Why risk it?
Look, man, I know you miss her.
I know how much it hurt to lose her.
This isn't about me, Matt.
I'm trying to save two people...
What's going on here?
Chloe?
No. Amanda Perry.
Mandy?
Yes, Nick. It's me.
I wondered if you were in there,
if there was any chance that you survived.
We think Dr. Perry has been in there
the whole time,
but both she and Ginn are fading.
Chloe's becoming more prominent now.
We're going to have to act
fast on this, Colonel,
otherwise we're going to lose both of them.
Amanda's consciousness is already
far weaker than the other two.
All right.
Well, do we have any solutions yet?
Well, I've had no luck
with the communications device,
but I do have another idea.
The neural interface chair.
Now, I believe with that,
we can isolate each consciousness
and upload them into Destiny's
memory bank.
Like Franklin.
Wait, like what?
I've seen and spoken to Dr. Franklin
many times now on the bridge.
So that's what happened to him?
He was uploaded to the ship?
Well, I can't say for certain, but I do
know that Destiny has a neural link
with the people on board this ship.
It's caused us to see things before.
Are you seeing him now?
No.
I managed to sever the link
shortly after your experience
with the alien battle simulations.
Always the chair with you.
Well, you asked for a solution.
Well, it didn't work the first time
when Chloe was becoming an alien.
Yeah, this is different.
I know what we're dealing with here.
- So there's no danger to Chloe at all?
- I didn't say that! Did I say that?
I'm going to have to remove
some of the safeguards
I put into the chair's programming, yes,
but I've done the calculations.
The chances of her being harmed
are minimal.
Colonel, this is not our decision to make.
You know, guys,
I've got to go stretch my legs.
- I'll be back in a couple of minutes, okay?
- Yeah.
I have never liked hospitals or doctors.
Well, this is not a hospital
and T.J. is no doctor, so you're fine.
Thanks, that's comforting.
Mmm-hmm.
All things considered, though,
I wouldn't want to be anywhere else.
- I hear that.
- Yeah, I miss home.
Sitting in the backyard,
warm summer night, sippin' a beer,
staring at the stars through my telescope,
you know.
I love that backyard.
All right.
You sure?
Yeah, I don't want to disconnect the stone
and risk losing them forever.
We need to do this.
Whatever it takes to help them.
Okay.
Hey, T.J., I just stopped by the infirmary.
Volker looks worse.
I know he and Greer are ready to do this.
I know you're scared.
This is a major surgery.
It is complicated, and it's dangerous.
And if you do nothing, Volker dies.
I do the surgery, and they both could die.
That is a risk that both men have accepted.
Listen to me.
I'm not gonna order you to do this
because you know that it needs to be done,
and you know that you are
the only person who can do it.
It's not permanent, Mandy,
but my hope is to find a way
of putting you into another body.
A fresh start.
That's been my dream
ever since the accident.
Where'd they go?
Who?
Oh!
Wow.
This place has really filled out.
As close to a backyard
as we're gonna find on this ship.
You and me? We're gonna be fine.
You can trust that.
Greer, where
the hell are you?
Took a little walk, T.J.
Gettin' some fresh air.
Is Volker with you?
Yes, I am.
A SPACE OD YSSEYTHEME PLAYING)
I thought a little music
might help you relax.
The theme to 2001?
Ah!
It's not very relaxing, is it?
No.
You ready?
How will I exist?
You'll live inside Destiny's
computer system.
You'll be a part of the ship. Literally.
And when I'm switched off,
what will happen to me then?
Now, that can't happen.
The only thing that we can
switch on and off
is the ability to communicate with you.
Remember, this is only temporary.
The SGC knows of alien races
with the ability to download
a consciousness into a host body.
Hell, the Ancient database
may even have information on it.
We just need to find it and figure out
a way to do it here, on the ship.
I know it isn't perfect,
but we can be together.
Just to see you, talk to you,
hear your voice.
It can be enough.
Can't it?
Ginn?
Okay, right there, that's the lumbar
vein coming off the back of the renal vein.
You want to cut that.
Okay, got it.
T.J., have you started
the surgery yet?
Yes, sir, about 30 minutes ago.
- Ginn had another choking attack.
Is she all right?
Yeah, she's okay.
It passed, but I'm not waiting any longer.
We've got to do the transfer now.
I'm going to be here another
four or five hours, sir. I can't leave.
All right, well, keep going. We'll manage.
Copy.
Go ahead.
Okay. Ready?
Get the retractors, please?
I want you to pull up.
All right, I'm reading two energy
signatures, each separate from Chloe's.
Now, are we sure that that one's Chloe's?
Well, it appears to be
the dominant presence,
so I think we can safely assume
that it's Chloe.
I'm transferring the other two.
- She's choking again!
- Turn it off.
I can't, the transfer's already begun.
- What happened?
I don't know.
Destiny's mainframe
just had a huge power surge.
We lost imaging, database, everything.
What's happening?
Must have been some kind of power surge.
Is it still transferring?
I don't know.
The mainframe is inaccessible.
- Anything?
- No, it's crashed.
Why?
- I don't know!
- What, did you fix it?
No.
The ship must have overcome the problem.
At least partially, at any rate.
There's still
several systems malfunctioning.
Well, can you turn the chair off now?
Yeah, but I can't be sure
the transfer's been...
I don't care. Turn the chair off now.
We don't have time! I need to finish this!
Hang on. I think I've got
the ligature device back online.
The database is still down.
Tamara?
Who are you?
- What?
- I'm Amanda Perry.
- Dr. Perry, how did you...
- No time to explain.
You need to finish the surgery.
- T.J., what's wrong?
- You're not real.
Listen to me.
I'll help you. I have access
to the entire medical database.
Trust me, Tamara. I can help.
- Okay, tell me what to do.
- Who are you talking to?
No one. I'll tell you later.
- T. J...
I'm fine!
Just let me do this. Go.
All right, the first connection
you need to make
is to the renal vein.
Attach it to the external iliac vein.
- Did it transfer?
- Yeah, I believe so.
Two new programs have suddenly
appeared in Destiny's memory bank.
One of them, in fact,
is active somewhere on the ship right now.
Doing what?
Okay, the artery's attached.
Go ahead and unclamp it.
It's pink.
That's good.
That's it. You did it.
- Chloe?
- Yeah.
I'm all right.
Okay... Okay.
So far, so good.
I started the stem cell infusions.
Over time we'll wean him off of it
as he reaches a chimeric state,
but hopefully his body
won't reject the kidney.
- We just have to wait and see.
- He won't reject it.
Great, no pressure.
Hey, you did good.
Colonel Young?
- Yeah, go ahead. - I need you
in the Communications Lab.
- David?
- Yeah, it's me.
We just made the connection.
We had a problem with
the communication device on our end.
Took a few days,
but our guys finally fixed it.
David...
The bomb was defused. Washington is safe.
Nicholas...
It worked.
Thank you.
How do you feel?
Free.
Have you peed yet?
What kind of question is that?
Well, the kidneys clean the blood,
they process the waste...
No, I know what they do, for...
Yes. I've... Yes, okay?
- Good.
Hey, you need to walk,
just a little bit around the infirmary.
Helps the body heal.
Oh, I gotta go. I'm on duty.
I'll stop by later.
I'll help you.
- Are you sure?
- Mmm-hmm.
All right.
There might be a little infection
setting in there.
I'm fine.
Yeah. No, I know.
Just gonna change the dressing.
I was getting worried.
I saw your consciousness
in the memory bank,
but you hadn't appeared to anyone yet,
so I didn't know what to think.
I know it's only temporary.
It is. I promise,
but for now, it's the best we can do.
I've thought about what you said.
Just being here, seeing you,
hearing your voice...
It is enough.
English - US - SDH