This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
That ship is the best chance
we have of getting home.
- Are we done?
- We'll never be done.
You shouldn't have
left him on the planet.
You think I don't know that?
Everyone thinks we're safe.
They think that they'll never find us again.
Why did you take
one of our people prisoner?
We're not safe, are we?
They're coming!
- Who's coming?
Lucian Alliance,
they're coming to take Destiny.
There's only one way
this is going to end if we wait.
I'm not
surrendering this ship.
They actually
built this planet?
That would make them the number-one
all-time advanced civilization.
Some of the people have decided
that they would like to
stay behind on the planet.
Whoever created this planet
will provide for us.
They are our best chance
of getting back home.
I am leaving
the damaged shuttle behind.
You can use it for shelter and power.
All military personnel will return with me.
My skin's changing.
It's coarse. And it's growing.
Our baby is still alive.
Just because you want something to be true
it doesn't mean it is, T.J.
Hmm, not much to look at,
is it?
Well... Well, it depends what you see.
I see a sign of intelligence that cannot
possibly have been there
by any current description of the universe,
and yet, there it is.
I see the greatest mystery of all time.
Really?
Look, if you can't fix that thing,
I don't know what we're doin' here.
Keep your pants on.
Okay, I got it this time.
- What?
- Nothing. Cheers.
Brody, looks like we just came out of FTL.
What's going on?
This is Volker.
Brody had to fix the still,
so we switched shifts.
I know you hate that.
I don't care. Speak.
Okay, well, we've got a couple of
gate addresses popping up.
Holy cow, do you see that?
Yeah, I do.
It looks like our shuttle.
Yes, it does.
Rush, this is Young.
Meet me on the bridge. Now.
What's it doing?
Nothing. It's just matching
our velocity off the right side.
Where did that thing come from?
I don't know. One minute it wasn't there,
the next minute it was.
What's happened?
It just came out of nowhere.
Is that the shuttle?
Yeah, seems like it.
No, I wasn't drinking, I was fixing it.
Hello?
Can anyone hear me? Hello?
That sounds like Caine.
Caine's more monotone than that.
He's also in another galaxy.
Hello? This is Robert Caine.
We can see the Destiny.
What should we do?
How?
This is Colonel Young. As far as we know,
Dr. Caine and a number of other people are
on a planet thousands of light years away.
And as far as we remember, Colonel
, that was where we still were
when we went to sleep last night.
Look, the shuttle we left you wasn't
capable of leaving the atmosphere,
let alone fly between galaxies.
We understand that, Dr. Rush,
but here we are.
The others are with you?
Yes, all of us.
Which brings me back to "how?"
Honestly? I have no idea.
- Lieutenant Scott, report to the bridge.
- Yes, sir.
How could they have known when or where
we were going to come out of FTL?
Or for that matter, drop them
right beside us? This is impossible.
- There they are.
- If it's them.
That's a fair question.
Do you think that we could electronically
compare the voice we are getting
from the shuttle to an old Kino recording
of Caine?
Okay, trust me, these aliens built
a planet from scratch
and can just throw a shuttle
between galaxies.
I'm pretty sure they could impersonate
Caine if they wanted to.
Boone used to do a pretty good Caine.
I thought it was the other way around.
So, what, we take them for their word?
They are who they say they are,
and ignore the possibility
that this could be a ruse
to get by our defenses?
Like a Trojan horse?
Well, the truth is, with aliens that can
do this, defenses are meaningless.
Wouldn't mind having
a working shuttle again.
There is that. I suggest we invite them
on board and take every precaution.
Sorry for the delay, Dr. Caine. I've asked
Lieutenant Scott to come and help
talk you through the docking procedure.
I don't even drive a car.
Just what a Trojan would say.
The guys in the horse were Greek.
- Well, why is it "Trojan" horse, then?
- Because that's what...
They're from Troy.
Are you guys done?
Don't worry, Dr. Caine,
we'll take it nice and slow.
This is Greer. Ready and standing by.
I am on my way.
Is it them? I just ran into Eli.
Well, Eli's got a big mouth.
You don't need to be here.
- Try and stop me.
- Listen to me, T.J.,
- I know what you must be thinking...
- You should have told me...
What you experienced was a simulation,
we know that.
No, you know that.
Look, I'm just saying,
if they can send our people back to us,
don't you think it's possible
they could save our daughter?
Nobody mentioned a child.
I don't want you to set yourself up.
I need to know.
All right, Dr.
Caine, what we want now
is one short burst from
the forward maneuvering thrusters
just to set her down, and we are home.
Just a kiss, now.
All right, good. Good job. You got it.
I can lock you down from here.
Stand by for egress.
Docking clamps in place, sir.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Hi.
Colonel Young.
This must be just as much
a surprise to you.
You have no idea.
You will exit the shuttle
one person at a time.
Sergeant Greer and members of his team
will escort you to a holding area.
Move quickly, talk to no one,
touch nothing.
I don't understand. You know us.
We're not a threat.
And I'm glad to hear that. Sergeant.
After you. Sir.
One at a time, please.
Peter!
Val!
You all right?
I'm fine.
I'm losing Chloe.
I mean, she's losing herself,
and we can't stop it.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Did you hear the news?
Dr. Caine and the bunch that stayed back
on that planet, they came back.
- How?
- Hell if I know.
They don't even know.
I guess we'll find out.
We've got a shuttle again, though,
so you gotta like that.
Can I get you anything?
- No.
- Okay.
You're trying so hard,
but every time I look at your face,
you can't hide it.
What?
That you're not looking at me anymore,
at least not as the person I used to be.
- You see the other.
- Chloe...
No, it's just your
inability to lie, Matthew.
It's one of the best things about you,
but I know what you see.
I see it, too.
This is new this morning.
We're gonna fix this.
- I don't even know if I want you to.
- Yeah, you do.
I'm hardly blacking out anymore.
The new part of me is just there,
in the foreground.
I'm not afraid of it anymore.
You have to fight it.
I think we're past that.
So that's the last thing you
remember, going to sleep in the shuttle?
And that it was cold, it was winter.
We were using it as a shelter.
I remember closing my eyes,
and then we were delivered here
by a greater power.
The aliens who created the planet,
you mean.
Or by Providence.
Are you suggesting that God did this?
Is that you, Camile?
Yes.
It's nice to hear your voice.
Well, of course there's no way
of knowing His will,
but I do know that I prayed every
night before I went to sleep
that He would keep us safe.
So, magic then.
You have to admit that our arrival here
is nothing less than miraculous, Eli.
"Any sufficiently advanced technology
is indistinguishable from magic,"
Arthur C. Clarke.
"Turn the mic back on." Winston Churchill.
Really?
- Are you going to keep us here?
- We haven't done anything.
Try to be patient.
You'll be released
once you've all undergone
a physical examination one at a time.
But we're perfectly fine.
Well, forgive me if I don't take
your word for that.
The more answers we have,
the less precautions we'll have to take.
Let's keep an eye on them.
What do you think?
Well, it appears to have been
completely restored.
Brand spankin' new, more like it.
Every part, every system,
every square inch of this thing is
in perfect factory condition.
Even has that new shuttle smell.
Again, how?
Well, I don't know,
but it could be invaluable to the mission.
So, nothing to be concerned about?
No ticking time bombs?
Alien transmissions?
No, sir. At least not yet, anyway.
Let's keep looking.
They're all in perfect health.
No trace of disease or malnutrition.
Just like the day we left them.
What are the odds of that?
Eight adults who've been through
what they've been through?
You know, not one of them remembers
a damn thing about the planet,
or how they got here.
Well, Caine believes that's God's way
of telling them they've been reborn.
Was that before or after
He gave them amnesia?
The others think that maybe
the aliens discovered them
and returned them to us as
an act of benevolence.
Well, that's nice.
- You're not buying it?
- No, these aliens are too damn powerful.
I mean, building planets,
rebuilding shuttles? They could...
They could squash us like ants
if they wanted to.
- That scares you?
- Yes.
But what scares me even more is the
feeling I got when I looked him in the eye.
I thought it was just me.
I should be welcoming them
with open arms,
but I can't be in a room with any of them
for more than a minute
before I want to get the hell away.
- Why?
- I don't know, but I want to find out.
Go ahead.
Okay. Um...
I don't know how much longer I'm going
to be me. It's kind of hard to explain...
You don't have to.
Everybody understands.
- So I should just do this?
Yeah.
Who should I start with?
Somebody easy. I'm right here.
Start with me.
Okay.
Eli, you've been the most...
Wait, what do you mean
start with someone easy?
You're the hardest to say goodbye to
out of everyone!
Okay, okay, pick somebody else. Chloe?
Chloe!
You can all return
to your original quarters.
You will be given a list of duties to help
carry your weight as members of this crew.
Is this as close as we're going to get to
"welcome aboard"?
Yeah, it is. Right now I don't have
any reason to treat you like prisoners.
- Thank you.
- Don't give me a reason.
Hey.
Young finally let us out.
Yeah, that's good.
I've got a shift in hydroponics.
What's wrong?
Don't touch me.
What was that all about?
I see you haven't spent time
with the new arrivals.
No.
Eight science types,
no survival skills.
I've seen a lot of people go in my time
and I know I'm going to see more
before I'm done here.
I have never seen anyone come back.
Until now.
Okay, you're being too deep again.
Hi.
Hey. Good morning.
We were just remarking at how different
the food tastes here than on Eden.
That's what we called the planet.
- I hope you stayed away from the apples.
- Right.
We're actually growing more and more
of our own food.
- If you like, I could show you.
- Yeah.
Incredible.
It's a start.
Soon it'll be a garden.
I wanted to talk to you about something.
I... I have a memory.
Well, lucky you.
A vivid memory that I visited you
on the planet with my daughter.
Your daughter?
When we first arrived at the planet,
I was pregnant, remember?
I do remember.
It was winter,
and you were living in cabins.
You told me that they were provided
by the aliens who created the planet.
I told you?
And that my daughter was safe,
and you would take care of her.
I don't remember anything like that,
Tamara. I'm sorry.
I wish I did.
It was so real.
How about the day before that?
Let's say in the morning when you
woke up. Was it raining, snowing?
I don't know.
Doesn't it bother you that
you don't remember anything
but the most generic things from
your experience on that planet?
Just gathering food and fuel?
Maybe that's all we did.
Oh, come on, Peter.
You have to remember more than that.
You were there for months.
I could show you some of the others, but
the conversation is more or less the same.
So you think their memories
have been tampered with?
I guess it could be a side effect of
whatever mechanism transported them here,
but I'm starting to think that maybe
the aliens didn't want our people
to remember something.
The whole thing to me feels like
a damn science experiment.
They're still our people.
They don't creep you out? Even a little?
Well, a lot of people creep me out a
little, so I'm not the best person to ask.
- Really?
- A little.
Me?
Not as much now.
Hmm, that's good. Progress.
Well, keep at it.
They've got to remember something.
- Oh, hey, brother.
- Hi.
- Off duty?
- Yeah, long day.
Long day.
- You... You gonna go see Chloe?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
What's wrong with that?
I'm not stoppin' you.
Go.
All right, look, she's alone in there
all damn day.
The only time she's got company
is when I come to see her.
That must be hard for her.
I'm just sayin' it wouldn't hurt, you know,
if people went to see her.
She's alone for a reason. I mean,
whether you want to admit it or not,
there's a freak show going on in there.
You are outta line, Greer.
No, sir, I'm not, because it is part of
my job as a Master Sergeant to see to it
that butter-bar Lieutenants like yourself
don't make mistakes.
What did you just call me?
You heard me.
Okay, Master Sergeant, you tell me what is
so wrong with giving that girl comfort
in what might be her last few days?
Because you don't know when
that day's gonna be.
You don't know how much I care about her.
I think I do, and you're not the only one.
I pray for her every single night,
but that girl is turning into the enemy.
And the day is gonna come.
Hey. Mind if I...
So many of you are keeping your distance
from us, I appreciate it.
They're all boring.
You're not missing a thing.
So, the planet you guys...
I heard you called it Eden.
- We did.
- I never got to go.
Everybody said it was amazing.
Do you miss it?
Honestly, my memory of it is just now
coming back to me in pieces.
Hey, at least it's coming back.
In flashes. Just moments, you know?
In fact, the strangest memory came
back to me when I was sitting here.
What?
I'd be embarrassed to say it.
Well, now I have to know.
Skinny-dipping. There was a lake...
Yeah, no... I've heard about it already.
People were doing that before you guys
decided to stay.
That's right.
What about when you were alone?
You must have checked out
the obelisk, right?
I don't...
- It was there the whole time.
- I...
Whoa. Your nose is bleeding.
What's happening?
We need help over here!
Somebody get help!
Dr. Rush.
Found you. Hey.
I see we've come out of FTL.
Anything interesting out there?
There's always something interesting
out there.
I've just been going over
the shuttle's navigational data,
trying to figure out the path you took
back to Destiny.
And?
Well, it seems you were there
and then you were here.
Nothing in between.
I wish I could help you with that, but I
fell asleep there, and I woke up here.
Yeah.
Listen, I heard that you've learned
what Destiny's original mission was.
Yes, we have.
In search of a message from
the moment of creation.
I don't know about "message."
"Fingerprints" might be a better word.
A sign that some intelligence
may have had a hand in all of this.
The hand of God?
I don't know about that either,
I'm afraid. I'm a scientist.
I'd go so far as to call it evidence
of an intelligence having existed
prior to its own potential to exist.
You just can't bring yourself to call it
a miracle, can you?
No, actually.
- Well, I'd like to hear more.
- Oh, why bother?
Call it God's will
and you needn't give it another thought.
He must have brought us here for a reason.
He must have saved us for a reason.
Yeah, saved from what? Do you remember?
I mean, the burning bush spoke to Moses?
Gabriel, was it, spoke to Abraham, yet you,
you were returned here with no proof
of your savior one way or the other.
I'll leave you to your work.
Let me ask you...
The shuttle was restored to
its original condition
by the aliens who sent you here,
better than it was before, even.
Well, that sounds to me more like
the work of God than aliens.
Well, if this shuttle has been restored
so perfectly, then why weren't all of you?
I mean, Norris wasn't born
with astigmatism, was he?
Mr. Chan surely had a full head of hair
at one time.
All of you have enormous gaps
in your memory.
What's your point?
Well, either He's lost his touch,
or God's got nothing to do with this.
Rush, this is Young.
Is Caine with you?
Yeah, go ahead.
Tell him to come to the infirmary.
Val is dead.
It was a severe head trauma,
as bad as if she was struck
with a sledgehammer.
There's nothing anyone could've done.
- What happened?
Nothing.
She just grabbed her head,
and her nose started to bleed.
Are you sure?
She was just talking with Eli
in the observation room.
There were witnesses.
She was already dead
when we got there.
And still there's evidence of skull
fracture, hemorrhage, brain swelling.
- I don't understand.
Neither do we.
Something caused this. A blunt force
injury doesn't happen spontaneously.
Something that happened on the planet?
I don't know. I wish I did, I swear.
Look, this might be a long shot,
but I'd like to put you and the others
from the shuttle under hypnosis.
See if I can stimulate memories
from your subconscious.
The IOA teach you that?
Yeah, they did.
Anything else I should know about?
That I was a little overqualified for HR?
I say we do it.
I'd like to tell the
others about Val first.
Yeah, of course.
In the meantime,
I'll take a shot at an autopsy.
Maybe I missed something
in the observation.
I don't think you missed anything.
I don't think so either, but I don't really
know what else I can do.
Hey, listen, you're doing good.
Actually, I'm not.
Come in.
How are you?
Still me. Mostly, anyway.
Good to know.
Once I've changed completely,
the Colonel will see me as a threat,
won't he?
I think so.
What will he do?
Remove the threat.
One way or another.
Will it be you?
Yes, ma'am. I think so.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
I couldn't let it be anyone else.
Is that what you came to tell me?
I came to ask for your forgiveness,
for when the time does come.
Of course.
If I could please hear you say it.
I forgive you, Ronald.
Thank you.
That's important.
Take care of Matt.
You don't even have to ask me to say it.
I already tried once to keep him from
comin' to see you,
but you know how stubborn he is.
I could tell him to stay away.
That might be a good idea.
I mean, for him.
Will I see you again?
It would be better for me
if I said goodbye now.
Okay.
I'm sorry,
but I can't do that.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Miss Armstrong.
I love you, Matt. Know that.
I wish that I could have shown you off
to my friends and hear you say
"dang" in front of my mom.
I wish we could have grown old together
and had a family,
but I'm grateful for what we had.
Please take care of everyone.
You're far more important to holding
this place together than you know.
Take care of Eli, because he's going to
take care of you in his own way.
And forgive Ronald.
He did what he had to do, and if it was
going to be anyone, I am glad it was him.
Okay?
I love you.
Just relax. Breathe deeply, slowly.
- You're on the planet now. Eden.
- Yes.
What do you feel?
There's a nip in the air.
I can see my breath.
It's morning.
Yes, the sun is out.
Tell me what you see.
The lake outside camp.
It's beautiful.
Val is here.
What is Val saying?
She's just smiling.
We spent the night together
under the stars.
The others don't know. It's our secret.
Where are the others now?
Working.
We're always working.
It's just too late in the season.
It's a waste of time.
Well, we need to try.
And we will, okay?
We'll try again in the spring.
For now we should just gather
what we can.
We've picked
most of this area clean.
Well then,
at least gather some firewood.
All right? I mean, there's no way
of knowing how long this winter will last.
It's just getting colder every night.
He's afraid.
Who is?
Caine. Winter is coming.
All right. It's another day. The afternoon.
- Yes.
- Where are you now?
In the forest.
Chopping trees for firewood.
- With Caine?
- No.
No.
Val!
- No...
- Peter...
Val! Val...
Peter, what's happening?
She died on the planet.
- Are you sure?
- I remember now.
It was before winter came.
I was falling a tree.
I didn't see her coming.
She couldn't get out of the way.
I saw her die! Months ago!
How is that...
Peter!
This is Wray! I have a medical emergency!
Make a hole!
This time the symptoms are consistent
with dehydration and hypothermia.
You said the hypnosis was working.
He was starting to remember.
Yeah, the last thing
he remembered was Val died on the planet.
Well, based on the condition of his body,
I would say Peter died on the planet, too,
from extreme exposure.
But he said Val died months ago,
before the winter.
Months ago?
What if they're dying again?
In order?
Lieutenant Scott,
I need you to locate Dr. Caine
and the other members of the shuttle
and escort them to the infirmary now.
Rachel, open the door, please.
Please help me.
We're going to help you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
maybe you shouldn't touch her.
- I don't want to die.
- We're gonna get you to the infirmary.
She was like this when we found her.
Put her over here.
Strip down and get your ass into decon.
This could be anything.
- I told him.
Go!
Please help me.
Hey.
I want to know what the hell's going on.
I swear I don't know.
Well, you're going to sit down with Wray until
you figure it out, or I swear to God...
We are members of your crew.
No, you're former members.
You left by choice!
And if what's happening to you people
spreads to the rest of us,
you're going to be dropped off
on the next planet!
Sir, it's not his fault.
None of this would be happening
if Caine had not talked those people
into staying on that planet.
I wanted to stay, too.
And that's what would have
happened to you.
Camile, this is Young.
Dr. Caine is your next volunteer.
- Colonel...
- Go. Now.
Chloe?
Chloe.
I thought you should know what's goin'
on with those folks from the shuttle...
- Go away, Matt.
- What?
I said leave. Now.
I'll come back later, then. All right?
All right, everyone,
we know we're fighting hypothermia here,
so let's keep their core temperatures up.
What do you see?
Snow is falling.
The shuttle is our only shelter now.
It's so cold.
We lost power days ago.
Something vital is broken
and none of us know how to fix it.
It's airtight, so we have to leave
the door ajar or we'll suffocate.
We still have some food,
and Peter has made some candles
to keep us warm.
They provide enough light to read
and share our evening meal.
Peter is still with you?
In his heart, he's already left us.
I try to tell him...
It'll be all right, Peter.
No, it won't be all right.
Nothing will be all right.
But by morning, he's gone.
Okay. Um...
It's the last night.
The night before you woke up inside the
shuttle and Destiny was there.
Yes. I remember.
Tell me what you see.
It's very dark.
There's no pain. Just...
Just the cold.
Who else is there with you?
- What?
- They're all dead. Frozen.
I'm alone.
What are you doing?
There's nowhere for me to go.
Nothing to do now but pray.
The next thing I remember is
waking up on the shuttle
and seeing Destiny out the window.
Is that all?
I wish I had more answers for you.
Me, too.
But you won't have to drop me off
at the next planet, Colonel.
I expect I'll be dead before
you come back out of FTL.
You don't know that.
Yes, I do.
Because now I remember something
that no one ever should.
I'm already dead.
Eli, did you leave this in the shuttle?
No. Why?
Well, somebody did.
They all died in their sleep.
- With symptoms of severe exposure?
- Yeah.
But I'm guessing whatever the aliens did
to bring you back, it was only temporary.
You're all just reverting back to
the state they probably found you in.
I'm sorry.
I did everything I could think of.
It's not your fault.
How much time do I have left?
Not much.
May I be allowed to see the stars
one last time?
Yeah, of course. Go ahead.
I would like very much not to be alone.
Wow. I forgot how beautiful this view was.
Maybe they were just giving you
the chance to see it one more time,
or to say goodbye to all of us.
This isn't me. At least not the man I was.
That's what Dr. Rush was trying to tell me
in his own way.
I just didn't believe him.
This body's nothing but a shadow,
not reborn, but reanimated,
and not by God,
but by beings who can
rebuild a man's body,
but not his soul.
Maybe that's what you
and Colonel Young were sensing.
I don't feel that way now.
That's kind of you to say.
But even though I have his thoughts
and some of his memories,
I'm not the Robert Caine that God made.
After all of this, you still believe?
That is faith, T.J.
I believe that my soul
has already moved on,
and is looking down even now marveling
at how kind you are to comfort a shadow.
You have to believe with all of your heart
that your daughter
is in a better place.
The greatest gift that you can give her,
and to all of us, is to live your life,
to fulfill Destiny's mission
and have faith in each other.
If anyone's
listening, help us.
Help us. Please.
I don't want to die.
Help us...
Please...
English - US - SDH