Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
RUSH: This is what Destiny intended from
the moment it entered the star system.
YOUNG: We are going to survive.
We are going to make it home.
I'm telling you,
the ship came here for a reason!
RUSH: Destiny is powered
by the stars themselves.
WRAY: He and Young are
bumping heads, yes.
Not sure which camp is the better choice.
I don't even know what to do
with myself.
I'm the last person who should be here.
RUSH: You're the wrong man
for the job, Colonel.
You don't believe in the mission.
YOUNG: Neural interface?
A repository of knowledge that can be
literally downloaded into one's mind.
Do you know what a device like this
did to General O'Neill?
The sheer amount of information
overwhelmed him, yes.
It damn near killed him.
Young is not going to listen.
And Dr. Rush, well, like you said,
he's in no hurry to come home.
JOHANSEN: Well, the convulsions have
stopped, but he's completely unresponsive.
YOUNG: You just couldn't wait, could you?
Anyone who had access to that room
was under strict orders
not to sit in that chair.
YOUNG: You knew.
You wanted somebody there
because you didn't have the guts
to do it yourself!
This is obviously someone trying
to undermine the Colonel's authority.
We cannot let that happen.
Somebody's trying to frame me, Eli.
- Where's Rush?
- YOUNG: He didn't make it.
No headaches? Any blurry vision?
I'm fine.
- You sleeping okay?
- T.J., I'm good. I got to go.
Sir, you lost someone
under your command.
Most recently, three people.
Gorman, Spencer, and Rush. It happens.
Well, I know how much it affects you.
In different ways, I let them down.
So, if you ever want to talk about it,
I'm here.
- I don't.
- You should.
I'm sorry?
Like you said, you felt like
you let Sergeant Spencer down. We all do.
And there's been a lot going on
between you and Rush.
What are you saying?
That emotionally,
a lot has been left unresolved.
Another time.
WRAY: Colonel.
- Off to file your latest report back to Earth?
- That's right.
I'm curious about the details
you intend to provide
regarding the incident with Dr. Rush.
Exactly what happened.
I'm scheduled to file my report
with Earth later today,
and it may cast some doubt
on your version of events.
There were only two people
on that planet, me and Rush.
I'm talking about the obvious issues
between the two of you.
That doesn't change anything.
Listen, if you want to accuse me,
you should have the guts
to come right out and accuse me.
I don't have proof of anything.
I think you just want to be in charge again.
I'm saying you had plenty of motive.
Really? Do you think that I want people
on this ship suspecting me of murder?
Maybe that burden is easier to bear
than actually dealing with Rush.
Well, I'll admit it, I don't miss the man.
I say we're all better off.
Well, that's reassuring.
So if you don't measure up,
you just get left for dead?
What exactly is the criteria, then,
for sticking around? Do you agree?
All right. Let's do this.
All good?
All good.
Hey, Eli. Hey, when you get a chance,
can you check the shower system?
- The pressure's been kind of low.
- Sure, once I'm done here.
Dr. Caine's pretty cute, huh?
There is nothing sexier than a widower.
A man who's proven
that he can make a commitment
and is single through no fault of his own.
I mean, what more could you ask for?
I can hear you.
I'm so sorry!
DR. CAINE: How about we just carry on
like nothing happened?
Okay. Thank you.
God, kill me now.
All right, I think we're ready.
Welcome aboard Destiny.
I'm Lieutenant Matthew Scott.
- You okay?
- Excuse me?
Hi. Who are you?
Sergeant, what happened?
I have absolutely no idea, sir.
- Now, what do you think?
- I'm an IT tech.
You know, I fix Earth computers,
not Ancient communication devices.
- Malfunction in the connection?
- That's quite a hiccup.
I've seen worse.
We don't exactly know
what these stones do, do we?
Well, no, not personally.
I just got put on stone duty
'cause Riley's not back on his feet yet.
You know, sir, you have been
under quite a bit of stress.
You're not suggesting that I imagined it?
No.
Whoever took over your body was
acting kind of strangely...
Look, there is no way that I hallucinated
that ship or that alien.
My imagination isn't that good.
I was on a ship, and I saw an alien.
Now, I want to know
exactly what happened,
what went wrong and why.
And until then, the Communications Room
and that device are off-limits, understood?
- WRAY: Got a minute?
- Please, sit.
You know, I always figured
limited resources meant that
every day would be a struggle for survival,
but I never thought it would come to this.
- Is that supposed to be some sort of hint?
- Yeah, it's a hint.
If you're wondering what to get me
for Christmas, I need socks.
I heard about today's incident.
Caine's looking into it.
You know, I find it interesting that
the device just happens to malfunction
moments after we had
our conversation this morning.
I guess it's kind of coincidental.
That's one word. Another is "convenient."
And another is "surprising."
Okay, your turn.
You actually think that this will keep me
from filing my report back to Earth?
Actually, yeah. No, I'm pretty sure it will.
When the time comes, let's hope that
those who sit in judgment of you
grant the mercy you denied Dr. Rush.
I believe you mean
"allegedly" denied Dr. Rush.
Communications with Earth will resume
as soon as I am completely satisfied
that the next attempt to connect
will not result in another coincidence,
or convenience, or a surprise.
Thank you.
We have tomatoes!
We finally have tomatoes!
More or less.
Wow, that's odd.
So I was talking to Dr. Inman,
and she said the hydroponics team
will have strawberries for us
in about a month.
Sort of strawberries. Talk to me when
they can finally start growing meat.
Well, actually, I heard
they're working on a soy-based protein.
Happy Thanksgiving, everyone.
Enjoy your Tofurky.
You're in a bad mood. What's the matter?
I haven't slept much.
Colonel Young has me working
round the clock
trying to figure out everything
that Rush was working on...
RICHMOND: You can't be serious.
Colonel Young was willing
to sacrifice his own life
so that one of us could have a shot
at getting on a shuttle
when the ship
was heading towards that star.
You think he's a cold-blooded murderer?
- I wasn't saying that.
- It's fine.
Can you believe it? Tomatoes!
Mmm!
What?
From the second we got on this ship,
they've been the ones calling all the shots.
What we eat, where we sleep,
what we do and when,
- and we just sit back and let them.
- Yeah, they're the ones with the guns.
Yeah, I mean,
we have every right to be afraid.
Look at what happened
to the last person to challenge them.
So, what do you think we should do?
I don't know.
Purple plants? Are you kidding me?
Well, purple chlorophyll is sensitive
to red and infrared light.
The planet's probably orbiting a red dwarf.
Well, the Kino says
breathable atmosphere, water and oxygen.
I'm concerned about potential
stellar flare activity. Spot radiation.
All right, then. We'll suit up.
Sirs! You've got to see this.
It just showed up.
- Eli.
- Bringing it up.
Now.
- What is it doing?
- Nothing yet. It's just sitting there.
Maybe we should try
communicating with it?
- How?
- Well, we have broadcast capability.
Of course, there's no way in hell
they'd understand us.
Eli.
But I guess
there's only one way to find out.
Two alien encounters in a day.
What are the chances?
I am thinking, likely zero.
Okay, sending now.
Let's hope they speak Ancient.
There is no way this is a coincidence.
I bet you I was on that ship this morning.
You figure you piqued their curiosity,
they came here to check on us?
I'm thinking they've been checking on us
for a while.
There's no other way
they can find us this fast.
They answered back.
That's not a translation.
- They answered in English.
- Now, how the hell is that possible?
- I...
- What did you say?
"Hello. We're peaceful humans
from planet Earth.
"We mean you no harm
and we'd like to meet you."
- What do I do? What do I say back?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
- Nothing. Get our weapons online.
This is Colonel Young.
All personnel, report to designated areas.
Lieutenant, I need you and Greer
in that shuttle.
Yes, sir.
Something's happening.
I think they're launching smaller ships.
Oh, my God.
Only 30% of the weapons
are coming online.
Rush put limits on how many
could be activated at once.
Right, right, after what happened to Riley.
We were still in the process of checking
each gun's functionality.
Well, find a way around it, Eli.
Disengaging.
- YOUNG: Eli, come on.
- Hey, hey, first real space battle over here.
- You got it?
- GREER: Just about.
- Eli, activate the forward battery.
- That's what I'm trying to do.
- Come on, get back. Come on.
- MAN: Let's go.
We're taking heavy fire!
- Can you boost power to the shields?
- I'm working on it.
Shield power is being drained
by the weapons.
MAN: Come on, move. Go.
WOMAN: Go.
Stay back!
We've got surges happening
all over the ship.
The weapons system wasn't ready for this.
Eli, everyone on board this ship
is counting on you.
I don't need to hear that.
- You can do this.
- No. No, I can't!
- Yes, you can.
- Why is this all on me, okay?
- What about him?
- I don't care. Both of you!
I need this ship working now!
You should've thought of that
before you got rid of Rush.
Just fix it.
- You guys okay?
- MAN: Yeah.
- Check her!
- JAMES: Okay.
They're pulling back.
Colonel Young, this is Airman Dunning, sir.
Please respond.
- They're retreating.
- GREER: We got them on the run.
Let's give them something
to remember us by.
Lieutenant, I need you to end pursuit
and fall back to Destiny.
- But, sir...
- Do not engage. I repeat, do not engage.
Chloe may be on board one of those ships.
- SCOTT: What the hell happened?
- Easy, Lieutenant. It was nobody's fault.
- We were not ready for this.
- They gave up pretty quickly.
The attack may have been a distraction
to try to come in close and take prisoners,
- try to gain intel.
- Why are we the enemy?
I don't know.
Sir, that ship is still within shuttle range.
Request permission to...
- Permission denied.
- Colonel.
You wouldn't stand a chance. With me.
- What are we going to do?
- I'm going after her.
- How?
- The communication device.
Sir, you are only assuming
that's the same ship that you were on.
Guess I'll find out when I'm on board.
Let's elevate this.
Have a seat over there,
and I'll get to you as soon as I can, okay?
Thanks so much.
- Anything I can do?
- Take your pick.
Grab some gauze.
Don't touch, don't touch.
- Chloe was taken.
- What? How?
One of the ships latched on, cut a hole.
I can't get a pulse over here!
Grab the bag.
Keep the pressure on him, please.
- Caine.
- Yeah?
- Caine, we need you.
- Okay.
Okay, that's good.
Tighter.
Sir. Sir! Let me do it.
Lieutenant, it's not going to happen.
For the record,
I think this is a very bad idea.
Yes, but it's the best of the bad ideas.
Go.
ELI: I think I got most of the weapons
back online.
- How long is he going in for?
- Twenty minutes, then we pull him out.
Okay.
Colonel, you can always go back in
if you don't find her.
Okay?
We are not your enemy.
We mean you no harm.
I don't think it understands you.
They spoke English.
They sent a one-word message.
For all we know, they have a translation
device on their ship or something.
SCOTT: Which sent it in Ancient.
Why did you attack us?
Why did you take
one of our people prisoner?
Why did you do that?
You want to help me?
This is how you read my mind.
Do you understand?
This one transmits.
This one receives.
Like this. Here, like this.
Yeah. Yeah.
Do not engage.
Chloe may be aboard one of those ships.
Colonel Young!
- What happened?
- He's back.
- YOUNG: What just happened?
- The alien ship is closing in on us.
Send me back.
Send me back now!
Okay, good to go.
Ready.
It's not working. Why isn't it working?
Untie me.
There doesn't seem to be anything
wrong with the device.
Did you find Chloe?
Guys? You may have noticed
they're attacking us again.
Eli.
Our shields aren't going to hold
for much longer.
Bring the main weapon online.
Fire on the big ship.
Chloe is still on board that ship!
Do it now, Eli! Return fire!
Everything we've got!
We can't keep this up.
The whole weapons system is overloading.
- Shields are down almost 50%.
- I know!
- Where are you going?
- To try and save Chloe.
RUSH: It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
We have to go. Here.
Oh, God.
Where are we going?
This way.
- Report.
- Bad and more bad.
Too much power is going to the weapons.
Our shields are going to fail.
Bolster the shield. Devote all remaining
weapons power to the main weapon.
Keep firing on the big ship.
Not like you,
taking the shuttle without asking.
He'll say no, and I don't want to disobey
an order. You got a problem with that?
You want to save her? Do it.
- I'm going. You don't have to.
- I'm already here.
- They're retreating.
- Keep firing.
We fire again,
and we risk blowing ourselves up.
I don't have a choice. Do it.
They're retreating.
All of them except that one.
Wait.
They're gone.
Matt!
Colonel Young said you were dead.
Did he? Did he say how it happened?
- Rock slide.
- Well, obviously, he was wrong again.
Colonel Young, this is Greer. Come in.
Go ahead.
GREER: You are not going to believe this.
I managed to activate the systems
on the crashed ship.
Found a database.
I'd only just begun to look through it
when aliens showed up.
I guess I must have accidentally activated
some kind of distress beacon.
Anyway, I'm glad I did.
I would have died out there.
Well, there are a few people
who thought Colonel Young
left you to die on purpose.
RUSH: I imagine there were.
No, no, he would have rightly assumed
that I was... I was gone.
In the rock slide.
So, what happened when the aliens
brought you on their ship?
To be honest, I don't remember that much.
The few times I was conscious,
they were probing my mind.
That's something
I'd rather not think about, really.
I know they were frustrated.
I seemed to be able to resist
giving them the information they wanted.
He used their own neural interface
against them,
getting what he needed
so we could escape.
Location of the fighter bay,
basic operating systems.
Anything else?
Like why they wanted to destroy us?
I don't think they did want to destroy us.
What they really want is Destiny.
Probably only care about us
because we recently came aboard.
No, what they want
is a way past her defenses,
try and find out
what secrets she might hold.
Unfortunately, I didn't have time
to find out any more.
My first priority was getting
Chloe and I off the ship.
Well, it's good to have you back.
Both of you.
- So?
- So.
I suppose you're wondering
why I didn't tell everyone the truth.
YOUNG: It's your word against mine.
I didn't tell anyone you tried to frame me
for Spencer's death.
Well, that's true.
No, I just wanted to know
whether I can assume that
you are going to try and kill me again
next chance you get.
I saved you from those aliens.
You fired on the alien ship
while I was still aboard.
Well, so was Chloe.
That was a command decision,
protecting the greater good.
Yes, indeed.
Look, I realize that I did provoke you.
Well, if it means anything,
I regret leaving you on that planet.
Don't get me wrong,
I think you deserved it,
but I regret that I lost control,
that I became a man
that I couldn't respect anymore.
Well, you're here, I'm here.
We just have to live with it, don't we?
Well, so does everyone else on board.
They don't need the distraction.
They don't need to doubt their leadership,
and this ship needs to be ready
for the next encounter.
If we haven't found our way home by then.
Of course.
So, what,
we just pretend nothing happened?
Well, it's not like we were ever friends.
- For the sake of the crew.
- Hey, there.
- Hi!
- Do you mind?
- No, it's okay.
- You want to try some?
- What is it?
It's a little something
that Dr. Inman's been working on.
She claims it tastes like gin.
I say it's a little closer to rubbing alcohol.
Solid sales pitch. No, thank you.
All right.
So, what do you think?
You and James, any chance there?
It could just get really awkward,
you know, if things didn't work out.
I mean, being stuck on this ship
with someone you've had
a bad relationship with? No, thanks.
It's probably best
to just keep things professional,
for as long as we can, anyways.
I mean, we'll see.
If we're here much longer,
I hereby reserve the right
to completely change my mind.
And when the hour is upon us
And our beauty surely gone
No, you will not be forgotten
And you will not be alone
No, you will not be alone
And when the day has all but ended
And our echo starts to fade
No, you will not be alone then
And you will not be afraid
No, you will not be afraid
And when the fog has finally lifted
From my cold and tired brow
No, I will not leave you crying
No, I will not let you down
I will not let you down
The Colonel's dangerous.
We need to do something about that.
I tried.
- I know.
- Damn near killed me for it.
Next time will be different.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org